<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>best cancer treatment in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/best-cancer-treatment-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 10:07:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Lymphoma &#8211; A Cancer Of The Infection Fighting Cells</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lymphoma-a-cancer-of-the-infection-fighting-cells/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 10:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lymphoma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1114</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Lymphoma is the cancer of lymphocytes, the infection fighting cells of the immune system. In this condition, the lymphocytes start growing out of control. The lymphocytes are present in the spleen, bone marrow, lymph nodes and other parts of the body. The two types of lymphomas include – Hodgkin Non Hodgkin – This is the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lymphoma-a-cancer-of-the-infection-fighting-cells/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Lymphoma &#8211; A Cancer Of The Infection Fighting Cells"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Lymphoma is the cancer of lymphocytes, the infection fighting cells of the immune system. In this condition, the lymphocytes start growing out of control. The lymphocytes are present in the spleen, bone marrow, lymph nodes and other parts of the body. The two types of lymphomas include –</span></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Hodgkin </span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Non Hodgkin – This is the most common type of lymphoma</span></p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/lymphoma.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1115" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/lymphoma.jpg" alt="lymphoma" width="750" height="374" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/lymphoma.jpg 750w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/lymphoma-300x150.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The growth rate is different for different lymphomas and they have different lymphocyte cells. For people who aren’t aware, Lymphoma and Leukemia are not the same because both the cancers start in different cells. Lymphoma begins in the infection fighting lymphocytes as mentioned before while Leukemia begins in blood forming cells within the bone marrow. </span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;"><b>Symptoms </b></span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The symptoms of Lymphoma are not very severe in the beginning. They include swelling on the lymph nodes, shortness of breath, fever, cough, weight loss, fatigue, itching and night sweats.</span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;"><b>Diagnosis</b></span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The oncologist will carry out a physical examination and ask for one of the tests including Biopsy, MRI, chest X ray, Molecular Test and PET scan and Blood Test based on the examination.</span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;"><b>Treatment </b></span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The treatment is based on the diagnosis that includes Chemotherapy, Radiation therapy, targeted therapy and immune therapy primarily. If the cancer does not subside then stem cell transplant is the alternative. This treatment involves killing the cancer cells but along with them even the stem cells get destroyed. So, after the therapy is completed, you need to get a stem cell transplant. There are two types of stem cell transplants namely autologous and allogeneic transplant. Autologous transplant involves replacement of own stem cells and allogeneic involves donor stem cells transplant. </span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;"><b>Causes/ Risk Factors– </b></span><span style="font-size: medium;">As yet scientists haven’t been able to figure out exact cause of this cancer but risk factors include the following – </span></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Weak Immune System due to some organ transplant or HIV/Aids or some immune disease by birth.</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Virus infections like Hepatitis C, Epstein Barr or lymphoma(HTLV-1) / T-cell leukemia </span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Exposure to chemicals or benzene use for killing plant bugs and weeds</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The age group prone to Hodgkin lymphoma is 15-40 years and 55 or older while for Non Hodgkin Lymphoma it is 60 plus. </span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Family history of having this condition.</span></p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8220;<a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is one of the recognized premiere institute in Bangalore, to start <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/">surgical oncology</a> department at its inception to cater to the growing needs of the society and offers surgical treatment to various cancers.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Genetically Modified Virus Effective in Cancer Treatment &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetically-modified-virus-effective-in-cancer-treatment-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1055</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The study published in the journal for Cancer Research states that scientists have developed a new technique in which they use a genetically modified virus for killing cancer cells and even has the ability to destroy their hiding places. Named as the enadenotucirev, this novel dual action virus targets cancer cells as well as the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetically-modified-virus-effective-in-cancer-treatment-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Genetically Modified Virus Effective in Cancer Treatment &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The study published in the journal for Cancer Research states that scientists have developed a new technique in which they use a genetically modified virus for killing cancer cells and even has the ability to destroy their hiding places. Named as the enadenotucirev, this novel dual action virus targets cancer cells as well as the healthy cells that are tricked into cancer cell protection by the immune system of the body called fibro-blasts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1056" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment.jpg" alt="Genetically Modified Virus Effective in Cancer Treatment" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The therapy used presently for killing the tricked viruses of cancer may also kill the fibroblast cells leading to toxicity. Carcinomas, the most common kind of cancer are found to start in the cells of the skin or in the tissues covering or lining internal organs like lungs, pancreas, breasts, colon, prostate and ovaries.<br />
As per Kerry Fisher of Britain’s University of Oxford there hasn’t been any way where you can kill the cancer cells and the fibroblasts that are known to protect them as well, without causing any harm to the other parts of the body. Therefore, this technique that can be used for targeting the cancer cells as well as the fibroblasts is definitely cited as a vital development in reducing the suppression inside the carcinomas as well as initiating the normal immune process.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><img class="alignnone wp-image-1057 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/rrmch.gif" alt="rrmch" width="647" height="42" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The team included some genetic instructions before publishing the study in the journal order the infected cancer cells to produce a protein called bispecific T cell engager, that has the ability to bind and stick two cells together. Here the first end is fibroblasts and the second end is T cells – a kind of immune cell that kills defective cells. The result, T cells started killing attached fibroblasts. The team also carried out the testing of the virus on a human bone marrow successfully to find that the process did not result in creating any toxicity to the rest of the body or any inappropriate activation of T cells.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The clinical trials of Enadenotucirev have already started for carcinoma treatment and in the upcoming year it will begin its clinical trials of finding out the safety and affectivity of it on people suffering from cancer.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Top Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore, Karnataka</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ductal Carcinoma in Situ (DCIS) &#038; Mastectomy</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-dcis-mastectomy/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 06:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1016</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In India Breast Cancer is the top occurring cancer amongst females with a mortality rate of 12.7 per 1,00,000. A non-invasive form of breast cancer, Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) is a common form of cancer in India. Ductal means ducts as its starts in the milk ducts and carcinoma means cancer that starts in &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-dcis-mastectomy/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Ductal Carcinoma in Situ (DCIS) &#038; Mastectomy"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">In<em> India Breast Cancer</em> is the top occurring cancer amongst females with a mortality rate of 12.7 per 1,00,000. A non-invasive form of breast cancer, <em><strong>Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS)</strong></em> is a common form of cancer in India. Ductal means ducts as its starts in the milk ducts and carcinoma means cancer that starts in the skin or any other tissues covering the internal organs and in situ means in its original place. The reason this cancer is known as non- invasive cancer is that is has not spread beyond the milk duct to the neighboring tissues.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">DCIS is a grade 0 cancer and is not a life threatening cancer but having it in first place does increase the risk of developing an invasive breast cancer later on compared to people who haven’t had it before. The possibility of recurrence is usually 5 or 10 years post the first appearance with a 30% likelihood.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1017" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-DCIS.jpg" alt="Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS)" width="500" height="287" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-DCIS.jpg 500w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-DCIS-300x172.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The possibility of recurrence in women undergoing the breast conserving surgery is around 25% to 30% . To lower the risk of recurrence by 15% you need to include radiation therapy in the treatment plan. Also, if DCIS comes back after treatment it could either be non-invasive or invasive too, chances are 50% for each.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Here’s a look through the symptoms, causes, diagnosis and treatment of the condition.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DICS &#8211; Symptoms</strong><br />
Generally there are no visible symptoms of DCIS. Only a few people might have a lump in the breast or some nipple discharge. Diagnosis is only possible for most of the cases through mammography.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DICS – Diagnosis</strong><br />
<strong>Breast Examination</strong> – A physical examination of breasts is carried out if a lump is present though such lump is rarely noticeable.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Mammography</strong> – A mammography can easily detect DCIS. Even when a physical examination fails, mammography can be used to detect DCIS.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Biopsy</strong> – Biopsy is only carried out when a mammogram does not give a clear result. There are two kinds of non-invasive biopsies which involve a bit of surgery.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong> Core needle biopsy</strong> – A large needle is inserted for a big sample of tissue from the suspicious area.</li>
<li><strong> Fine needle biopsy</strong> &#8211; A sample of cells are obtained by inserting a small hollow needle in the breast and then examining it under the microscope.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Though more invasive biopsies are rarely need for DCIS, if the above are not able to give conclusive results then biopsies like incisional and excisional biopsy’s are to be done.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong> – Once the diagnosis confirms DCIS, surgery is done to remove the <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cancer</a> as well as the border of the healthy tissues surrounding the cancer, known as the clear margins. This means doing the procedure of lumpectomy or sometimes mastectomy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
