<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>admissions in medical college bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/admissions-in-medical-college-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 10:57:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Medical College Admission 2018 &#8211; MBBS-MS-MD-PhD</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/mbbs-ms-md-admissions-2018-19/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 10:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2018 mbbs admissions in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[admissions in medical college bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs admissions 2018]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs admissions in 2018 Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs ms md admissions in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical admissions in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college admissions 2018]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical course admissions in 2018]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=796</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[With the onset of summer in India, students start getting ready for their board exams and even start head hunting for colleges in India to pursue their dream careers. Well, Indians are slowly evolving and the mindset of medical stream or medicine being the only choice to succeed in Life is slowing fading away from &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/mbbs-ms-md-admissions-2018-19/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Medical College Admission 2018 &#8211; MBBS-MS-MD-PhD"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">With the onset of summer in India, students start getting ready for their board exams and even start head hunting for colleges in India to pursue their dream careers. Well, Indians are slowly evolving and the mindset of medical stream or medicine being the only choice to succeed in Life is slowing fading away from the minds of many educated souls. Having said that, there is still a major chunk of parents in India who feel that the first career choice is nothing better than medicine. True to a certain extent for it offers a career path that is so rewarding since ages.</p>
<p align="justify">Now that it’s time of the year when parents of students aspiring a career in medicine are shortlisting or have already shortlisted medical colleges as per their choice, let talk about a possibility that stands out in health education.<br />
RRMCH is an endeavor of Moogambigai Charitable and Educational Trust, established in 1992 with an objective of bringing about academic excellence in Karnataka. RRMCH has a holistic approach towards education and gives equal importance to extracurricular activities together with academics.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/mbbs-admissions-2018-19-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-797" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/mbbs-admissions-2018-19-1-1.jpg" alt="MBBS Admissions 2018-19" width="998" height="270" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Spread across a wide spanning campus of 25 acres, the college and hospital are nestled in South West Bangalore. An institutional member of the <strong>International Medical Sciences Academy, IMSA</strong>, a global body that aims in upgrading medical standards around the world, RRMCH is also recognized by the MCH and is affiliated to RGUHS.</p>
<p align="justify">RRMCH has a 1300 bed hospital which provides an easy window for practical learning besides digitally equipped classrooms, auditorium, Bank, intensive care unit, Central research laboratory with state of the art facilities to name a few. The laboratory in collaboration with renowned international institutions carries out numerous research programs. Furthermore, RRMCH also houses a medical museum, that showcases over 300 dissected specimens and 1000 plus models of pathology and anatomy. No wonder it is a <a title="NAAC A Grade Medical College in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/accreditation/naac/" target="_blank">NAAC A Accredited college</a> and a leader in health education in Bangalore.</p>
<p align="justify">RRMCH offers undergraduate and post graduate course in medicine which include undergraduate, post graduate, doctoral programs and paramedical as well as super specialty courses.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>MBBS</strong> – RRMCH offers MBBS course of 4.5 years plus 1 year compulsory rotating internship</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>MD</strong> &#8211; Doctor in Medicine program can be done in subjects namely Anatomy, Anaesthesia, Bio-Chemistry, Community Medicine, Dermatology, Forensic Medicine, General medicine, Microbiology, Pathology, Paediatrics, Pharmacology, Physiology, Psychiatry, Radio Diagnosis and Respiratory Medicine.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>MS</strong> – RRMCH offers MS in subjects namely ENT, General Surgery, OBG, Opthalmology and Orthopaedics.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>PhD</strong>&#8211; RRMCH offers PhD in Physiology course</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Paramedical Courses</strong> – Paramedical courses under RRMCH include Diploma in Medical Laboratory Technology, Operation Theatre Technology, X Ray Technology, Health Inspection, Ophthalmic Technology and Medical Record Technology</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Super Specialty Courses</strong> &#8211; RRMCH also offers super specialty courses in DM – Cardiology, MCH in Urology, Plastic Surgery and Pediatric Surgery and super specialty course in Neurology.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, if you are also one of those parents of students looking out to make it big in the world of medicine, RRMCH definitely is one of the institutions that can help you pave the way to success in the healthcare arena. <a title="medical colleges in bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org" target="_blank"><strong>Medical college admission for the year 2018-19</strong></a> are now open at RRMCH.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Contact for more info: </strong></p>
<p>No.202, Kambipura, Mysore Road,<br />
Bengaluru-560 074.</p>
<p><strong>Phone: 2843 7444/ 2843 7777</strong><br />
<strong>Fax       : 080-2843 7393</strong><br />
<strong>E mail id:<a href="mailto:enquiry@rrmch.org" target="_blank">enquiry@rrmch.org</a><br />
<a href="mailto:info@rrmch.org" target="_blank">info@rrmch.org</a></strong></p>
<p><a title="Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org" target="_blank">http://www.rrmch.org</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
