<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Physiotherapy Career In India &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/physiotherapy-career-in-india/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 06:58:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 06:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Career In India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1234</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>
A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid
in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The
study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues
at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the
electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants in Partners
biobank for the study. The study was spread across 2 years wherein
the lead author Choi and his team studied through millions of data
points in order to look into people having any depression related
diagnosis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1235" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-768x511.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>
They also calculated the genetic risk score for every participant by
combining information around every participant complete genome to
come to score that determines their genetic risk for developing
depression. The data also revealed that people with high genetic risk
score could be diagnosed about it anytime in the coming 2 years. But,
those who were active physically even with higher genetic risk of
depression were less likely to experience depression. 
</p>



<p>
As per Choi an average 35 minutes of exercise on a daily basis could
help you reduce the risk of depression and even protect you against
depression bouts in future. The findings of the study Choi said that
“our findings strongly suggest that, when it comes to depression,
genes are not destiny and that being physically active has the
potential to neutralize the added risk of future episodes in
individuals who are genetically vulnerable”.</p>



<p> Well, exercise is always a good idea because it is useful and sparing out 30 to 35 minutes for yourself every day is the least you could do for your own wellness. A fit body definitely helps to keep you mind fit. So, invest in exercising atleast half and hour a day and you’ll see the difference in your overall fitness levels soon.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>&#8220;The <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/">department of physiotherapy</a> was established in 2003 at <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital</a> to cater to the preventive, creative, therapeutic and rehabilitation needs of the rural people need was felt to impart the much needed physiotherapy vocational and rehabilitation training programme. &#8220;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Career in Physiotherapy in India &#8211; Promising or not?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 05:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best bpt colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bpt course in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career in physiotherapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career in physiotherapy in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Career In India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rrmch.org/blog/?p=389</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[With pollution clogging up the air and chemicals degrading the quality of vegetables and greens, increased stress levels due to constant workloads, early age strokes, accidents while commuting, lifestyle diseases like obesity and more are taking a toll on people. Rehabilitation is slowly and steadily gaining importance in the healthcare sector. These days most of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Career in Physiotherapy in India &#8211; Promising or not?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">With pollution clogging up the air and chemicals degrading the quality of vegetables and greens, increased stress levels due to constant workloads, early age strokes, accidents while commuting, lifestyle diseases like obesity and more are taking a toll on people. Rehabilitation is slowly and steadily gaining importance in the healthcare sector. These days most of the multi-specialty hospitals have a rehabilitation centre with qualified Physiotherapists for treatment and therapy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Physiotherapy-Career-In-India-1-1.jpg"><img class="wp-image-390 aligncenter" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Physiotherapy-Career-In-India-1-1.jpg" alt="Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore" width="569" height="494" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Experts are already forecasting the immense possibilities for expansion and growth of Physiotherapy. The career is definitely a promising one, considering the fact that even people have realized the potential of physiotherapy in significantly improving quality of life by working on body mobilization.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">But, before you decide to take your plunge into this field which for sure offers total work satisfaction and is miles away from being monotonous in nature, you need to sit down and think about flip-side of the coin. You need to be aware that this career involves working with people of all ages and mental as well as physical disabilities or challenges. From kids to elderly, mentally challenged to accident victims, general populace to criminals, anyone for that matter could be your patient. Dealing with all kinds of people also means dealing with their tempers. So, primarily you need to have loads of patience and ability to keep calm during stressed times. It is a bit of physical work also because you need to demonstrate the exercises or body moves to the patients. This could be physically draining at times as well. So, take your decision about pursuing the career only after contemplating on these facts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">After giving it a thought, if you still feel passionate about pursuing the career, go ahead. Depending upon your interest you may either go for a Bachelors in Physiotherapy, Masters in Physiotherapy or you many are interested in doing research of taking up teaching as a profession. A doctorate is always advisable. In the US and UK, there is a high demand for Physiotherapists compared to India where the sun seems to be shining on this profession though its only into its initial growth phase. So, taking up a doctorate or a specialization in the field in an overseas university definitely would open doors to umpteen opportunities overseas for this profession. Even the payscale oversees is significantly high compared to India.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In India as a <a title="Physiotherapist in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/" target="_blank">physiotherapist</a> you may get to work in private hospitals, rehabilitation centres, defence establishments, sports and fitness centres, as private consultant to corporates, private practice at your own clinic or with the government hospitals, old age home, mental healthcare centres and more. The work timings are generally good and flexible to an extent. The good part is this profession does not require working during odd hours of the night, etc. So, you get ample time to spend with your family.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, <a title="Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/" target="_blank">Physiotherapy</a> is a challenging field but it is interesting and self satisfying as well. If it interests you a lot and you want to work for serving people and augmenting their health and fitness levels, then this profession is the right choice for you.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">* Disclaimer – Sourced from the internet. Verification required</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
