<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cataract Surgery &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/cataract-surgery/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 08:38:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cataract Surgery &#8211; What All You Need To Know?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cataract-surgery-what-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 08:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore eye hospital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cataract Surgery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lasik operations in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=868</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Though cataracts are a common amongst people over 65 years, they can happen in one or both even in the age group of 50 plus. Cataracts are common because they are only a result of aging process. Cataract causes the lens in our eye to become cloudy and results into vision loss inspite of wearing &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cataract-surgery-what-all-you-need-to-know/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Cataract Surgery &#8211; What All You Need To Know?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Though cataracts are a common amongst people over 65 years, they can happen in one or both even in the age group of 50 plus. Cataracts are common because they are only a result of aging process. Cataract causes the lens in our eye to become cloudy and results into vision loss inspite of wearing spectacles. This can happen in one eye or both as well. The cataract surgery is performed to remove the cloudy lens and replace it with an artificial lens known as intraocular lens in order to restore clarity in vision. It is a very simple and speedy surgery which requires just around 15-20 minutes of time. No overnight stay is required and the patient is discharged the same day within few hours of the surgery.</p>
<p align="justify">The cataract surgery performed these days is a very advanced one known a phacoemulsification or ‘phaco’ carried out using a high frequency ultrasound device that has the ability to break down the cloudy lens into pieces. These are then removed gently from the eye with the help of suction. ‘Phaco’ has greatly reduced the complications of eyes which the earlier surgeries had a risk part of it, besides the advantage of faster healing.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Cataract-Surgery-RRMCH-Bangalore-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-869" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Cataract-Surgery-RRMCH-Bangalore-1-1.jpg" alt="Cataract Surgery " width="500" height="362" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">The process typically includes the surgeon removing the cloudy lens from the eye and then inserting the intraocular lens and positioning is properly behind the pupil and iris exactly at the location of the natural lens. It very rare but sometimes in special cases the lens is placed in the front of the iris and pupil instead of the back. The procedure is concluded by closing the incision in the eye with a stitch or sometimes without it. In order to further protect the eye in the early stages of the surgery, a shield is placed over it as well.</p>
<p><strong>Cataract Surgery &#8211; After Care</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The eye drops provided by the doctor have to be used as per the doctor’s recommendation so as to avoid watering or itching.</li>
<li>Regular day to day activities can be performed as usual but some of them need to be restricted. Activities like reading, watching TV, walking and writing can be done but activities like lifting heavy loads, bending a lot and likes need to be restricted.</li>
<li>Do not perform strenuous exercises but light can do.</li>
<li>Wear your protective eye covering all the time even when sleeping. Do not sleep on the side of the operated eye.</li>
<li>Avoid water contact with the eyes during bath or shower.</li>
<li>Do not rub your eyes because it can cause infection.</li>
<li>Restrict yourself from swimming for atleast two weeks.</li>
<li>Do not drive for atleast 24 hours after surgery.</li>
<li>Avoid wearing any kind of eye makeup as well until your doctor permits.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>RRMCH one of the <strong><a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">best ophthalmology/eye hospitals in Bangalore</a></strong> for LASIK operations, Dr Vijay Kumar Srivastava eye specialist in bangalore</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
