<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Karradcon 2017 &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/karradcon-2017/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 11:51:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>KARRADCON 2017 &#8211; 33rd Annual State Conference of IRIA</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/karradcon-2017-33rd-annual-state-conference-of-iria/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 11:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[33rd Annual State Conference of IRIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karradcon 2017]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=436</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[KARRADCON 2017 &#8211; 33rd Annual State Conference of IRIA Karnataka State Chapter Today, with so much advancement in the field of medical science and much more in the offing, a question that arises time and again is whether Medical Science is the ultimate savior of humanity. Well, Karradcon 2017, the 33rd Annual State Conference of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/karradcon-2017-33rd-annual-state-conference-of-iria/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "KARRADCON 2017 &#8211; 33rd Annual State Conference of IRIA"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>KARRADCON 2017 &#8211; 33rd Annual State Conference of IRIA Karnataka State Chapter</strong><br />
Today, with so much advancement in the field of medical science and much more in the offing, a question that arises time and again is whether Medical Science is the ultimate savior of humanity.</p>
<p>Well, Karradcon 2017, the 33rd Annual State Conference of IRIA Karnataka State Chapter, was apparently and effort to throw light in the regard. Inaugurated by the guest of honor Prof. Dr. B M Hegde, Former Vice Chancellor, MAHE, the conference witnessed the auspicious presence of many notable delegates and dignitaries from the field of medical science namely Shri A C Shanmugam, Chairman RRGI, Dr Bhupendra Ahuja, National President, IRIA, Shir C N Seetharam, CEO, RRGI, Dr Amarnath, National secretary General, Dr Umesh Krishnamurthy, Organising Chairman, Karradcon 2017, Dr H V Shetty, Dean RRMH and Dr Umesh Krishnamurthy, Organising Chairman, KARRADCON 2017, to name a few.</p>
<p>The conference not only cleared the fog on potential of medical sciences, it also was a booster dose for the curious minds of medicine, encouraging them towards a systematic approach in the field. The highlights of the event included a book release on the biography of Roentgen, the man behind X-rays, authored by Dr Pravin G.U Prof. and HOD of Radiology at RRMCH and the go green initiative for awareness on living a greener lifestyle.<br />
It was followed by the felicitation ceremony of Prof. Dr H T Narayana, HOD, Siddhartha Medical College for his contribution in taking Karnataka State Chapter of the IRIA to greater heights as well as that of Prof. Dr. H.S Ballal, Prof. Dr. S.R Hegde, Professor and former Head of Department of Radiology at JJMC, Prof. Dr. Saroja, Professor of Radiology and Prof. Dr. H.T Narayan.</p>
<p>The award winning scientists and speakers from the medical fraternity, also threw light on the future of radiology at the scientific sessions on KARRADCON 2017 – Musculoskeletal and small parts, organized across different venues.</p>
<p>Altogether, it was an enlightening and insightful event for all one and all.<br />
Last but not the least the credit for the success of this conference goes to the participating delegates, dignitaries and all the team members of the organizing committee for their enthusiasm and efforts. <a href="http://college.rrmch.org/news/karradcon-2017/" target="_blank">Read More</a></p>
<p><a href="http://i.freegifmaker.me/1/4/9/0/3/6/1490360511186461.gif?1490360514"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://i.freegifmaker.me/1/4/9/0/3/6/1490360511186461.gif?1490360514" alt="KARRADCON 2017 @RRMCH" width="400" height="269" /></a></p>
<p>click to Download the <a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/karradcon-2017-1.ppt">KARRADCON 2017 &#8211; Medical Colleges in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
