<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>cancer hospitals in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/cancer-hospitals-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 06:42:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Weight Loss After 50 Years Of Age Reduces Breast Cancer Risk</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/weight-loss-after-50-years-of-age-reduces-breast-cancer-risk/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 06:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breast cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1251</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Breast cancer is one of the most common cancers amongst women in India and worldwide. A recent study about women who lost weight at 50 and maintained a healthy weight thereon showed a decreased risk of breast cancer as compared to women with more weight. This study is therefore a way to help women work &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/weight-loss-after-50-years-of-age-reduces-breast-cancer-risk/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weight Loss After 50 Years Of Age Reduces Breast Cancer Risk"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Breast cancer</strong> is one of the most common cancers amongst women in India and worldwide. A recent study about women who lost weight at 50 and maintained a healthy weight thereon showed a decreased risk of breast cancer as compared to women with more weight.  This study is therefore a way to help women work around prevention of cancer.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-1024x683.jpg" alt="Breast Cancer Risk" class="wp-image-1252" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
study is published in the Journal of the National Cancer Institute.
In USA over two third of the adult women are overweight or obese. The
study was carried out by the researchers at the American Cancer
Society, Harvard T. H. Chan School of Public Health using the Pooling
Project of Prospective Studies of Diet and Cancer (DCPP) in order to
determine the connection between sustained loss of weight after
menopause or later adulthood and the risk of breast cancer.</p>



<p>The
study involved over 180,000 women over 50 years of age across 10
studies. The sample size is huge and this analysis is the first to
assess the breast cancer risk impact over sustained weight loss. The
study did examine weight three times across 10 years period viz. at
the time of enrollment, post five years and again four years
thereafter. 
</p>



<p>The
results showed that women who were able to reduce more weight in
later adulthood and sustained it were able to lower the risk of
breast cancer. The women who were able to shed around 9 kg’s of
weight and then game some of it but not all did show a significant
reduction in breast cancer risk. 
</p>



<p> The lead author of the study Lauren Teras, PhD says ‘These findings may be a strong motivator for the two thirds of American women who are overweight to lose some of that weight. Even if you gain weight after age 50, it is not too late to lower your risk of breast cancer”.</p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>RRMCH is one of the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/"><strong>Best Cancer Treatment Hospital in Bangalore India</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Changes In Diet That Help You Reduce The Risk Of Cancer</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/changes-in-diet-that-help-you-reduce-the-risk-of-cancer/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1179</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As per statistics cancer is the causes the second highest number of deaths in India every year. Out of the 9.6 mn, over 8% are from India. Well, that’s not a small number. One of the most common cancers in India today is breast cancer. We all know that with all the innovations and advances &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/changes-in-diet-that-help-you-reduce-the-risk-of-cancer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Changes In Diet That Help You Reduce The Risk Of Cancer"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As
per statistics cancer is the causes the second highest number of
deaths in India every year.  Out of the 9.6 mn, over 8% are from
India. Well, that’s not a small number. One of the most common
cancers in India today is breast cancer. We all know that with all
the innovations and advances in Science, even today cancer does
affect the life expectancy negatively and also quality of life. So,
trying to prevent it seems a better idea. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1180" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer-300x160.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer-768x409.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>A
new study has revealed that the foods that are rich in flavonoids are
helpful in decreasing the risk of cancer and extending longevity. The
study was carried out over 50,000 participants across a span of 20
years. Finding out the impact of single compounds on health
conditions as well as mortality is not an easy study, even though
food does form the most important part of our lives.  
</p>



<p>Researchers
have already brought to light that eating vegetables and fruits
factually reduce the risk of cardiovascular conditions and increase
life span too. Though, the details on how they do it is under
research phase yet. Many researchers believe that it is rich in
flavonoids play a vital role in the same. 
</p>



<p>Flavonoids
are found in different natural food likes vegetables, dark
chocolates, fruits and tea are form a chemical class known as
polyphenols. These compounds are further divided into six sub classes
namely Flavonols, flavanones, flavan-3-ols, anthocyanins, flavones
and isoflavones.</p>



<p>A group of scientists from Edith Cowan University of Australia did begin a research in order to find out how the compounds could help increasing life span and help protect against health conditions. They also wanted to look into the effects of alcohol and smoking around the benefits of flavonoids. For investigation of the same, the scientists used the Danish Diet data of over 56048 adults across 23 years. During the process over 14083 participants passed away too. The researchers concluded that it was true that flavonoid rich diets with individual flavonoid subclasses do actually reduce the risk of cancer and cardiovascular diseases also increasing longevity.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/"><strong>Best Cancer Hospital Treatment in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lymphoma &#8211; A Cancer Of The Infection Fighting Cells</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lymphoma-a-cancer-of-the-infection-fighting-cells/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 10:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lymphoma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1114</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Lymphoma is the cancer of lymphocytes, the infection fighting cells of the immune system. In this condition, the lymphocytes start growing out of control. The lymphocytes are present in the spleen, bone marrow, lymph nodes and other parts of the body. The two types of lymphomas include – Hodgkin Non Hodgkin – This is the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lymphoma-a-cancer-of-the-infection-fighting-cells/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Lymphoma &#8211; A Cancer Of The Infection Fighting Cells"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Lymphoma is the cancer of lymphocytes, the infection fighting cells of the immune system. In this condition, the lymphocytes start growing out of control. The lymphocytes are present in the spleen, bone marrow, lymph nodes and other parts of the body. The two types of lymphomas include –</span></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Hodgkin </span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Non Hodgkin – This is the most common type of lymphoma</span></p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/lymphoma.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1115" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/lymphoma.jpg" alt="lymphoma" width="750" height="374" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/lymphoma.jpg 750w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/lymphoma-300x150.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The growth rate is different for different lymphomas and they have different lymphocyte cells. For people who aren’t aware, Lymphoma and Leukemia are not the same because both the cancers start in different cells. Lymphoma begins in the infection fighting lymphocytes as mentioned before while Leukemia begins in blood forming cells within the bone marrow. </span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;"><b>Symptoms </b></span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The symptoms of Lymphoma are not very severe in the beginning. They include swelling on the lymph nodes, shortness of breath, fever, cough, weight loss, fatigue, itching and night sweats.</span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;"><b>Diagnosis</b></span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The oncologist will carry out a physical examination and ask for one of the tests including Biopsy, MRI, chest X ray, Molecular Test and PET scan and Blood Test based on the examination.</span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;"><b>Treatment </b></span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The treatment is based on the diagnosis that includes Chemotherapy, Radiation therapy, targeted therapy and immune therapy primarily. If the cancer does not subside then stem cell transplant is the alternative. This treatment involves killing the cancer cells but along with them even the stem cells get destroyed. So, after the therapy is completed, you need to get a stem cell transplant. There are two types of stem cell transplants namely autologous and allogeneic transplant. Autologous transplant involves replacement of own stem cells and allogeneic involves donor stem cells transplant. </span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;"><b>Causes/ Risk Factors– </b></span><span style="font-size: medium;">As yet scientists haven’t been able to figure out exact cause of this cancer but risk factors include the following – </span></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Weak Immune System due to some organ transplant or HIV/Aids or some immune disease by birth.</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Virus infections like Hepatitis C, Epstein Barr or lymphoma(HTLV-1) / T-cell leukemia </span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Exposure to chemicals or benzene use for killing plant bugs and weeds</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">The age group prone to Hodgkin lymphoma is 15-40 years and 55 or older while for Non Hodgkin Lymphoma it is 60 plus. </span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-size: medium;">Family history of having this condition.</span></p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8220;<a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is one of the recognized premiere institute in Bangalore, to start <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/">surgical oncology</a> department at its inception to cater to the growing needs of the society and offers surgical treatment to various cancers.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Depression and Anxiety can be as Harmful to Health as Smoking</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/depression-and-anxiety-can-be-as-harmful-to-health-as-smoking/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 11:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Depression and Anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1068</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A recent study has revealed that people who have high anxiety levels as well as depression are at 65% higher risk of developing a heart condition, 64% at a higher risk of developing a stroke, 50% high risk of developing high blood pressure and 87% higher risk of developing arthritis. Comparatively, even people who smoke &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/depression-and-anxiety-can-be-as-harmful-to-health-as-smoking/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Depression and Anxiety can be as Harmful to Health as Smoking"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A recent study has revealed that people who have high anxiety levels as well as depression are at 65% higher risk of developing a heart condition, 64% at a higher risk of developing a stroke, 50% high risk of developing high blood pressure and 87% higher risk of developing arthritis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Comparatively, even people who smoke and are obese are at the same level of risk thus pointing out the importance of mental health condition with respect to physical health. The lead author Andrea Niles of the University of California San Francisco said that hence smoking and obesity as well as mental health conditions like depression and anxiety pose the same risk.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1069" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking.jpg" alt="Depression and Anxiety can be as Harmful to Health as Smoking" width="936" height="624" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking.jpg 936w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Yet, cancer is not included in the list of conditions that are a result of depression and anxiety. The co-author Aoife O Donovan from UCSF has said that the study is similar to the other studies in terms of the psychological distress being a strong predictor of many types of cancers. She also asked people not to attribute <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/">cancer diagnosis</a> to stress, depression and anxiety history.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Niles also said that the study was the first one that compared between anxiety and depression with smoking and obesity as potential risk factors for health conditions that could be life threatening.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In a nutshell, the study is only brings to light the fact that mental health is to be cared for equally and has the ability to do equal harm as addictions or unfit habits do. And that it is time that people shun away the taboo around mental health and habits and take a step to consult mental health practitioners if they are facing issues like depression, anxiety or more so that they can be treated not only for it but also to avoid their physical health being affected.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is of the <a href="http://college.rrmch.org/">best medical colleges in Bangalore</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early Cancer Detection To Be Easier In The Coming Times</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-cancer-detection-to-be-easier-in-the-coming-times/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 04:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Early Cancer Detection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=784</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Cancer is killing people across the world and there is a significant rise in the number of deaths that are caused by cancer. We are all aware that the cancer detection and treatment as well as life expectancy has lot of do with the stage of detection. The earlier you detect it the more the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-cancer-detection-to-be-easier-in-the-coming-times/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Early Cancer Detection To Be Easier In The Coming Times"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Cancer is killing people across the world and there is a significant rise in the number of deaths that are caused by cancer. We are all aware that the cancer detection and treatment as well as life expectancy has lot of do with the stage of detection. The earlier you detect it the more the life expectancy and possibility of eliminating it completely. Here is some good news in the regard. Researchers at MIT have recently found a way to detect cancer at an early stage which always has been a challenge as the particular proteins that cancer cells secrete are not easy to detect, thus aiding cancer growth prior discovery.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Early-Cancer-Detection-To-Be-Easier-In-The-Coming-Times-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-785 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Early-Cancer-Detection-To-Be-Easier-In-The-Coming-Times-1-300x168.jpg" alt="Early Cancer Detection To Be Easier In The Coming Times" width="300" height="168" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Now there is a breakthrough in cancer research at MIT wherein, using nanotechnology, researchers can make tests to detect potential life threatening conditions like Alzheimer’s, cancer and more in the early stage. They used the nano-technology in the blood scanner. It is especially useful in detection on cancers within the body like ovarian, pancreatic and lung cancer including 100 types.</p>
<p align="justify">Presently, the most popular method of detecting cancer is MRI scan, CT scan or a biopsy. But, the fact still remains that even these technologies aren’t able to detect micro-metasteses or micro tumors due to the minute size of them. Using Nanotechnology though, practitioners can effectively detect them and find out where the cancer is growing and spreading. These light emitting nano particles allow tracking of cancer in real time. The results are based on the research that was carried out by a team on a mouse model with human breast cancer. They injected the nano-probes, tiny X-ray using optical devices for detecting micro-tumors. These probes move around or commute through the blood stream and locate the cancer cells where-ever there are. These work quite faster than MRI and have the ability to identify micro-tumors in suprarenal, adrenal, bones and other animal glands.</p>
<p align="justify">In a nutshell, the researchers believe that they have been able to find the address of cancer now, as it can detect withing the first five years itself, if used. If this projection works in humans well then it will help save many lives.</p>
<p align="justify"><a title="RRMCH" href="http://www.rrmch.org" target="_blank">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</a> is one of the leading <a title="Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank">cancer hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microscopic Robots To Replace Doctors Sooner or Later?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/microscopic-robots-to-replace-doctors-sooner-or-later/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 11:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forensic science colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microscopic Robots To Replace Doctors Sooner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=672</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Microscopic robots may seem a new phrase but we all are aware of nanotechnology, the word at least if not more. Now, nanometer is equal to one billionth of a meter and is smallest of the scales. It is apparently the size we consider for atoms and cells inside the body. We all know are &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/microscopic-robots-to-replace-doctors-sooner-or-later/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Microscopic Robots To Replace Doctors Sooner or Later?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify"><em><strong>Microscopic robots may seem a new phrase but we all are aware of nanotechnology</strong></em>, the word at least if not more. Now, nanometer is equal to one billionth of a meter and is smallest of the scales. It is apparently the size we consider for atoms and cells inside the body. We all know are body is made of millions of cells and atoms but when it comes to treatment, it happens on a greater scale. Cells or atoms are not even visible through the naked eye. So, nanotechnology works at the cellular level thus matching the levels at which our body cells or atoms work. Though, its not perfected as yet, we’ve certainly come out with a lot of solutions based on nanotechnology and are probably heading northward in the arena.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Microscopic-Robots-To-Replace-Doctors-Sooner-or-Later-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-673" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Microscopic-Robots-To-Replace-Doctors-Sooner-or-Later-1-1.jpg" alt="Microscopic Robots To Replace Doctors Sooner or Later" width="736" height="525" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">In layman’s language using nanotechnology, we can shrink the medical tools used for treating or intervention in the human body to the size of cells or atoms present inside. Using the right size tool will help intricate interventions with simplicity. Surgeries with complexities and involving heavy blood loss can be done away with using such a technology. There is a lot of scope to this technology, as per the researchers and experts in the field. Be it targeted drug treatment to treating critical illnesses like <a title="cancer hospitals in bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/cervical-cancer-spreading-at-alarming-rates-in-india/" target="_blank">cancers</a>, where nano scalpels are presently being used for damage repair of individual cells.</p>
<p align="justify">Furthermore, there is a possibility of improved biological sensors as well as disease diagnosis in the times to come. Just imagine subatomic robots just like a miniature army of soldiers getting into your body and fighting against the ailment to cure you off, that too without any major blood filled surgeries or incisions.</p>
<p align="justify">One of the examples on which researchers are presently working in some part of the world is ‘drug agnostic’. Consider a reservoir miniature in nature filled with a drug that needs to be delivered to a certain part of the body. All this needs to be done in a sustained linear way without using pumps, valves or any electrically powered tool. Its works through the nano channel delivery system (NDS). On the basis of the size of the drug molecules, the nano channel membranes are tailored and implanted below the skin. It then moves through the membranes into the patients body. As per the researchers, presently, the nano channel size is a barrier to its movement and lower the size to 2.5 nano meters would definitely help overcome the snag and also help control the drug delivery speed. Looking at the potential of this project a multi-million dollar grant has been already approved for the same.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, the use of <strong>microscopic robots</strong> for treatment is just at its infancy stage and a lot needs to be worked on yet, but positively it would take less than a decade to see it reach the operation theatres of hospitals and that’s definitely a good sign.</p>
<p align="justify">Know about <a title="Best medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">best medical college</a> and <a title="Good Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">hospitals in Banglaore</a></p>
<p align="justify">* Disclaimer – Sourced from the internet. Verification required</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cervical Cancer Spreading At Alarming Rates In India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cervical-cancer-spreading-at-alarming-rates-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 05:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cervical cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rrmch.org/blog/?p=392</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Cervical cancer cases in India are increasing at an alarming rate, so much so this monster is known to take 200 lives of women in India, on a daily basis. Over 60,000 deaths have been accounted during the year 2015 itself. It is thus, one of the most common cancers in women in India alongside &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cervical-cancer-spreading-at-alarming-rates-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Cervical Cancer Spreading At Alarming Rates In India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Cervical-Cancer-Hospitals-in-Bangalore-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-393" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Cervical-Cancer-Hospitals-in-Bangalore-1.jpg" alt="Cervical-Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore" width="601" height="492" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Cervical cancer cases in India</em> are increasing at an alarming rate, so much so this monster is known to take 200 lives of women in India, on a daily basis. Over 60,000 deaths have been accounted during the year 2015 itself. It is thus, one of the most <strong>common cancers in women in India</strong> alongside breast cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>FACTS ABOUT CERVICAL CANCER</strong><br />
<em>Human Papolloma virus or HPV causes Cervical cancer</em>. It usually effects women in the age group of 40-65, but 55-65 is the age group with highest associated risks. The virus is easily transmitted through skin to skin contact and not just sexually, which is a myth many of us believe in. In 90% of the cases, the immune system takes care of clearing the virus. The remaining 10% whose bodies are not able to create the antibodies needed to kill these invaders get affected by Cervical cancer. Also, no test is still available for knowing whether your body has the ability to create the antibodies required to defeat the cervical cancer virus or not. The rural areas bear the brunt more so due to failure in doing checkups and ignorance.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, it has been also found that women don’t really seem to be willing to take the vaccine available for cervical cancer. In India, its majorly because most of them don’t know about it or because of the cost factor. Well, the side effects also are a major concern for people with numerous myths surrounding the condition doing rounds, already. One such myth is infertility. Though, against the myth about the side effects of cervical cancer, lies the fact sheet of over 200 vaccinated cases that proves no serious long term side effects of the vaccine. Another fact being that over 65 countries have included this vaccine as a part of their health program already. The awareness levels are also less, even though there has been a lot of effort in the area for the past three decades.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT &amp; PREVENTION</strong><br />
As mentioned<strong> vaccines for cervical cancer</strong> are already available and as per experts one of this vaccines is 99% effective in prevention in young women. It’s the nonavalent, but it has yet to see the light of day in India. But, the bivalent and quadravalent vaccines are readily available and provide around 70% protection against the earlier mentioned nonavalent which offers 90%. The world health organization has recommended the vaccine for age groups of 9-13 years old girls due to its immunogenic ability at this age.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In a nutshell,<em> cervical cancer is a deadly condition in women and India</em> needs to have an action plan against it. Each one of us is responsible for our family and kids. So, go ahead and shield your girls against this deadly disease by vaccinating them early on. The HPV virus has the ability to stay in the body of a woman for a decade before it turns cancerous therefore it is advisable to do a pap smear test on a regular basis for detection of any symptoms, early on. For women not eligible for vaccination it is advisable to take up the Pap smear test after a certain age on a recommended basis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">RRMCH conducted <a title="Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/news/cervical-cancer/" target="_blank">Cervical Cancer</a>  awareness programs</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
