<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Hot Tea Increases the cancer &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/hot-tea-increases-the-cancer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 09:06:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Drinking Hot Tea Increases The Chances Of Cancer By 5 Times</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/hot-tea-increases-cancer/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 09:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot Tea Increases the cancer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=789</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yes, you read that right. Though it does not hold true for all, it does hold true for men who drink tea while they are also regular consumers of alcohol and smoke tobacco. Particularly in under developed regions of countries like China esophageal cancer is quite common. Chinese men drink tea besides smoking and being &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/hot-tea-increases-cancer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Drinking Hot Tea Increases The Chances Of Cancer By 5 Times"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Yes, you read that right. Though it does not hold true for all, it does hold true for men who drink tea while they are also regular consumers of alcohol and smoke tobacco. Particularly in under developed regions of countries like China <strong>esophageal cancer</strong> is quite common. Chinese men drink tea besides smoking and being alcoholic. Esophageal cancer has very low survival rates and the rate at which it is spreading its wings in these countries is worrisome.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Drinking-Hot-Tea-Increases-The-Chances-Of-Cancer-By-5-Times-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-790 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Drinking-Hot-Tea-Increases-The-Chances-Of-Cancer-By-5-Times-1-300x168.jpg" alt="Drinking Hot Tea Increases The Chances Of Cancer By 5 Times" width="300" height="168" /></a></p>
<p>Researchers of the National Natural science foundation of china as well as national key research and development program went on to undertake a survey in China to test if consuming hot tea is associated with esophageal cancer risk. The study was done on 456155 participants between the age-group of 30 and 79 for around 9.2 years of median followup. The researchers found out that drinking hot tea while being an alcoholic and smoker did increase the risk of esophageal cancer. The participants who smoked, consumed alcohol and hot tea did tend to risk esophageal cancer risk by 5 times as compared to participants with none of the three habits. Though, the participants who did not consume alcohol or smoke were not subject to the risk of esophageal cancer.</p>
<p>The study is based on observations and hence its you cannot determine the cause and effect link, but the researchers do speculate that hot tea does damage the lining of the tissue inside the esophagus, thus increasing the chances of injury due to smoking and drinking as well. It can possibly form inflammatory compounds post repeated irritation to the esophagus, thereby increasing the risk of cancer as well.</p>
<p>Having said that, we have also come across contradictory statements with regards to cancer and tea. In the recent past WHO did conclude that beverages with temperatures above 149 degrees F including did increase the risk of esophageal cancer, however tea has been excluded most of the times in the past from the cancer causing beverages. Furthermore green tea is known to be lowering cancer risk as well.</p>
<p>So a better idea is to consume tea at less higher temperatures that do not risk the chance of causing esophageal <a title="Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank">cancer</a>. Obviously, it goes without saying that you need to stay away from addictions like smoking or alcohol as well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*source from internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
