<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>laser operation for eyes &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/laser-operation-for-eyes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 08:38:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cataract Surgery &#8211; What All You Need To Know?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cataract-surgery-what-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 08:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore eye hospital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cataract Surgery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lasik operations in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=868</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Though cataracts are a common amongst people over 65 years, they can happen in one or both even in the age group of 50 plus. Cataracts are common because they are only a result of aging process. Cataract causes the lens in our eye to become cloudy and results into vision loss inspite of wearing &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cataract-surgery-what-all-you-need-to-know/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Cataract Surgery &#8211; What All You Need To Know?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Though cataracts are a common amongst people over 65 years, they can happen in one or both even in the age group of 50 plus. Cataracts are common because they are only a result of aging process. Cataract causes the lens in our eye to become cloudy and results into vision loss inspite of wearing spectacles. This can happen in one eye or both as well. The cataract surgery is performed to remove the cloudy lens and replace it with an artificial lens known as intraocular lens in order to restore clarity in vision. It is a very simple and speedy surgery which requires just around 15-20 minutes of time. No overnight stay is required and the patient is discharged the same day within few hours of the surgery.</p>
<p align="justify">The cataract surgery performed these days is a very advanced one known a phacoemulsification or ‘phaco’ carried out using a high frequency ultrasound device that has the ability to break down the cloudy lens into pieces. These are then removed gently from the eye with the help of suction. ‘Phaco’ has greatly reduced the complications of eyes which the earlier surgeries had a risk part of it, besides the advantage of faster healing.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Cataract-Surgery-RRMCH-Bangalore-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-869" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Cataract-Surgery-RRMCH-Bangalore-1-1.jpg" alt="Cataract Surgery " width="500" height="362" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">The process typically includes the surgeon removing the cloudy lens from the eye and then inserting the intraocular lens and positioning is properly behind the pupil and iris exactly at the location of the natural lens. It very rare but sometimes in special cases the lens is placed in the front of the iris and pupil instead of the back. The procedure is concluded by closing the incision in the eye with a stitch or sometimes without it. In order to further protect the eye in the early stages of the surgery, a shield is placed over it as well.</p>
<p><strong>Cataract Surgery &#8211; After Care</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The eye drops provided by the doctor have to be used as per the doctor’s recommendation so as to avoid watering or itching.</li>
<li>Regular day to day activities can be performed as usual but some of them need to be restricted. Activities like reading, watching TV, walking and writing can be done but activities like lifting heavy loads, bending a lot and likes need to be restricted.</li>
<li>Do not perform strenuous exercises but light can do.</li>
<li>Wear your protective eye covering all the time even when sleeping. Do not sleep on the side of the operated eye.</li>
<li>Avoid water contact with the eyes during bath or shower.</li>
<li>Do not rub your eyes because it can cause infection.</li>
<li>Restrict yourself from swimming for atleast two weeks.</li>
<li>Do not drive for atleast 24 hours after surgery.</li>
<li>Avoid wearing any kind of eye makeup as well until your doctor permits.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>RRMCH one of the <strong><a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">best ophthalmology/eye hospitals in Bangalore</a></strong> for LASIK operations, Dr Vijay Kumar Srivastava eye specialist in bangalore</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eye Lid Surgery in India &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eye-lid-surgery-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 12:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=833</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As we age, it shows and one area that is show clearly is the region around the eyes. One of the prominent difference we see is in the upper eyelids, under eyes and eye brows, which tend to sag with age. Here is the good news, even if age causes the mentioned differences in eyes, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eye-lid-surgery-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Eye Lid Surgery in India &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">As we age, it shows and one area that is show clearly is the region around the eyes. One of the prominent difference we see is in the upper eyelids, under eyes and eye brows, which tend to sag with age. Here is the good news, even if age causes the mentioned differences in eyes, they can be corrected with a surgery called blepharoplasty. It is popularly known as eye lift and is done by women specifically for enhancement of their looks or appearance by fixing their droopy and dull eyelids. The surgery procedure involves removal of fat pockets and excess skin from upper and lower lids. Though, patients who already have ophthalmic issues are excluded from taking up this surgery.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-834 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-300x144.jpg" alt="Eye Lid Surgery in India" width="300" height="144" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-300x144.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-768x370.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1.jpg 889w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">This is a sort of cosmetic surgery done for alteration of eye aesthetics in a way. Here what kind of corrections it can do for your eyes.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>1. Dull or fatigued eyes</strong> – With this eyelift surgery the work on correcting eyes that make the person look older and tired than actually she is</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>2. Excess skin on upper eye lid</strong> &#8211; If you have excess skin on upper eye lid it can also obstruct your eyesight. So, this surgery helps in removing the excess skin or the fat pockets there that can obstruct the eyesight.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>3. Puffy Upper Eyelids</strong> – Sometimes puppy eyes are result of genetics than sleeplessness. Blepharoplasty surgery can fix this issue</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>NON INVASIVE OPTION</strong><br />
For some doctors might recommend the non-invasive procedure as compared to the invasive one. This is considered to be a more appropriate course of treatment as well compared to the invasive one. The non -invasive treatment involves usage of Botox injections for enhancing looks by reducing wrinkles. Even facial fillers are used in this treatment for the purpose of reducing the dark circles and eye bags.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>RESULTS</strong><br />
The results of the surgery are never instant. Primarily, you may see inflammation and swelling around the area where it is done and it would generally take a couple of days to a week to subside. Once the healing occurs best results are seen.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong><a title="medical colleges in bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> <a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">Ophthalmology(eye) department</a></strong> is registered under District Blindness Control Society and has a successful record of offering the best possible care for our patients. We conduct eye screening camps every month at Mudaliar Sangha, Rajajinagar in Bangalore. We also provide treatment free for patients who can’t afford to pay their daily bills. We provide services to about 100 patients every day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Reduce Diabetes Related Eye Issues? A sneak Peek</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diabetes-related-eye-issues/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 08:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospitals in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes eye problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diabetic eye disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=811</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Diabetes can affect your eyes as early as 40 through 60 years and can result into blindness if left undetected or untreated. At an advanced stage it can cause irreparable damage to the retina besides bleeding and oedema. The only way out here is prevention. To prevent yourself from getting into this soup called blindness &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diabetes-related-eye-issues/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to Reduce Diabetes Related Eye Issues? A sneak Peek"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Diabetes can affect your eyes as early as 40 through 60 years and can result into blindness if left undetected or untreated. At an advanced stage it can cause irreparable damage to the retina besides bleeding and oedema. The only way out here is prevention. To prevent yourself from getting into this soup called blindness due to diabetes you need to arrange a regular may be a yearly eye checkup. If you live in USA or UK, there is a definite procedure under which once you are listed under the diabetic ones you automatically get listed under the eye checkup program which allows you to examine your eyes every year all your life.</p>
<p>In India there are over 100 million diabetics already and hence the eye checkup facility is necessary. Either you do a private personal checkup every year or you can do it through a non-profit organization like eyebetes foundation. This foundation has been established with an objective to bridge the gap between diabetes and eye issues. It provides free eye screening camps, carries out further research in the field and also spreads awareness on the same through their various initiatives.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank"><strong>BEST EYE HOSPITALS IN BANGALORE</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Diabetes-Related-Eye-Issues-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-812 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Diabetes-Related-Eye-Issues-1-1.jpg" alt=" best eye hospitals in bangalore" width="306" height="165" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Eyebetes Camps</strong><br />
These camps carry out free checks for eye and blood pressure as well as sugar. You can register by providing your name and mobile number age and gender to get a unique ID for the process. The reports are texted to the participants post the tests and are also available on the website to review for the patient. The eyebetes foundation representative also follow up after a month to enquire from patients who have eye issues whether they have taken further treatment.</p>
<p><strong>Research</strong><br />
The foundation uses data or research from the west to devise prevention and treatment plans for Indian Diabetics. Though food habits, genetics, etc. of Indians are very different from others the international data still is of great use in understanding the Indian diabetic and creating custom made prevention and treatment plans.<br />
The eyebetes foundation has successfully carried out over half a lac screenings and spread awareness across almost 9 lacs people living in Mumbai and its sub burbs. If you are a diabetic and have not screened your eyes do it now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brain Has Eyes Too &#8211; A sneak Peek Into Neurons</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-has-eyes-too-a-sneak-peek-into-neurons/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 09:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ent hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=704</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yes, that is true. Nicknamed as ‘Jennifer Aniston’ a neuron based on the participant study which showed that one of the neuron of his brain lit up on recognizing the face of particular people like Jennifer Aniston or Hillary Clinton. So, this neuron was named after Jennifer Aniston. This report further revealed that one single &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-has-eyes-too-a-sneak-peek-into-neurons/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Brain Has Eyes Too &#8211; A sneak Peek Into Neurons"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, that is true. Nicknamed as ‘Jennifer Aniston’ a neuron based on the participant study which showed that one of the neuron of his brain lit up on recognizing the face of particular people like Jennifer Aniston or Hillary Clinton. So, this neuron was named after Jennifer Aniston. This report further revealed that one single specific cell lit up whenever a person’s certain conscious experience was concerned. This throws further light on the response of brain cells the relation of the activities with consciousness. Though, understanding the scope and science of human consciousness is a mystery that is yet to be unfolded and even researchers cannot say with surety if these neurons lead to conscious thoughts.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Brain-Has-Eyes-Too-A-sneak-Peek-Into-Neurons-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-705" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Brain-Has-Eyes-Too-A-sneak-Peek-Into-Neurons-1-1.jpg" alt="Brain Has Eyes Too - A sneak Peek Into Neurons" width="665" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>There were studies around the same carried out in 2008 which used a masking technique. This technique showed an image of a popular person like Aniston for 16 milliseconds immediately followed by a pattern Image muddling the face afterimage on the retina, thus making it rather hard for the brain to register what it saw. Later on in another study that used a method for hiding images from participants awareness. The phenomenon used for the experiment is called attentional blink wherein two target images are shown in a high speed streaming along with some other similar images. This results in a person often not able to recognize the second image targeted.</p>
<p>A similar study was carried out over a list of 21 patients under epilepsy and brains were fitted with special treatment electrodes. The trial included showing 14 different images predetermined by the scientist as familiar to the person. Further each one had a particular activity of specific brain cell. Now, when the trial was conducted, the researchers asked the participants to concentrate on two target images of the 14. All the images would later be flashed on the screen for 150 milliseconds. The medial temporal lobe was under constant monitoring during and after the trail and the researchers queried the participants if they had seen two images of familiar faces.</p>
<p>Every cell with unique signature was studied as it lit up and helped researchers link a brain cell pattern to particular images and had the ability to tell about the image represented even though<br />
the participants are not aware of it.</p>
<p>Furthermore, research work is on as the researchers believe that they are at the intersection of perception and memory and investigation was needed to find out the results of direct stimulation of neurons.</p>
<p><a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore</a>   <a title="Best Neuro Hospital in India" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/" target="_blank">Best Neuro Hospital in India</a>  <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Best Hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
