<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>health tips for women &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/health-tips-for-women/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 05:28:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Health Tips For Women Above 40</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/health-tips-for-women-above-40/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 05:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health tips for women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=846</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As women age and surpass the middle age milestone called 40, even though age is just a number, practically the body does have to deal with certain issues that crop up as we enter this phase. So what can you do to keep your health in optimal condition? Here are few tips that might just &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/health-tips-for-women-above-40/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Health Tips For Women Above 40"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">As women age and surpass the middle age milestone called 40, even though age is just a number, practically the body does have to deal with certain issues that crop up as we enter this phase. So what can you do to keep your health in optimal condition? Here are few tips that might just help you out.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Health First</strong> – Many a times while keeping the family needs as a priority women forget to check on their health issues or ignore It most of the times. One needs to understand that only when one is healthy then only can they take care of their loved ones.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Health-Tips-For-Women-Above-40-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-847" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Health-Tips-For-Women-Above-40-1-1.jpg" alt="Health Tips For Women Above 40" width="702" height="336" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Body Check</strong> – If you haven’t done a <a title="Health Checkup packages in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/health-checkups/" target="_blank">medical checkup its time</a>. Once you hit 40 do it once every two to three years. Check for deficiencies in your body particularly Calcium, Vitamin D and B12. Vitamin D and Calcium are needed for strong bones and in your 40’s you require 1000mg of calcium and 400 to 800 UI of vitamin D every single day so either you have to switch to that sort of diet or go for supplements. The checks you need at this age include eye testing, BP test, Mole check, Mammogram, Glucose test Pap and pelvic test as well as thyroid. All these need to be done every 2 – 3 years approximately.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Exercise</strong> – Exercise is good for all but more so once you turn 40. You are aging and you need to exercise to stay fit. Kick start your day with strength training and see the change within 6 months. Just dedicate 30 minutes a day to it.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Diet Check</strong> – It’s time you revamp your diet and go for a balanced one which will help you cope with your deficiencies and keep your cholesterol levels under check. Having breakfast daily can help greatly against skipping it. A study reveals that over a period of time people who take good breakfast lose more weight than the ones who make breakfast their smallest meal. Get in a lot of protein as they are mood boosters and help you relieve yourself from poor memory, excessive thinking or depression.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Get good Sleep</strong> – Sleeping helps you reduce stress and hence a good sleep is important. Particularly women don’t care about it much and it ultimately takes a toll on their health. Also try to control your stress through meditation and yoga. This will help you stay fit physically and mentally.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Spend time with Girl Friends</strong> – Ya, you might be busy to the core but take out time to hangout with your girl buddies because it is found that women with socialization or hobby activities have less risk of heart disease or less blood pressure and diabetes issues.</p>
<p align="justify"><a title="Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> has got the <a title="Master Health Checkup in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/health-checkups/" target="_blank">best health checkup packages in Bangalore</a>. You can check out the pricing packages of 4 plans available for all employees and individuals.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
