<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>top hospitals in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/top-hospitals-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 23:08:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Chronic Kidney Disease</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/chronic-kidney-disease/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 23:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best kidney hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysore road hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=825</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Chronic Kidney disease or CKD is s result of loss of kidney function over a period of time. Practically, the kidneys fail, if you may say so. There are though, five stages of CKD depending upon the severity. When the kidneys fail the waste, water and toxic substances accumulate in the body because the kidneys &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/chronic-kidney-disease/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Chronic Kidney Disease"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chronic Kidney disease or CKD is s result of loss of kidney function over a period of time. Practically, the kidneys fail, if you may say so. There are though, five stages of CKD depending upon the severity. When the kidneys fail the waste, water and toxic substances accumulate in the body because the kidneys are not able to excrete them. This can further result in conditions like acidosis (excessive acidity of body fluids), disorders related to fatty acids and cholesterol, anemia and high blood pressure.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-828 size-large" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-1024x576.jpg" alt="Chronic Kidney Disease" width="615" height="345" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" /></a></p>
<p>While Stage five is obviously the end stage known as kidney or renal failure which results in complete kidney function failure. At this stage the person needs dialysis to survive or kidney transplantation.<br />
Acute kidney failure can also lead to loss of kidney function but it’s faster over a period of few days or weeks. But, this condition is reversible many times and there is a possibility of complete recovery of kidney function. But sometimes, it could end up as irreversible and require dialysis.</p>
<p><strong>STAGES</strong><br />
Here’s a run-down the stages of chronic kidney diseases.<br />
1. Slight damage with normal or increased filtration      GFR &gt; 90<br />
2. Mild decrease in kidney function                                GFR range 60-90<br />
3. Moderate decrease in kidney function                       GFR range 30 -59<br />
4. Severe decrease in kidney function                           GFR range 15-29<br />
5. Kidney Failure                                                            GFR &lt;15 / Dialysis</p>
<p><strong>DIAGNOSIS</strong><br />
To check for kidney damage, you need to undergo a few tests that include checking the level of waste products like creatinine and urea, in blood and urine test for abnormalities that indicate kidney damage cause. You may have to undergo an ultrasound for kidney structure assessment and biopsy for determining the cause of kidney problem. The diagnosis is based on results of Glomerular filtration rate and includes details like patient’s age, gender, race and serum creatinine levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="best kidney hospitals in bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/urology/" target="_blank"><strong>BEST KIDNEY HOSPITALS IN BANGALORE</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>RISK FACTORS</strong><br />
Some of the common risk factors of Chronic kidney disease include smoking, hypertension, obesity and diabetes mellitus.</p>
<p><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
After course of treatment is decided after determining the cause of the disease. Some kidney complications are treatable while some are not. The treatment procedure includes controlling the symptoms, reducing the complications and slowing the progression process through tested methods. In case the kidneys are severely damage then end stage treatment is provided. The medications used include those for reducing cholesterol levels, treating anemia and high blood pressure, reducing the swelling and protecting your bones. You might also be required to go on low protein diet to minimize wastage in blood.</p>
<p><strong>END STAGE TREAMENT</strong><br />
If your kidneys fail then the only treatment options available are dialysis or transplant. Dialysis is the process of removal of waste products from the body artificially with the help of a machine viz hemodialysis or a thin tube (catheter) fitted in the abdomen and dialysis solution that absorbs the waste plus excess fluids and is drained out. viz peritoneal dialysis. Kidney transplant on the other side is an expensive but better procedure because it involves replacing your kidney with a healthy kidney of a donor surgically. It could be of a deceased or living person. Though, medications after the procedure are to be taken life long for your body to accept the organ through life but no dialysis.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Complications from Cosmetic Surgeries</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/complications-from-cosmetic-surgeries/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 11:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Complications from Cosmetic Surgeries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cosmetic Surgeries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cosmetic Surgeries Complications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=807</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The cosmetic market place is booming at present and you can find health spas skin clinics and cosmetic services easily across the city. People are getting more and more health and look conscious and hence opting for services for cosmetic experts. Celebrities and high profile ladies are known to be opting for services of renowned &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/complications-from-cosmetic-surgeries/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Complications from Cosmetic Surgeries"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The cosmetic market place is booming at present and you can find health spas skin clinics and cosmetic services easily across the city. People are getting more and more health and look conscious and hence opting for services for cosmetic experts. Celebrities and high profile ladies are known to be opting for services of renowned cosmetic experts to keep looking radiant and attractive for years.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Cosmetic surgeries are also popular these days and many people even if being scared of surgeries do opt for them for benefits they offer. But, it is always advisable to look at both sides of the coin.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignright wp-image-808 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1-300x151.jpg" alt="Complications from Cosmetic Surgeries" width="300" height="151" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1-300x151.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1-768x387.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Damaged Nerves</strong> &#8211; Numbness and tingling are some symptoms of nerve damage post a plastic surgery. There have been cases where women experience sensitivity issues after cosmetic surgeries like breast augmentation. Over 10% even lose nipple sensitivity as per experts.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Deep Vein Thrombosis</strong> &#8211; This is caused due to clotting of blood in deep vein. This can further develop in a rare life threatening complication of lungs, if the clot in the veins breaks and commutes into them.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Infections</strong> &#8211; Infections of internal or external type can occur in many cases. One of them is cellulitis, a common infection type caused in around 4 percent of people undergoing breast cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Organ Issues</strong> – Some cosmetic procedures like liposuction can damage internal organs. This is when the surgical probe comes in internal organs contact thus leading to punctures or visceral perforations further leading to additional surgery.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Scarring</strong> – Cosmetic treatments do include surgeries and surgeries bring along scarring. The irony being that the purpose of cosmetic treatments is looking good but it does give scars which is troublesome.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Hematoma</strong> – It is caused in up to 6% of the people who undergo breast augmentation procedures and is a pocket of blood that looks like a large painful bruise.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Anaesthesia Complications</strong> &#8211; When patients are to undergo cosmetic surgeries, they are given anaesthesia, a medication that causes unconsciousness. It could lead to stroke, lung infection, heart attack or death like complications. One of the rarest being waking up in the middle of surgery.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The above are just some of the side effects or complications that can occur besides some others like blood loss or seroma and more. Having said that, you can lower the risk of these side effects by taking services from a credible doctor with good infrastructure.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">For <a title="Cosmetic Surgery in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/plastic-surgery/" target="_blank">Cosmetic Surgery Bangalore</a>, <strong>RRMCH</strong> provides the best results and regarded as one of the better <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">hospitals in Bangalore</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Early You Quit Smoking The Better For Your Lungs</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-early-you-quit-smoking-the-better-for-your-lungs/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 09:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quit Smoking The Better For Your Lungs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rajarajeswari hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stop smoking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=653</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[All of us are quite aware of the ill effects of Cigarette smoking to our health. Here is some information that you may consider as a bit of good news particularly if you’ve started smoking recently. Experts say that if a smoker quits smoking, his/ her lungs do heal to a certain extent. HOW SMOKING &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-early-you-quit-smoking-the-better-for-your-lungs/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Early You Quit Smoking The Better For Your Lungs"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">All of us are quite aware of the ill effects of Cigarette smoking to our health. Here is some information that you may consider as a bit of good news particularly if you’ve started smoking recently.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Experts say that if a smoker quits smoking, his/ her lungs do heal to a certain extent.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/How-Smoking-Affects-Your-Lungs-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignright wp-image-657 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/How-Smoking-Affects-Your-Lungs-1-300x180.jpg" alt="HOW SMOKING AFFECTS OUR LUNGS?" width="300" height="180" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/How-Smoking-Affects-Your-Lungs-1-300x180.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/How-Smoking-Affects-Your-Lungs-1.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>HOW SMOKING AFFECTS OUR LUNGS?</strong><br />
Well, as per the experts when you inhale the smoke of a cigar or cigarette, it causes inflammation and irritation of the lung’s delicate lining. Our lungs are lined with tiny hairs called cilia. After smoking, even upto several hours the brush like movement of cilia is slowed down because smoking causes temporary paralysis to them. Now, this in turn makes their job of cleaning the mucus and other substances like dust particles from the lung airways comparatively ineffective.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Furthermore, there is also an increase in production and thickness of mucus in the lungs of smokers. The inability of the cilia to chuck of the mucus out of the lungs leads to accumulation of the mucus within the lung airbags, thereby choking them and thus leading to cough issues. If smoking persists it can also lead to chronic bronchitis, a kind of lung infection.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>WHAT HAPPENS AFTER YOU QUIT SMOKING?</strong><br />
The short term inflammation caused by smoking can be reversed once you quit smoking. Though, initially for a few weeks post quitting, you may experience more coughing issues than you ever had while smoking. But, consider this as a positive signal is what experts say. You cough when the lungs are cleaning up your gunk which means that your cilia is again active and on the job of cleaning of mucus, from the airbags of your lungs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Gradually, the breathing improves and swelling decreases as the lining of the lungs is no longer exposed to the irritants produced due to smoke. The decrease in swelling also aids in regulating the airflow through the passageways.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>SOME IMPORTANT FACTS ABOUT SMOKING</strong><br />
Statistically speaking, 10 years after you quit smoking, your chances of getting lung cancer are practically reduced to half. This does mean that there is always a risk because once upon a time you were a smoker but the 50% reduction in its possibility is off course a great consideration to quit smoking.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Having said that, one fact that which needs a mention is that not everyone’s lungs get functioning normally once they quit smoking. It actually depends on the number of packets you have been smoking and the number of years you have been doing so. The term is known as pack years and in simple words, the greater the number of pack years, the greater the damage or to put it the other way, lesser the irreversibility. Further, Lung cancer is most likely to occur amongst smokers and ex-smokers and not amongst non smokers.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">So, if you’ve started smoking recently, quitting seems a smart idea. And if you have been smoking for a long time, it definitely is a wake up call to call smoking quits.</p>
<h4><a title="World NO Tobacco day - Awareness Initiative" href="http://college.rrmch.org/news/world-no-tobacco-day-awareness-initiative/" target="_blank">World NO Tobacco day “Awareness Initiative”</a> and <a title="No Tobacco Day" href="https://college.rrmch.org/news/no-tobacco-day/" target="_blank">No Tobacco Day</a> Conducted by <a title="Rajrajeswari Medical College and Hospital" href="http://www.rrmch.org" target="_blank">RRMCH</a></h4>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
