<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>eye specialist in Bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/eye-specialist-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best dermatologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1238</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Also known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and obesity. Many a times your skin shows you the symptoms and &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Also
known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do
not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a
very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and
obesity. 
</p>



<p>Many
a times your skin shows you the symptoms and it is preventable if you
exercise and maintain normal weight. As per reports around 90% of
cases of diabetes are apparently preventable if measures are taken on
time. Furthermore, if diabetes type 2 is left untreated then it could
also lead to life threatening health complications like heart attack,
kidney failure and strokes. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1239" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg 825w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>So,
why are the warning signs not taken seriously, is one question that
haunts many. The reason could be as simple as not taking them as
signs but simple health issues that could fade away with time or just
taking notice and delaying checkup till it’s forgotten. 
</p>



<p>Well,
let us run down some of the signs that could help you alert around
type 2 diabetes. 
</p>



<ol><li>

	 <strong>Frequent Washroom trips</strong>
	– high blood sugar means kidneys work hard to remove the excess
	sugar form the blood and hence it is considered to be an alarm for
	diabetes if one has to frequently wake up to go to pee. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Frequent urge to drink
	water</strong> – Due to frequent urination, even the urge to drink
	water increases due to dehydration
	</li><li>

	Fatigue – The energy levels
	of type 2 diabetes people are low due to deficiency of sugar through
	the blood stream to the body cells. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Hunger pangs</strong> – Due
	to lack of energy people suffering from type 2 diabetes tend to feel
	hungry on a constant basis even if they’d have eaten recently
	enough
	</li><li>

	<strong>Blurry Vision </strong>– At
	times high sugar could damage vision and result into blurred vision
	in one or both the eyes
	</li><li>

	<strong>Yeast Infections </strong>–
	Excess sugar in body could lead to yeast infection. The affected
	areas could get red, sore or itchy. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Tingling and Numbness</strong>
	– Due to rise in sugar levels people with this condition could
	experience tingling and numbess in their hands and feet. Known as
	neuropathy this condition has chances of worsening with time and
	hence early intervention is required.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Skin Darkening</strong> – For
	people suffering from diabetes, dark, velvety and soft patches
	appear on skin anywhere around the armpits, groin or neck. 
	
</li></ol>



<p> Perhaps, its not that difficult to be alarmed if we only pay attention at the signs. Early intervention could help deal with diabetes in a better way and also keep other life threatening conditions at bay.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brain Has Eyes Too &#8211; A sneak Peek Into Neurons</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-has-eyes-too-a-sneak-peek-into-neurons/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 09:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ent hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=704</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yes, that is true. Nicknamed as ‘Jennifer Aniston’ a neuron based on the participant study which showed that one of the neuron of his brain lit up on recognizing the face of particular people like Jennifer Aniston or Hillary Clinton. So, this neuron was named after Jennifer Aniston. This report further revealed that one single &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-has-eyes-too-a-sneak-peek-into-neurons/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Brain Has Eyes Too &#8211; A sneak Peek Into Neurons"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, that is true. Nicknamed as ‘Jennifer Aniston’ a neuron based on the participant study which showed that one of the neuron of his brain lit up on recognizing the face of particular people like Jennifer Aniston or Hillary Clinton. So, this neuron was named after Jennifer Aniston. This report further revealed that one single specific cell lit up whenever a person’s certain conscious experience was concerned. This throws further light on the response of brain cells the relation of the activities with consciousness. Though, understanding the scope and science of human consciousness is a mystery that is yet to be unfolded and even researchers cannot say with surety if these neurons lead to conscious thoughts.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Brain-Has-Eyes-Too-A-sneak-Peek-Into-Neurons-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-705" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Brain-Has-Eyes-Too-A-sneak-Peek-Into-Neurons-1-1.jpg" alt="Brain Has Eyes Too - A sneak Peek Into Neurons" width="665" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>There were studies around the same carried out in 2008 which used a masking technique. This technique showed an image of a popular person like Aniston for 16 milliseconds immediately followed by a pattern Image muddling the face afterimage on the retina, thus making it rather hard for the brain to register what it saw. Later on in another study that used a method for hiding images from participants awareness. The phenomenon used for the experiment is called attentional blink wherein two target images are shown in a high speed streaming along with some other similar images. This results in a person often not able to recognize the second image targeted.</p>
<p>A similar study was carried out over a list of 21 patients under epilepsy and brains were fitted with special treatment electrodes. The trial included showing 14 different images predetermined by the scientist as familiar to the person. Further each one had a particular activity of specific brain cell. Now, when the trial was conducted, the researchers asked the participants to concentrate on two target images of the 14. All the images would later be flashed on the screen for 150 milliseconds. The medial temporal lobe was under constant monitoring during and after the trail and the researchers queried the participants if they had seen two images of familiar faces.</p>
<p>Every cell with unique signature was studied as it lit up and helped researchers link a brain cell pattern to particular images and had the ability to tell about the image represented even though<br />
the participants are not aware of it.</p>
<p>Furthermore, research work is on as the researchers believe that they are at the intersection of perception and memory and investigation was needed to find out the results of direct stimulation of neurons.</p>
<p><a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore</a>   <a title="Best Neuro Hospital in India" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/" target="_blank">Best Neuro Hospital in India</a>  <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Best Hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
