<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cosmetic Surgeries Complications &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/cosmetic-surgeries-complications/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 11:10:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Complications from Cosmetic Surgeries</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/complications-from-cosmetic-surgeries/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 11:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Complications from Cosmetic Surgeries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cosmetic Surgeries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cosmetic Surgeries Complications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=807</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The cosmetic market place is booming at present and you can find health spas skin clinics and cosmetic services easily across the city. People are getting more and more health and look conscious and hence opting for services for cosmetic experts. Celebrities and high profile ladies are known to be opting for services of renowned &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/complications-from-cosmetic-surgeries/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Complications from Cosmetic Surgeries"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The cosmetic market place is booming at present and you can find health spas skin clinics and cosmetic services easily across the city. People are getting more and more health and look conscious and hence opting for services for cosmetic experts. Celebrities and high profile ladies are known to be opting for services of renowned cosmetic experts to keep looking radiant and attractive for years.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Cosmetic surgeries are also popular these days and many people even if being scared of surgeries do opt for them for benefits they offer. But, it is always advisable to look at both sides of the coin.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignright wp-image-808 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1-300x151.jpg" alt="Complications from Cosmetic Surgeries" width="300" height="151" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1-300x151.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1-768x387.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Complications-from-Cosmetic-Surgeries-1.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Damaged Nerves</strong> &#8211; Numbness and tingling are some symptoms of nerve damage post a plastic surgery. There have been cases where women experience sensitivity issues after cosmetic surgeries like breast augmentation. Over 10% even lose nipple sensitivity as per experts.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Deep Vein Thrombosis</strong> &#8211; This is caused due to clotting of blood in deep vein. This can further develop in a rare life threatening complication of lungs, if the clot in the veins breaks and commutes into them.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Infections</strong> &#8211; Infections of internal or external type can occur in many cases. One of them is cellulitis, a common infection type caused in around 4 percent of people undergoing breast cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Organ Issues</strong> – Some cosmetic procedures like liposuction can damage internal organs. This is when the surgical probe comes in internal organs contact thus leading to punctures or visceral perforations further leading to additional surgery.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Scarring</strong> – Cosmetic treatments do include surgeries and surgeries bring along scarring. The irony being that the purpose of cosmetic treatments is looking good but it does give scars which is troublesome.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Hematoma</strong> – It is caused in up to 6% of the people who undergo breast augmentation procedures and is a pocket of blood that looks like a large painful bruise.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Anaesthesia Complications</strong> &#8211; When patients are to undergo cosmetic surgeries, they are given anaesthesia, a medication that causes unconsciousness. It could lead to stroke, lung infection, heart attack or death like complications. One of the rarest being waking up in the middle of surgery.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The above are just some of the side effects or complications that can occur besides some others like blood loss or seroma and more. Having said that, you can lower the risk of these side effects by taking services from a credible doctor with good infrastructure.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">For <a title="Cosmetic Surgery in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/plastic-surgery/" target="_blank">Cosmetic Surgery Bangalore</a>, <strong>RRMCH</strong> provides the best results and regarded as one of the better <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">hospitals in Bangalore</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
