<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>best Neuro hospital in India &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/best-neuro-hospital-in-india/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 09:51:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1209</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them. It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them.  It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of us know that a declining oral health could be an indication of other risky health conditions that can also affect the quality of life of a human being.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1210" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>An article published in the <a href="http://www.jisponline.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology (opens in a new tab)">Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology</a> shows that there is a link between tooth loss as well as gum disease with stroke occurrence.  </p>



<p>As
per the conclusions of this article of 2010, gum disease is
responsible for increase in the risk of heart attack by 20%. Well,
there’s another team at the University of New Brunswick, NJ are
focusing on a connection between oral health and cognitive decline. 
</p>



<p>Even
a research team from Rutgers University carried out a two separate
studies around perceived stress and cognitive decline and published
the reports of two separate studies in the Journal of American
Geriatrics Society.</p>



<p>Talking
about other parts of the world like for example China, XinQi Dong,
the director of Rutgers University’s Institute for Health,
healthcare policy and aging research says that in china it was the
ethnic and racial minorities who were typically vulnerable to
consequences of poor oral health.  The reason being that already
there are barriers like socio economic status and language plus
access to preventive dental care is less. Particularly, the old
Chinese Americans are at a risk of oral health problems because of
lack of regular dental checkup and dental insurance. These studies
were carried out on Chinese elderly in Chicago of 60 years and above
age. The study involved quizzing question around oral health and then
asking them to complete five cognitive tests.  The second study asked
people if they had faced issues like dry mouth besides measuring
their social strain levels, social support and perceived stress with
the help of pre-defined scales. 
</p>



<p>The study involved 2700 Chinese Americans and results revealed that around half of them did had symptoms of tooth related issues. Also, there was not significant relationship between congnitive issues and gums but researchers believe that the participants may not have reported gum problems and ignored them as they do not cause major problems to health.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a> is one of the <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/">best neuro hospital in india</a></strong> </p>



<p>know more about <a href="https://www.rrdch.org"><strong>Top Dental Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Genetic Components Related To Left Handedness – A Study</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetic-components-related-to-left-handedness-a-study/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best neurologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1205</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A recent study by scientists reveals about regions of the Human DNA and their association with left handedness. These regions are connected to the brains language related features. An earlier study around handedness had revealed that genes were responsible for 25% of it but the type or name of the genes was unknown. In India &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetic-components-related-to-left-handedness-a-study/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Genetic Components Related To Left Handedness – A Study"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
recent study by scientists reveals about regions of the Human DNA and
their association with left handedness. These regions are connected
to the brains language related features. An earlier study around
handedness had revealed that genes were responsible for 25% of it but
the type or name of the genes was unknown. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Genetic-Components-Related-To-Left-Handedness.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1206" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Genetic-Components-Related-To-Left-Handedness.jpg 685w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Genetic-Components-Related-To-Left-Handedness-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 685px) 100vw, 685px" /></figure>



<p>In
India and across the world there were has been a lot of stigma and
taboo around being left handed. But, today rarely anyone is of the
belief or even discriminates between left and right handed people. 
</p>



<p>10%
of the population in the world is known to be left handed and also
includes many well-known individuals like Alert Einstein and Leonardo
da Vinci amongst them.  
</p>



<p>The
recent study was published in the journal ‘Brain’ and involved
the participation of 40,000 people including 38000 left handed ones.
After doing the genetic analysis, the researchers found that it was
the DNA regions that linked to left handedness strongly.  
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers the three regions are inside or are responsible
for protein code of brain development and patterning.  Proteins play
a significant role in making microtubules which are scaffolding like
building block and are responsible for guiding cell construction. 
</p>



<p>Microtubules
are made up of long chained molecules making up the physical
structure of the cells throughout the body also known as cytoskeleton
and have the ability to respond to cell singals by quickly assembling
and disassembling. 
</p>



<p>The
scientists did study brain scan details of 9000 participants after
analyzing their DNA samples.  The findings indicate that in left
handed people right and left side for brain that deals with language
coordinate in a better way compared to right handed ones. These
findings thus pave the path for getting deeper into finding if left
handed people are better in tasks that involve verbal communication
compared to the right handed ones. 
</p>



<p>Well, as per Gwenaelle Dououad, associate professor at the Wellcome Centre for Integrative Neuroimaging that it was apparently for the first time that they had been able to establish that in humans the handedness is linked to cytoskeletal differences in the brain.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Know more about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>On World Heart Day Decide on a Healthy Oil for Cooking</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/on-world-heart-day-decide-on-a-healthy-oil-for-cooking/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 09:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1029</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[It is not secret that India tops the list of mortalities due to cardiac arrests and diseases. The reasons obviously point out to many, and unhealthy lifestyle is one of the main ones. A healthy lifestyle is an amalgamation of a balanced diet, a fitness regime that is followed on a regular basis and addiction &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/on-world-heart-day-decide-on-a-healthy-oil-for-cooking/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "On World Heart Day Decide on a Healthy Oil for Cooking"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">It is not secret that India tops the list of mortalities due to cardiac arrests and diseases. The reasons obviously point out to many, and unhealthy lifestyle is one of the main ones. A healthy lifestyle is an amalgamation of a balanced diet, a fitness regime that is followed on a regular basis and addiction free. As per a leading nutritionist, though food forms a significant part of your lifestyle, it’s not just about the type of food that is consumed. A lot of things are associated with food, it’s the way the food is cooked, served, consumed as well as the time when you consume it.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1030" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/World-Heart-Day-Healthy-Oil-for-Cooking.jpg" alt="On World Heart Day Decide on a Healthy Oil for Cooking" width="732" height="549" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/World-Heart-Day-Healthy-Oil-for-Cooking.jpg 732w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/World-Heart-Day-Healthy-Oil-for-Cooking-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also, when anyone says oil, everyone seems to be rolling their eyes because, we feel that the real culprit of your unhealthy body is the oil. But, the fact is that oil is not bad as you would imagine it to be. It is a mix of different kinds of fats. Also, a healthy oil is a mixture of different kinds of fats. Hence, when you select your oil, it’s important that you check for a balance between the essential fats of it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Here are a few tips to help you out with selection of a healthy oil for healthy cooking – </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Loaded with Mono-saturated Fats</strong> – Mono-saturated fats are good for health and hence it’s good to choose an oil that is rich in mono-saturated fats. These fats solidify when kept in the fridge and transform into liquid when at room temperature.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>More of Polyunsaturated fats</strong> – Poly unsaturated fats contain Omega 3 and Omega 6, which happen to be vital for the body. We all know that omega 3 is responsible for protecting our body against inflammation, thus protecting us against diseases. Our body is not capable of producing them and hence we need it to be there in our diet. Though Omega 3 is what we need more than omega 6, precisely in a ratio of 1:2 or 1:4.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Less of Trans Fats</strong> – Trans-fat are highly harmful to the body. To say the least, its best to avoid this fat. Trans-fats are formed when poly-saturated fats are transformed into solid. These fats are leading causes of heart diseases, high cholesterol as well as cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Less of Saturated Fats</strong>&#8211; Saturated fats are known to be bad fat but apparently they come under the neutral category. You can have an intake of saturated fat but in limit. They are good but not as good as mono-saturated fat. Also, the bad saturated fats are the hydrogenated saturated fats that are man-made.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lastly, fat is bad only when it is consumed in a quantity that is more than required. So, controlling eating habits is the key to healthy body.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>RajaRajeswari hospital</strong></a> is having one of the <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best Cardiologist in Bangalore</a></strong>, It provides all types of cardiology services with cutting edge facilities advance cardiac</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>All you Need to know about Brain Tumor</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-brain-tumor/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 10:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brain Tumor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=884</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A brain tumor is a condition that is caused when abnormal cells in the brain grow within the brain or the spinal cord. It can be life threatening because it can disrupt brain functioning. There are two types of brain tumors, ones that are benign (cancerous) and the other malignant (malignant). The life expectancy varies &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-brain-tumor/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All you Need to know about Brain Tumor"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A brain tumor is a condition that is caused when abnormal cells in the brain grow within the brain or the spinal cord. It can be life threatening because it can disrupt brain functioning. There are two types of brain tumors, ones that are benign (cancerous) and the other malignant (malignant). The life expectancy varies depending upon the stage of the cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Benign Tumor</strong> – This tumor grows slowly and does not spread to other tissues, thus is not cancerous in nature.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Malignant Tumor</strong> – This tumor grows very fast and contains cancerous cells that invade other parts of the brain and is considered to be life-threatening condition.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Brain Tumors are also classified as primary and secondary tumors depending on their origin. If the tumor starts in the brain it is known as primary tumor and if it originates from some other part of the body, it is known as a secondary or metastatic tumor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-885 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-300x169.jpg" alt="Brain Tumor - signs" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong></p>
<p>The symptoms of a brain tumor depend upon the type of tumor and the origin of it. The symptoms are mild initially and gradually increase. Sometimes there may be no symptoms at all. Some common symptoms &#8211;</p>
<p>A headache that persists<br />
Nausea, vomiting, and drowsiness<br />
Speech issues<br />
Memory Issues<br />
Seizures or convulsions<br />
Personality Change<br />
Coordination Change</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diagnosis</strong><br />
Diagnosis involves various tests to be carried out including the following-</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>EEG</strong> &#8211; An electroencephalogram is used to record brain activities for abnormalities if any using electrodes that are attached to the head.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>CT Scan</strong> – It gives a detailed X ray picture of the patient’s brain</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>MRI Scan</strong> &#8211; It makes use of magnetic field as well as radio waves and provides a detailed image of the brain<br />
Even biopsy is used to further confirm the presence of a tumor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
The treatment depends on the diagnosis. It includes factors like the type of tumor, the age of the patient, size of the tumor, tolerance levels of the patient to name a few.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Surgery</strong> – The first course of treatment for Cancer starts with surgery and removal of the tumor or a part of it as much as possible. Due care is taken to avoid any harm to the neighboring tissues. The remaining tumor is removed with the help of various cancer therapies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Chemotherapy</strong> &#8211; Chemotherapy is used for treating a serious type of malignant tumor. It stops the cells from multiplying or duplicating.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Radiation Therapy</strong> &#8211; Radiotherapy uses intense energy beams to destroy the tumor and prevent it from growing. It attacks the tumor cells, leading to shrinkage in the tumor, which can further be managed using an immune system of a person.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Radio Surgery</strong> – Also known as stereotactic radiosurgery (SRS), this treatment involves giving a targeted and precise dose in the form of an X-ray radiation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Risk Factors</strong> &#8211; There is no definite reason behind brain tumors. It might be hereditary but in rare cases. The only risk factor associated with the brain tumor is radiation exposure.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Survival</strong> – The survival rate post the diagnosis also depends on a lot of factors but for malignant tumors of a primary type, the 5-year survival rate is even less than 35%.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">RRMCH is one the best hospitals in Bangalore and amongst the <a title="Best Neuro Hospital in India" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best Neuro hospitals in India</a>. Equipped with the latest in Medical Technology, it also offers the expertise of the best neurologist in Bangalore.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Neuroendocrine Tumors, Types and Symptoms</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/neuroendocrine-tumors-types-and-symptoms/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 09:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best neurologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=842</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Recently Bollywood celebrity Irfan Khan is known to be diagnosed by Neuroendocrine Tumor. In order to restrain his fans and people in general from any kind of speculation he even went on to clarify that neuro does not always mean about the brain. He had to do that post rumors of he suffering from brain &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/neuroendocrine-tumors-types-and-symptoms/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Neuroendocrine Tumors, Types and Symptoms"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently Bollywood celebrity Irfan Khan is known to be diagnosed by Neuroendocrine Tumor. In order to restrain his fans and people in general from any kind of speculation he even went on to clarify that neuro does not always mean about the brain. He had to do that post rumors of he suffering from brain tumor surfaced across the social media. Well, as he is out of the country right now and is getting treated, best wishes of all the country are with him. Well, for those who are unaware about neuroendocrine tumor here’s a rundown this condition.</p>
<p>Neuroendocrine tumor or NET is a tumor which does not generally show any major symptoms as it grows slowly. Once the tumor grows or if it releases hormones while it is functional is when symptoms surface.<br />
Types of Endocrine tumors include pancreatic endocrine tumor, gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors and lung neuroendocrine tumors.</p>
<p>Pancreatic Neuro Endocrine Tumors – This is a rare kind of tumor. The symptoms of this cancer are subject to the hormones released by it. The symptoms generally include the following</p>
<ol>
<li>Stomach Ulcers</li>
<li>Heart burn</li>
<li>Jaundice</li>
<li>Low or high blood Sugar levels</li>
<li>Blood clots</li>
<li>Patches of red itchy and painful skin</li>
<li>Unexplained weight loss</li>
</ol>
<p>When the gastrin in body increases excessively it causes Zollinger Ellison syndrome further increasing the quantity of stomach acid ultimately causing small intestine or stomach ulcers. The symptoms include</p>
<ol>
<li>Severe Diarrhea</li>
<li>Heartburn</li>
<li>Abdominal Pain</li>
<li>Pain in abdomen</li>
<li>Nausea and vomiting</li>
<li>Blood vomits</li>
<li>Weight loss</li>
</ol>
<p>When the level of cortisol increases highly inside the body it causes cushing syndrome. When too much Adrenocorticotrpic hormone is released it leads to lung NETs which leads to adrenal glands making too much cortisol. The symptoms are as follows –</p>
<ol>
<li>Muscle weakness</li>
<li>Increase in hair growth on body and face</li>
<li>High blood sugar</li>
<li>Weight gain</li>
<li>Fat build up above the collar bone below the shoulders</li>
<li>Mood swing and behavioral changes</li>
<li>Purple lines on skin</li>
</ol>
<p>Gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors – This tumor develops in any part of the gastrointestinal tract besides large and small intestine. The symptoms are as follows –</p>
<ol>
<li>Nausea and vomiting</li>
<li>Diarrhea</li>
<li>Anemia with fatigue</li>
<li>Weight loss</li>
<li>Constipation or intestine blockage</li>
<li>Blood in stool or rectal bleeding</li>
<li>Heartburn or indigestion</li>
<li>Abdominal/ rectal pain or discomfort</li>
</ol>
<p>Lung Neuroendocrine tumors &#8211; This tumor develops in the bronchi. Symptoms include</p>
<ol>
<li>Never ceasing cough</li>
<li>Blood in cough</li>
<li>Difficulty Breathing</li>
<li>Pneumonia</li>
<li>Fatigue</li>
<li>Skin flushing, wheezing and diarrhea (Carcinoid Syndrome)</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="RRMCH Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> is one the <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">best hospitals in Bangalore</a> and it are also the<a title="Best Neuro Hospital in India" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/" target="_blank"> best Neuro hospital in India</a>. It has got the best neurologist in Bangalore</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brain Has Eyes Too &#8211; A sneak Peek Into Neurons</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-has-eyes-too-a-sneak-peek-into-neurons/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 09:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ent hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=704</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yes, that is true. Nicknamed as ‘Jennifer Aniston’ a neuron based on the participant study which showed that one of the neuron of his brain lit up on recognizing the face of particular people like Jennifer Aniston or Hillary Clinton. So, this neuron was named after Jennifer Aniston. This report further revealed that one single &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-has-eyes-too-a-sneak-peek-into-neurons/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Brain Has Eyes Too &#8211; A sneak Peek Into Neurons"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, that is true. Nicknamed as ‘Jennifer Aniston’ a neuron based on the participant study which showed that one of the neuron of his brain lit up on recognizing the face of particular people like Jennifer Aniston or Hillary Clinton. So, this neuron was named after Jennifer Aniston. This report further revealed that one single specific cell lit up whenever a person’s certain conscious experience was concerned. This throws further light on the response of brain cells the relation of the activities with consciousness. Though, understanding the scope and science of human consciousness is a mystery that is yet to be unfolded and even researchers cannot say with surety if these neurons lead to conscious thoughts.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Brain-Has-Eyes-Too-A-sneak-Peek-Into-Neurons-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-705" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Brain-Has-Eyes-Too-A-sneak-Peek-Into-Neurons-1-1.jpg" alt="Brain Has Eyes Too - A sneak Peek Into Neurons" width="665" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>There were studies around the same carried out in 2008 which used a masking technique. This technique showed an image of a popular person like Aniston for 16 milliseconds immediately followed by a pattern Image muddling the face afterimage on the retina, thus making it rather hard for the brain to register what it saw. Later on in another study that used a method for hiding images from participants awareness. The phenomenon used for the experiment is called attentional blink wherein two target images are shown in a high speed streaming along with some other similar images. This results in a person often not able to recognize the second image targeted.</p>
<p>A similar study was carried out over a list of 21 patients under epilepsy and brains were fitted with special treatment electrodes. The trial included showing 14 different images predetermined by the scientist as familiar to the person. Further each one had a particular activity of specific brain cell. Now, when the trial was conducted, the researchers asked the participants to concentrate on two target images of the 14. All the images would later be flashed on the screen for 150 milliseconds. The medial temporal lobe was under constant monitoring during and after the trail and the researchers queried the participants if they had seen two images of familiar faces.</p>
<p>Every cell with unique signature was studied as it lit up and helped researchers link a brain cell pattern to particular images and had the ability to tell about the image represented even though<br />
the participants are not aware of it.</p>
<p>Furthermore, research work is on as the researchers believe that they are at the intersection of perception and memory and investigation was needed to find out the results of direct stimulation of neurons.</p>
<p><a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore</a>   <a title="Best Neuro Hospital in India" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/" target="_blank">Best Neuro Hospital in India</a>  <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Best Hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Safe House For Many Disease Causing Viruses &#8211; Human Semen</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/safe-house-for-many-disease-causing-viruses-human-semen/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 11:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=701</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When researchers was carried out on Zika virus, it was found that the virus finds its way through the man’s semen and stays there safely for a long time, over a few months. This led to a further study about other viruses with the ability to find their way to the man’s semen and staying &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/safe-house-for-many-disease-causing-viruses-human-semen/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Safe House For Many Disease Causing Viruses &#8211; Human Semen"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Safe-House-For-Many-Disease-Causing-Viruses-Human-Semen-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-702 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Safe-House-For-Many-Disease-Causing-Viruses-Human-Semen-1-300x225.jpg" alt="Safe House For Many Disease Causing Viruses - Human Semen" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Safe-House-For-Many-Disease-Causing-Viruses-Human-Semen-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Safe-House-For-Many-Disease-Causing-Viruses-Human-Semen-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Safe-House-For-Many-Disease-Causing-Viruses-Human-Semen-1.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">When researchers was carried out on <em>Zika virus</em>, it was found that the virus finds its way through the man’s semen and stays there safely for a long time, over a few months. This led to a further study about other viruses with the ability to find their way to the man’s semen and staying there safely.</p>
<p>The research was carried out at the oxford university and it was discovered that there were a minimum of 27 different viruses with and ability to get into the blood and the semen as per the existing reports of scientific literature of ‘viremic’ viruses. The research also highlighted that the spread of the viruses in the semen is apparently even more than assumed.</p>
<p>The list of viruses not only includes lesser known ones but lots of popular ones too like <em>HIV, Hepatitis C, Ebola, herpes, chikungunya, chickenpox</em> and the less known ones like simian foamy, rift valley fever to name a few.<br />
Though research is just at the preliminary stage as only the list of the viruses that have the ability to use a man’s semen as a safe house stay are known but more details like how long can they actually stay there, in what concentrations and how able they are in triggering or fueling he disease is yet to be studied.</p>
<p>Additionally, it is yet to be known whether these viruses have the ability to infect the sperms. This holds grave importance because it can lead to mutating the sperm DNA and passing the same to the next generation further increasing cancer risk in that generation as well. Additionally, many of us might not be aware that testes are known to be immune to any invasions by the body’s immune system. They are also therefore called immuno-logically privileged.</p>
<p>These findings might just raise questions on the considerations around treatments developed for viral diseases and their effects on the virus located across the body included the male reproductive tract.</p>
<p><a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">Best Hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lower Back Pain vs Kidney Pain &#8211; The Difference</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lower-back-pain-vs-kidney-pain-the-difference/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 08:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lower back pain vs kidney pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=697</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many of us fail to figure out the difference when we experience pain particularly when its either kidney or lower back pain. So, to begin get down to the definition of lower back pain and kidney pain. It’s called lower back pain when it occurs anywhere from the buttocks upto the lower back. While kidney &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lower-back-pain-vs-kidney-pain-the-difference/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Lower Back Pain vs Kidney Pain &#8211; The Difference"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Many of us fail to figure out the difference when we experience pain particularly when its either<em> kidney or lower back pain</em>. So, to begin get down to the definition of<em> lower back pain and kidney pain</em>.</p>
<p align="justify">It’s called <strong>lower back pain</strong> when it occurs anywhere from the buttocks upto the lower back. While <strong>kidney pain</strong> is said to occur between the hips or flanks and the ribs. At times you may experience it in the upper abdominal region as well. Well, this is the basic difference in back pain and kidney pain but otherwise also there are many other difference that can help you figure out which kind of pain you are suffering from. Here’s a sneak peek into a few other differences between kidney pain and lower back pain.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-698 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-300x147.jpg" alt="LOWER BACK PAIN VS KIDNEY PAIN" width="300" height="147" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-300x147.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-768x377.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1.jpg 996w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Kidney Pain</strong><br />
Kidney pain is the result of a kidney infection or a kidney stone usually. Kidney infection can cause mild pain but kidney stone pain is very severe in nature and often compared to labor pain.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
The causes of kidney pain include kidney infection and kidney stones as mentioned before besides the pain could also be a result of renal infarction, kidney cancer and glomerulonephritis.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Lower Back Pain</strong><br />
Lower back pain is further divided as acute pain and chronic pain. While acute pain lasts for around 4 to 12 weeks, chronic back pain can easily last over 12 weeks. Also known as lumbago it affects people of all age groups.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
Lower back pain is a result of muscle sprain, spasm or tear leading to disc bulge or herniation, spinal stenosis, osteoporosis or sciatica. It could also be due to vertebral body, pedicle fracture or fracture of lamina. It can be caused due to Paravertebral muscle spasm or metastatic vertebral cancer.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Pain Management</strong><br />
<em>Kidney Pain –</em> Kidney pain treatment depends of its causes and usually involves use of antibiotics and medications if its infection but in case of kidney stones if that does not work a laser surgery or a minimally invasive surgery could be carried out.</p>
<p align="justify"><em>Back Pain</em> – For relief against lower back pain issues treatment could include suitable therapies like heat and cold, physical and massage therapies to name a few. In case with complications based on the diagnosis surgical procedures might be advised.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, its always advisable to visit your doctor if you suffer from back pain in order to figure out the root cause of the problem, be it <em>kidney or lower back</em>.</p>
<p align="justify">know about <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">best hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Supplements Women Need After 30</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-supplements-women-need-after-30/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 09:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5 supplements for women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[after 30 years women required supplements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best psychiatrist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=681</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many a times, lost in responsibilities around office or home, family or kids women forget about personal health or keep ignoring them. Till women are in the twenties, body is younger and fitter and hence copes in a better way. But, post 30 as you are nearly knocking door of your middle age, is when &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-supplements-women-need-after-30/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "5 Supplements Women Need After 30"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Many a times, lost in responsibilities around office or home, family or kids women forget about personal health or keep ignoring them. Till women are in the twenties, body is younger and fitter and hence copes in a better way. But, post 30 as you are nearly knocking door of your middle age, is when you really need to look into your bodily needs.<br />
After 30 there are a lot of changes that occur in a women’s body and are more visible after 35 years of age. These include changes in menstrual cycles, urinary incontinence, fibroids, pregnancy difficulties, prominent signs of aging, slow metabolism, but to name a few.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/5-Supplements-Women-Need-After-30-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-682 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/5-Supplements-Women-Need-After-30-1-300x199.jpg" alt="5 Supplements Women Need After 30" width="300" height="199" /></a>As per experts and specialists supplements can work well in maintaining the balance of nutrients required by the body.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Vitamin D</strong><br />
Vitamin D as we all know helps in a lot of ways that include immunity building, genes regulation, cancer prevention, bone health and more. The best, easy and affordable source of Vitamin D is sunlight. Sitting in the sunlight with minimal clothing for an hour can work well for your body. If not than Vitamin D supplements is the alternative.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Anti- Oxidants</strong><br />
It is in the mid or late thirties that women start noticing fine lines as well as thinning of skin. But, this process of aging can be slowed down with the help for a few minerals and vitamins together known as anti-oxidants. In order to boost immunity besides slowing aging women need to take in atleast 15 mg of Vitamin E. Further taking in 75 mg of Vitman C, which facilitates in vitamin E absorption and Vitamin A for protection against sun damage and eye</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>protection.</strong><br />
Omega 3 fatty acids/ fish oil<br />
As per doctors, our body needs 3 gms of omega 3 fatty acids per day. These help in keeping our joints health, weight management, keeping our blood fats normal and optimizing brain function. As these are essential fats and our body cannot make them taking mercury free supplements are advisable.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Calcium, Magnesium &amp; Iron</strong><br />
Calcium and magnesium help in bone building as well as producing energy and for better nerve functioning. Iron is also an essential nutrient responsible for keeping you active and protecting against infections as well as maintaining body temperature. As per experts our body requires about 18 mg per day. Though a pregnant and nursing women requires 27 mg and 9 mg per day respectively. Vitamin C and A help a lot in iron absorption.</p>
<p align="justify">As a busy woman, you might be occupied with umpteen activities around house, kids and family but its your health that equally matters so do take care of your health as well.</p>
<p align="justify">Contact to <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Best Hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Artificial Limbs That Respond To Thoughts &#8211; A Reality That Costs A Fortune</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/artificial-limbs-that-respond-to-thoughts-a-reality-that-costs-a-fortune/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 06:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial limbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=677</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Over the years, scientists have been working on prosthetic limbs that can respond to human thoughts. These projects have been heavily funded by many organizations and defense agencies across the world. A significant development in the direction has now led to the creation of the first ever prosthetic limb that responds to human thoughts much &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/artificial-limbs-that-respond-to-thoughts-a-reality-that-costs-a-fortune/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Artificial Limbs That Respond To Thoughts &#8211; A Reality That Costs A Fortune"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Over the years, scientists have been working on prosthetic limbs that can respond to human thoughts. These projects have been heavily funded by many organizations and defense agencies across the world. A significant development in the direction has now led to the creation of the first ever prosthetic limb that responds to human thoughts much like a real limb.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Artificial-Limbs-That-Respond-To-Thoughts-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-678 " src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Artificial-Limbs-That-Respond-To-Thoughts-1-1024x576.jpg" alt="Artificial Limbs That Respond To Thoughts " width="613" height="348" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Earlier, there was news about creation of prosthetic limbs that respond to thoughts but their movement was quite limited and hence, people in need either abandoned them or never preferred to use them. But, as per the doctor of Imperial college London, the new approach which shifts their focus from the muscles to the nervous system has helped them create a limb that responds to thoughts effectively.</p>
<p align="justify">According to him, their technology helps them detect and decode the signals clearly. The experiments and testing have been carried out with amputee volunteers and after physiotherapy they have been able to make more extensive movements.</p>
<p align="justify">Today, a lot of research scientists are already working and testing bionic arms. There is already and alternative of using brain implants available. But, the benefit of using the nerve from the spine is the compatibility factor, making it usable with existing prosthetic arms that too wire free linking from the brain, as per the researchers at Imperial College of London.</p>
<p align="justify">Another example is that of a thought controlled prosthetic being developed at the John Hopkins University, USA. It is being tested on a 50 plus amputee who lost his limbs in an electrical accident as a teenager. It is yet to be clinically tested and find a place in the market. The limbs are called Modular Prosthetic Limbs or MPL and the customer socket inside brain can pick up brain signals that control the arms. Thus, just by thinking the amputee is able to move the limb or limbs. To do the same, the amputee had to undergo a surgery for remapping the remaining nerves of his/her missing arms so that the brain could send signals to the prosthetic. As per the chief engineer at John Hopkins, with the remapping growing deeper, the working will better because of the over 100 sensors fitted in the arm. Another advantage of MPL being its modular design. This design helps in creating prosthetic limbs customized as per individual requirements.</p>
<p align="justify">Having said that, as on day MPL costs a bomb, as much as a Maserati car to be precise. Well, scientists are yet to work on a budget prosthetic, affordable to people in need. experts at John Hopkins are also working on creating caps that send signals about brain activity to the robotic arm. As for the market availability, they do hope to make the MPL available to the consumers within a few years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
