<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Role Of Legumes In Heart Health &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 09:47:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 09:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Role Of Legumes In Heart Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1245</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes. Though it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual basis. But, recently &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer
by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find
out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes.  Though
it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual
basis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1246" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>Five color legumes for healthy , Soy bean, Navy bean or white bean, Black beam, Red bean and Green bean,</figcaption></figure>



<p>But,
recently researchers of the review called Advances in Nutrition took
up the task of understanding the significance of legumes like
lentils, peas and beans etc. around heart health. 
</p>



<p>Primarily, they focused on cardiovascular diseases like <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">coronary heart</a> disease, stroke, myocardial infarction besides looking into hypertension, obesity and diabetes. They chose cardiovascular diseases because it is one of the most common causes of mortality and even one of the most expensive ones. It is known to cause US 1 billion dollars a day. </p>



<p>They
used the data analysis of Eurpoean Association which recently carried
out a series of systematic reviews as well as meta-analysis for
Diabetics study. The researchers hope that these results could be
quite a help in updating the recommendations already made around the
role of legumes in preventing as well as treating cardio-metabolic
diseases. 
</p>



<p>The
data review and comparison with people with lowest and highest intake
of legumes revealed that dietary pulses that had legumes which either
did or did not include other legumes did decrease coronary heart
disease, obesity incidence and hypertension. 
</p>



<p>
Though the researchers were able to find a positive relationship
between intake of legumes in higher amounts and reduction in certain
parameters related to cardiovascular risks, the conclusion they came
to are muted relatively. 
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers “The overall certainty of the evidence was
graded as low for CVD incidence and ‘very low for all the other
outcomes.” 
</p>



<p>Therefore, the co author of the study Dr Hana Kahleova said “ Americans eat less than one serving of legumes per day, on average. Simply adding more beans to our plates could be a powerful tool in fighting heart disease and bringing down blood pressure.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><strong>Best Cardiologist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
