<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>admin &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/author/admin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 04:47:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Egg Freezing &#8211; More Power to Women</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/egg-freezing-is-all-about-empowering-women/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 05:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=928</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Egg freezing is not an entirely unknown term. Awareness about it is fast spreading across cities in India. Even Gynaecologists have observed a spurt in the inquiries around egg freezing. Scientifically known as oocyte cryopreservation, this process involves the extraction of a woman&#8217;s egg from the ovary, freezing and storing it. Afterwards at the time &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/egg-freezing-is-all-about-empowering-women/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Egg Freezing &#8211; More Power to Women"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Egg freezing is not an entirely unknown term. Awareness about it is fast spreading across cities in India. Even Gynaecologists have observed a spurt in the inquiries around egg freezing. Scientifically known as <strong>oocyte cryopreservation</strong>, this process involves the extraction of a woman&#8217;s egg from the ovary, freezing and storing it. Afterwards at the time of conceiving, this egg is thawed and placed in the uterus as embryos.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This is a boon for women in India today who want to make life choices on their own at their time. Many women delay marriages as they do not want to get married under pressure and want to prioritize education and career. Such women can freeze their eggs and use them later to conceive. There are numerous case studies to help you understand how egg freezing helped women in India conceive and deliver a healthy baby at a time when they were ready for it.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-937 alignright" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cryopreservation-1-300x176.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="176" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cryopreservation-1-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cryopreservation-1.jpg 638w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Case 1</strong> &#8211; A 31-year-old female from Matunga wanted to conceive through IVF and her husband was in too much pressure while donating his sperm, so much so that he was not able to produce a semen sample required for the IVF on the day of collection. So, they extracted her egg and froze it. The IVF process was later completed once the semen was received and she had a hassle free pregnancy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Case 2</strong> &#8211; A 14-year-old female was diagnosed with cancer in one of her ovaries. The doctor extracted and froze her egg from the other ovary before she underwent chemotherapy. He mother was glad that her daughter had a choice to conceive in the future as freezing her egg granted protection to her fertility.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Case 3</strong> – A 36-year-old who was not ready for marriage, froze her eggs at 32 so that whenever she is ready for it and for maternity, there are no issues with conceiving.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Today, egg freezing awareness is spreading fast amongst the society and many women are opting for the alternative as it empowers them to make a choice of becoming a mother, at the time they want to. Across the world, egg freezing has already helped conceive and deliver over 2000 babies. Having said that, even though the freezing can be done at any age based on the count of antral follicles and hormone levels, the doctors generally advise doing the egg freezing before 35 years.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In today’s times when the world is embracing gender equality and women are determined to match the abilities of men in almost every walk of life, egg freezing is an amazing addition to their empowerment arsenal.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">RRMCH has got <a title="best Gynecologist in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best gynecologist in Bangalore</a> and the department provides the best treatment for women health care. RRMCH provides regular<a title="health care services in india" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/health-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> clinical services</a> as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Medical Tourism Destinations in the World</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-medical-tourism-destination-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 12:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medical Tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medical Tourism Destination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medical Tourism Destination in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top 5 Medical Tourism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=925</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know about the recent spurt in medical Tourism, but what you might not know and perhaps, would want to know is,  names of the countries that top this list. Before we look into that, here’s some information on medical tourism. As per international statistics, 11 million people from the USA opted for medical tourism &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-medical-tourism-destination-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Top 5 Medical Tourism Destinations in the World"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">We all know about the recent spurt in medical Tourism, but what you might not know and perhaps, would want to know is,  names of the countries that top this list. Before we look into that, here’s some information on medical tourism. As per international statistics, 11 million people from the USA opted for medical tourism in 2016. Now, that is a huge number. Furthermore, the medical tourism industry is slated to grow by 25% in the coming years. People are choosing medical tourism alternative for reasons like quality healthcare at impressive costs, convenience and more. Lets run-down 5 of the most sought-after medical tourism destinations in the world.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>BRAZIL</strong> &#8211; As per World Health Organization, Brazil tops the list of medical tourism destinations in the world. With over 40 JCI accredited hospitals and world’s best experts under their belts, Brazil is a one-stop solution for healthcare needs around cosmetic and plastic surgery. The reason it is third on the list of most visited countries for cosmetic and plastic surgery is due to its quality services at affordable rates.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>MEXICO</strong> &#8211; Mexico is one of the most preferred destinations for medical healthcare as it is known to reduce the medical costs by a staggering 40% to 65%. It boasts of over 98 JCI accredited hospitals and offers advanced treatment procedures in areas of cosmetic surgery and dentistry. Most of the people residing in the USA are known to travel to Mexico for their healthcare needs.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-938 alignright" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Medical-Tourism-1-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Medical-Tourism-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Medical-Tourism-1.jpg 638w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>INDIA</strong> &#8211; India is brimming with medical tourists as on day and the reason it stands in this list is its ability reduce healthcare costs by a mammoth 65% to 90% as compared to the USA, making it one of the most visited countries for healthcare services. India is a preferred location not only due to its affordability or quality healthcare services but because there is zero waiting time for scheduling surgeries and living here is a relaxing experience as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>THAILAND</strong> – The land of the white elephants as it is known, Thailand is also famous for its pristine beaches. But many of us aren’t aware of the fact that it is also a popular destination for medical tourism. You can not only reduce your medical expenditure by 50% to 75% but also avail facilities like private recovery gardens, Thai massage and other relaxation therapies at affordable prices.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TURKEY</strong> – The reason Turkey is on the list of most favored destinations for medical tourism is that it offers zero waiting times for services of healthcare particularly like transplant, neurosurgery, genomic medicine, radiation therapy for cancer. The Turkish airlines also offers discounts for medical tourists and the best part is the bottom line &#8211;  you end up saving around 50% to 65% of your money as compared to the USA.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, <a title="health care services in india" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/emergency-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">healthcare</a> has broadened its horizons and is available across borders at affordable prices. Hence, umpteen people across countries are opting for medical tourism.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>All You Need to Know About Terminal Illness</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/terminal-illness/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 12:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terminal Illness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=919</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The term terminal illness means disease that is not curable and is expected to result in death of the patient over a course of time. It is a commonly used term for illnesses like cancer, heart disease of advanced stage, to name a few. When a person is said to be suffering from a terminal &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/terminal-illness/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All You Need to Know About Terminal Illness"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The term terminal illness means disease that is not curable and is expected to result in death of the patient over a course of time. It is a commonly used term for illnesses like cancer, heart disease of advanced stage, to name a few. When a person is said to be suffering from a terminal illness, there is near certainty that the patient is going to die in a course of time irrespective of the treatment. Once diagnosed with a terminal condition the patient knows that death is certain and the doctor informs the patient about the time left, in days, weeks, months or years.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Once a patient is diagnosed for terminal illness, the disease management process is decided. The options for it include continual of treatment, caregiving, hospice care and even physician assisted suicide. The decision making is done keeping the patient as well as the family in loop. Many a time patients with terminal illness experience anxiety around the nearing death as well as depression and hence requires psychotherapeutic treatment to help them deal with the same.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">On the flip side, knowing about the terminal illness condition gives them time to get ready for advance treatment and care procedures as well as living will, to help them deal with end of life care effectively. Let us run through the different disease management or end of life care procedures for terminal illness patients.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Terminal-Illness-11-e1533277309474-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-939 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Terminal-Illness1-e1533277309474-1.jpg" alt="Terminal Illness" width="640" height="400" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Terminal-Illness1-e1533277309474-1.jpg 640w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Terminal-Illness1-e1533277309474-1-300x188.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment Continuation</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Palliative Care</strong> &#8211; Palliative care is more about after care of the physical needs of the patients post diagnosis. This includes emotional support, management of pain, psychological and spiritual care. It is a methodology that concentrates on improvement of quality of life of the patients and satisfaction besides helping family members deal and cope with the difficult situation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Care Giving</strong> – Care giving is an integral part of terminal disease management. It involves keeping a nurse to take care of the person suffering from the condition. The care givers provide support like psychological support, food, assistance with movement and routine activities on a day to day basis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Medications</strong> – Terminal patients who suffer from cancer related pain, need medications for relief. The medication prescribed varies based on the pain severity as well as status of disease. One of the common symptoms that terminal illness patients experience is dyspnea viz. breathing issues.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Good Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Good Hospitals in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Hospice Care</strong> &#8211; There is a misconception that people choosing hospice care live less compared to others, but study has proved that patients with hospice care live for the same span than others. It includes spending more time with family, friends or other inmates undertaking hospice disease management procedures. They usually stay away from a hospital at home or at an inpatient hospice facility.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Physician assisted Suicide (PAS)</strong> &#8211; This concept is legally approved only in a few countries in the world. It is when a patient decides to die with dignity that he or she opts for physician assisted suicide. The decision could be based on various different reasons like avoiding pain, disability, healthcare costs, family impact, personal and religious beliefs, to name a few. The patient has to give request in writing as well as orally after which the physicians offer them lethal drugs to help them die.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, some terminally ill patients stop all the treatments that they are undergoing to avoid side-affects while some go for even more aggressive treatment in a hope to increase their life span to the maximum. Some also opt for alternative methods of treatment that are non-proven as well as diet changes that are required.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Food Poisoning? An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/what-is-food-poisoning-and-more/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Poisoning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=916</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Recently, there was news of over 100 prisoners in Delhi falling sick suddenly and being admitted to the hospital. The reason cited for the same is either food poisoning, drug poisoning or contaminated water. Food poisoning is a common term and you hear people and kids suffering from it every now and then. It is &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/what-is-food-poisoning-and-more/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "What is Food Poisoning? An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Recently, there was news of over 100 prisoners in Delhi falling sick suddenly and being admitted to the hospital. The reason cited for the same is either food poisoning, drug poisoning or contaminated water. Food poisoning is a common term and you hear people and kids suffering from it every now and then. It is a very uncomfortable condition that leads to nausea, vomiting or diarrhea and is caused due to the intake of toxic, contaminated or spoiled food.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
Food poisoning can either be caused by bacteria, viruses or parasites. The most common though is through bacteria like Listeria, E coli and salmonella. The latter is said to be the biggest cause of serious food poisoning cases. Another rare or lethal bacteria responsible for food poisoning includes the C. botulism and Campylobacter. Norovirus is a virus type which can also lead to food poisoning but is not fatal mostly. Others include Rotavirus, Astrovirus, Sapovirus and Hepatitis A, wherein the latter can be serious. Toxoplasma is a parasite which causes food poisoning. Parasites live within your digestive tract but can go undetected for years.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-1-Main-blog-image-550x410-1-1.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-942 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410-1.png" alt="Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410" width="550" height="410" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410-1.png 550w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410-1-300x224.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong><br />
Usually, food poisoning is detectable based on the symptoms. The symptoms differ as per the infection source. The symptoms appear anytime within 1 hour or 28 days depending on the infection source again. Most people suffering from food poisoning show atleast three of the following symptoms.</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Headache</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Weakness</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Nausea</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Mild fever</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Loss of appetite</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Diarrhea</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Abdominal cramps</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Food poisoning ain&#8217;t life-threatening. But, this does not mean that you take the condition lightly. There is always a rare possibility of it getting life-threatening as well. Look out for the following symptoms and initiate immediate medical assistance &#8211;</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Fever of 105 or higher</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Severe dehydration, dry mouth, no urine passage</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Difficulty speaking or seeing</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Diarrhea that does not go for 3 or more days</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Blood in urine</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
Food poisoning generally does not require any treatment and can easily be managed at home. It can take three to five days to subside but the most important part is to stay hydrated all along. Consumption of Sports drink that has electrolyte in them works really well in dealing with the condition. To help yourself out of fatigue try natural drinks like coconut water and fruit juice.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Know about <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best Hospitals in Bangalore</a>, Karnataka.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Ongoing Trends in Healthcare Sector</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-ongoing-trends-in-healthcare-sector/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 05:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=912</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Gone are the times when healthcare sector had a reputation of almost negative customer experiences. Nowadays, healthcare companies are going all guns blazing about their approach towards their customers. The approach also includes the optimum use of advanced technology besides newer approaches in-order to create a progressive change in the healthcare industry. Let us run &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-ongoing-trends-in-healthcare-sector/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Top 5 Ongoing Trends in Healthcare Sector"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Gone are the times when healthcare sector had a reputation of almost negative customer experiences. Nowadays, healthcare companies are going all guns blazing about their approach towards their customers. The approach also includes the optimum use of advanced technology besides newer approaches in-order to create a progressive change in the healthcare industry. Let us run through some of the upcoming trends in the healthcare eco-system.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-913 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1.jpg" alt="Trends in Healthcare Sector" width="600" height="300" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1-300x150.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tailored Medicine</strong> – Medicine is all about observation based diagnosis with evidence to support the same. Today, <a title="Health care Services in India" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/health-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">healthcare centers</a> are equipped with the latest in technology that results into accurate and speedy diagnosis. For example, with the help of radiology clinicians can investigate structures deep inside the body and with techniques like histopathology, clinicians can identify virus and tumors using microscopes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Virtual Reality</strong> &#8211; Virtual reality is working well in the management and treatment of pain. As per a study of the recent times, children responded to chemotherapy better when they played games while undergoing the same. This was because their attention got concentrated from the treatment part to the play part and hence even resulted in them requiring less dosage. Side effects like nausea and hypertension were also reduced compared to children who were advised to rest.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Patient Customization</strong> &#8211; Data has grown and so has the ability of the healthcare facilities to provide their customers with an experience that is absolutely personalized. Based on the history of the patient, these clinics provide facilities like potential health issues, doctors preferred by the patient, patient preference in terms of remote treatment or walk in, to name a few. This can help avoid the complexities involved with the navigation through health care professional web and makes patients information available readily for speedy and accurate treatment solutions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Augmented Reality</strong> – Besides other fields, augmented reality is playing a crucial role in healthcare and is fast turning out to be one of the most effective applications in medical training. AR helps doctors while monitoring diagnosis with the treatment procedure options to look forward too. They don’t have to spend time in honing their medical knowledge further because treatment options can simply pop up on their screen with options and suggestions. For example, while doing a child checkup the growth chart can pop up on the monitor itself, thus helping the doctor with seamless treatment procedures.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Smart Technology in Hospitals</strong> – <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Smart Technology in Hospitals</a> has actually helped better patient experience, comfort, and care. For example, many hospitals have started using smart technology in hospitals. In a few countries, certain healthcare outfits use self-adjusting beds for pressure and support customization for patients. Many are also making use of man free facilities where robots carry out the monitoring process of the patient in the room. Smart technology is available in different forms and works in reducing risks while increasing comfort and efficiency. Affirmatively, the use of smart technology across the healthcare ecosystem is poised to grow day by day, obviously so.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 tips to help you sail through the pregnancy voyage safely</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-vital-tips-on-sailing-through-pregnancy-voyage-safely/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 07:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in banglaore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=907</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Pregnancy is the harbinger of a new life coming to form and the herald of a life changing journey commencing 9 months later. One of the most remarkable moments is when you come to know about it and then begins a daily routine that involves a lot of tests, doctor visits and self-care. While, it &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-vital-tips-on-sailing-through-pregnancy-voyage-safely/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "5 tips to help you sail through the pregnancy voyage safely"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Pregnancy is the harbinger of a new life coming to form and the herald of a life changing journey commencing 9 months later. One of the most remarkable moments is when you come to know about it and then begins a daily routine that involves a lot of tests, doctor visits and self-care. While, it is a vital part of a woman’s life, sailing through the pregnancy phase is also another extremely vital part because of the risks associated with the whole process. So, here are five important tips that could help you ensure safe drive through your pregnancy roads.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-908 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-300x225.jpg" alt="pregnancy Voyage Safely" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Genetic Screening</strong> &#8211; Sometimes genetic illnesses can affect the health of the fetus and hence it is detrimental for you and your spouse to undergo genetic screening.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>De-stressing</strong> – Stress can affect your health as well as the health of the fetus. So, keeping yourself stress-free is a good idea. To keep stress at bay you may indulge yourself in activities like breathing exercises, relaxing showers, yoga, and meditation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>De-Addiction</strong> &#8211; Addictions can be life-threatening for the fetus and create unnecessary complications like premature birth, low birth weight or miscarriage. Good idea to stay away from them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Exercise</strong> &#8211; Remaining active is the key to a healthy body. So, exercise on a routine basis, walk every day for some-time and feel fit all through your pregnancy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diet Balance</strong> – A balanced diet can help you and your fetus stay healthy and receive all the necessary nutrients throughout the prenatal period. So, get a dietician for a customized diet plan and follow it all through.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Prenatal Care</strong> – Do your research to get yourself a certified and experienced prenatal care center. Try finding it nearby to avoid the hassles of commuting through traffic for regular checkups and emergency times.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Besides that always take care of yourself all through the pregnancy while walking or commuting with respect to your safety and avoid any laborious activities that have a potential to harm you like lifting heavy stuff, riding two-wheelers through traffic, but to name a few.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Department of <a title="best Gynecologist in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/" target="_blank">Obstetrics and Gynecology</a> has been providing comprehensive health care for women. We provide regular clinical services in Obstetrics like antenatal care, labor management, Postpartum Care. We also provide specialized care in high-risk pregnancies like P.I.H, Eclampsia, GDM, Multiple gestations, BOH.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>All you need to Know About HLA-B27 Test</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/hla-b27-test/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 07:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HLA-B27 Test]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysore road hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rajarajeswari hospital in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=904</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[HLA B27 is a test that is conducted to identify the Human Leukocyte Antigen (HLA B27) protein. This protein is situated on the white blood cells surface and is an antigen that helps the immune system infection causing aliens and healthy body tissues. Though most of the HLAs protect the body against harmful invaders, HLA &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/hla-b27-test/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All you need to Know About HLA-B27 Test"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">HLA B27 is a test that is conducted to identify the Human Leukocyte Antigen (HLA B27) protein. This protein is situated on the white blood cells surface and is an antigen that helps the immune system infection causing aliens and healthy body tissues.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Though most of the HLAs protect the body against harmful invaders, HLA B27 is on a particular protein that is responsible for system dysfunction by attacking the healthy cells instead of foreign substances. This causes autoimmune diseases like ankylosing spondylitis or rheumatoid arthritis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/HLA-B27-1-1.jpg"><img class="wp-image-951 size-full alignright" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/HLA-B27-1.jpg" alt="HLA B27" width="225" height="225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/HLA-B27-1.jpg 225w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/HLA-B27-1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/HLA-B27-1-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms that indicate Test Taking</strong><br />
The HLA-B27 test is taken alongside other tests like MRI scan, urine and blood tests to confirm the presence of autoimmune disease.</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>Joint inflammation and skin lesions</li>
<li>Pain in the joints</li>
<li>Eye inflammation that reoccurs</li>
<li>Swelling or stiffness in the neck, chest or spine</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Auto-immune conditions due to HLA-B27</strong><br />
Based on the symptoms the doctor may advise the test to check for the presence and progression of HLA-B27 with certain autoimmune conditions like</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>Bone inflammation in the spine – <strong>Ankylosing spondylitis</strong></li>
<li>Joint inflammation in joints, eyes, urethra, and skins lesions at times – <strong>Reactive arthritis</strong></li>
<li>Swelling and irritation at eyes middle layer – <strong>Anterior uveitis</strong></li>
<li>Joint stiffness, pain, redness, limping, swelling and reduced motion range &#8211; <strong>Juvenile rheumatoid arthritis</strong></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Besides, HLA antigen tests are also taken when a patient needs to undergo a transplant of kidney or bone marrow as they help in determining a suitable match of a donor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diagnosis</strong><br />
If the test is positive, it indicates the presence of HLA- B27 in blood. Though, it still is not a cent percent confirmation that an autoimmune condition may develop. Other symptoms are also taken into account including blood tests and diagnostic exams.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Conclusion</strong><br />
HLA-B27 indicates the presence of the protein in blood but a positive or negative result cannot be taken as a cent percent confirmation of the autoimmune disorder. Once the test is done and the results are out, the doctor will advise you on further steps around the possible condition.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">know more about <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Pregnancy Complications To Be Aware Of</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-pregnancy-complications-to-be-aware-of/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 08:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top 5 Pregnancy Complications]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=889</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The news of pregnancy brings in smiles on the faces of the family members. On the flip side, during the three trimesters, you need to be on your toes and all alert because pregnancy can cause complications if proper care is not taken. Though you are going to be under the scanner all through the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-pregnancy-complications-to-be-aware-of/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Top 5 Pregnancy Complications To Be Aware Of"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The news of pregnancy brings in smiles on the faces of the family members. On the flip side, during the three trimesters, you need to be on your toes and all alert because pregnancy can cause complications if proper care is not taken. Though you are going to be under the scanner all through the pregnancy cycle and your doctor is going to get you tested on various complications, you yourself need to be aware of them and take self-care to keep them at bay.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Here is a run through <em>some complications of pregnancy</em> that can be life threatening to the fetus and the mom as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Top-5-Pregnancy-Complications-To-Be-Aware-Of-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-890 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Top-5-Pregnancy-Complications-To-Be-Aware-Of-1.jpg" alt="Top 5 Pregnancy Complications To Be Aware Of" width="299" height="168" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Pre-eclampisa</strong> &#8211; It is the almost rare condition in pregnancy because it usually affects only 5 % of the pregnant women in India. This condition is caused by high level of proteins in the urine, high blood pressure or kidney conditions post 20 weeks of pregnancy.<br />
Care needs to be taken to be aware and act promptly by the doctor if there are even mild symptoms of it because it can progress fast and can be life-threatening to the baby and the mother too. The solution to it is early delivery.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Gestational Diabetes</strong> &#8211; This is one of the common conditions occurring in pregnant women in India. Around 10% women could be prey to this condition that can be diagnosed during 24-28 weeks of pregnancy. Post-diagnosis your blood sugar levels will be monitored on a regular basis. Most of them with mild conditions manage to keep it at bay through exercise and diet and are able to deliver healthy babies without complications. But, care needs to be taken to avoid it from aggravating because it can then cause serious harm to the fetus.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Placenta Previa</strong> – This condition can cause complications towards the end of pregnancy not in the early stages. Hence, the doctors check the location and placement of your placenta with a sonography test during the second     tri-semester. 1 in 200 women suffer from this condition and it can be quite dangerous if the placenta is at extremely low levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Miscarriage</strong> – One of the most dreaded conditions which can only be avoided by taking proper care, miscarriage is caused in the first 20 weeks. This is common with Indian women and 20% of them experience this condition within 12 weeks mostly. The symptoms of it include spotting and bleeding at the vagina. The doctor does a sonography to check for the condition.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Premature Delivery</strong> – Premature delivery is when the cervix opens before 37 weeks of pregnancy. If the delivery happens too early then it can be life-threatening for the baby, so care needs to be taken to avoid it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The <a title="best Gynecologist in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">department of Obstetrics and Gynecology</a> has been providing comprehensive health care for women. We provide regular clinical services in Obstetrics like antenatal care, labor management, postpartum Care. We also provide specialized care in high risk pregnancies like P.I.H, Eclampsia, GDM, Multiple gestations, BOH. With the backup of NICU, we are able to salvage preterm babies of 30 weeks on wards. Highly qualified doctors, with the help of well equipped labor ward, conduct normal and caesarian deliveries</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>All you Need to know about Brain Tumor</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-brain-tumor/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 10:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brain Tumor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=884</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A brain tumor is a condition that is caused when abnormal cells in the brain grow within the brain or the spinal cord. It can be life threatening because it can disrupt brain functioning. There are two types of brain tumors, ones that are benign (cancerous) and the other malignant (malignant). The life expectancy varies &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-brain-tumor/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All you Need to know about Brain Tumor"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A brain tumor is a condition that is caused when abnormal cells in the brain grow within the brain or the spinal cord. It can be life threatening because it can disrupt brain functioning. There are two types of brain tumors, ones that are benign (cancerous) and the other malignant (malignant). The life expectancy varies depending upon the stage of the cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Benign Tumor</strong> – This tumor grows slowly and does not spread to other tissues, thus is not cancerous in nature.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Malignant Tumor</strong> – This tumor grows very fast and contains cancerous cells that invade other parts of the brain and is considered to be life-threatening condition.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Brain Tumors are also classified as primary and secondary tumors depending on their origin. If the tumor starts in the brain it is known as primary tumor and if it originates from some other part of the body, it is known as a secondary or metastatic tumor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-885 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-300x169.jpg" alt="Brain Tumor - signs" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong></p>
<p>The symptoms of a brain tumor depend upon the type of tumor and the origin of it. The symptoms are mild initially and gradually increase. Sometimes there may be no symptoms at all. Some common symptoms &#8211;</p>
<p>A headache that persists<br />
Nausea, vomiting, and drowsiness<br />
Speech issues<br />
Memory Issues<br />
Seizures or convulsions<br />
Personality Change<br />
Coordination Change</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diagnosis</strong><br />
Diagnosis involves various tests to be carried out including the following-</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>EEG</strong> &#8211; An electroencephalogram is used to record brain activities for abnormalities if any using electrodes that are attached to the head.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>CT Scan</strong> – It gives a detailed X ray picture of the patient’s brain</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>MRI Scan</strong> &#8211; It makes use of magnetic field as well as radio waves and provides a detailed image of the brain<br />
Even biopsy is used to further confirm the presence of a tumor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
The treatment depends on the diagnosis. It includes factors like the type of tumor, the age of the patient, size of the tumor, tolerance levels of the patient to name a few.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Surgery</strong> – The first course of treatment for Cancer starts with surgery and removal of the tumor or a part of it as much as possible. Due care is taken to avoid any harm to the neighboring tissues. The remaining tumor is removed with the help of various cancer therapies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Chemotherapy</strong> &#8211; Chemotherapy is used for treating a serious type of malignant tumor. It stops the cells from multiplying or duplicating.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Radiation Therapy</strong> &#8211; Radiotherapy uses intense energy beams to destroy the tumor and prevent it from growing. It attacks the tumor cells, leading to shrinkage in the tumor, which can further be managed using an immune system of a person.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Radio Surgery</strong> – Also known as stereotactic radiosurgery (SRS), this treatment involves giving a targeted and precise dose in the form of an X-ray radiation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Risk Factors</strong> &#8211; There is no definite reason behind brain tumors. It might be hereditary but in rare cases. The only risk factor associated with the brain tumor is radiation exposure.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Survival</strong> – The survival rate post the diagnosis also depends on a lot of factors but for malignant tumors of a primary type, the 5-year survival rate is even less than 35%.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">RRMCH is one the best hospitals in Bangalore and amongst the <a title="Best Neuro Hospital in India" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best Neuro hospitals in India</a>. Equipped with the latest in Medical Technology, it also offers the expertise of the best neurologist in Bangalore.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>High Belly Fat is Equal To Low Vitamin D &#8211; Know More?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/high-belly-fat-is-equal-to-low-vitamin-d-know-more/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 09:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[High Belly Fat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[High Belly Fat - vit D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Low Vitamin D]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=881</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A recent study has revealed that bigger waistline and high level of belly fat is a sign of lower levels of Vitamin D. We all know that Vitamin D is known to be one of the most important minerals of the body and is responsible for a varied roles. It does protect your body against &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/high-belly-fat-is-equal-to-low-vitamin-d-know-more/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "High Belly Fat is Equal To Low Vitamin D &#8211; Know More?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A recent study has revealed that bigger waistline and high level of belly fat is a sign of lower levels of Vitamin D. We all know that Vitamin D is known to be one of the most important minerals of the body and is responsible for a varied roles. It does protect your body against cancer, diabetes, hair-loss as well as heart failure. Though it is related to bone health it does have a role to play in areas of autoimmune diseases and respiratory tract infections, to name a few.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/High-Belly-Fat-is-Equal-To-Low-Vitamin-D-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-882" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/High-Belly-Fat-is-Equal-To-Low-Vitamin-D-1-1.jpg" alt="High Belly Fat is Equal To Low Vitamin D" width="530" height="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Indian population is said to have a deficiency of Vitamin D on an epidemic scale with around 70 – 100 percent of the population known to have Vitamin D Deficiency. While the link between Obesity and lower Vitamin D levels are always known, a team of researchers tried to dig into the details and understand more on the location as well as the type of role it plays. The study was based on the data of thousands of women from Epidemiology of obesity study of Netherlands.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The researching team concentrated on total fat that included belly fat (abdominal subcutaneous adipose tissue) under the skin (visceral adipose tissue) as well as in the liver (hepatic fat) and around the organs. They even made necessary adjustments around data with respect to education level, chronic disease, smoking, alcohol intake and physical activity levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The study found that abdominal fat had the greatest effect of lower vitamin D levels while both abdominal fat as well as total fat were linked to the deficiency in vitamin D. The other fact that came forth was in both males and females higher belly fat pointed to lower Vitamin D levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The study also revealed that people who have bigger waistlines are at a higher risk of developing Vitamin D deficiency and need to check up their Vitamin D levels as well. The study also sorts answers around questions like the reason behind the Vitamin D Deficiency, whether it was because the belly fat increased or was it that the deficiency resulted in the fat being stored in the belly part. Even though it’s tricky to draw a conclusion on why there is an association between vitamin D levels and obesity but one point is clear that there is apparently a strong association and that vitamin D has a definite role to play in terms of fat storage in the abdomen and function</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
