<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Measles Cases &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/measles-cases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 11:52:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Measles Cases Rise Around The World</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/measles-cases-rise-around-the-world/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Measles Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1071</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Measles is creating a sort of havoc across the world with over 173,000 cases reported in 2017. The reason behind the same is the fact that many parents do not vaccinate their children for the same. The 30% increase in the number of measles cases across the globe is very much due to the same. &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/measles-cases-rise-around-the-world/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Measles Cases Rise Around The World"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Measles is creating a sort of havoc across the world with over 173,000 cases reported in 2017. The reason behind the same is the fact that many parents do not vaccinate their children for the same. The 30% increase in the number of measles cases across the globe is very much due to the same. Although this disease can be prevented with the help of a vaccine, the death toll around the world has been over 110,000, which is startling.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Measles-Cases-Rise-Around-The-World.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1072" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Measles-Cases-Rise-Around-The-World.jpg" alt="Measles Cases Rise Around The World" width="660" height="371" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Measles-Cases-Rise-Around-The-World.jpg 660w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Measles-Cases-Rise-Around-The-World-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Though this disease can be prevented, it is known to be not only highly infectious in nature for also to be causing hearing loss as well as mental disorders in children. It can also result in diphtheria issues in the children who are not vaccinated. Countries like the Russian Federation, Germany and Venezuela have already had high outbreak in measles last year which has led to withdrawal of the interrupted transmission certification as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Measles outbreak affects the poor and down trodden all the more due to ignore or carelessness and even poverty or people residing in the conflict areas. This measles issues is also there around due to negative misinformation within people and trust worthiness as well which leads to skipping or avoiding the vaccine altogether. As per experts, people are not able to understand the importance of vaccination against measles and take it lightly or ignore the same and that it can be a life threatening disease amongst children.</p>
<p><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-995 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg" alt="" width="397" height="41" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg 397w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore-300x31.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 397px) 100vw, 397px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Even in India measles has taken a toll but as per WHO, the rate has dropped by a staggering 43% around 2015-16. Furthermore, the rate is expected to fall even more in the years to come because India has already taken a staunch stance to eradicate measles by 2020. While in 2015 there were around 30,168 cases, 2016 they reduced drastically to 17, 250. India has already planned it out on taking the vaccine to 40 crore Indian children in order to achieve its target or measles eradication by 2020.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
