<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>how much fiber intake &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/how-much-fiber-intake/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 06:19:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How Much Fiber Intake For Prevention Of Diseases</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-much-fiber-intake-for-prevention-of-diseases/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 06:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best neurologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how much fiber intake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1221</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A new study revealed exactly how much fiber is required for keeping the chronic conditions as well as premature mortality at bay. The objective of the study is to set the guideline for consumption of fiber besides bringing to light information around the carbs responsible for protection against non-communicable diseases as well as curb weight &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-much-fiber-intake-for-prevention-of-diseases/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Much Fiber Intake For Prevention Of Diseases"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
new study revealed exactly how much fiber is required for keeping the
chronic conditions as well as premature mortality at bay.  The
objective of the study is to set the guideline for consumption of
fiber besides bringing to light information around the carbs
responsible for protection against non-communicable diseases as well
as curb weight gain. 
</p>



<p>The
author of the study namely Professor Jim Mann, of Otago University
New Zealand and the author of the paper Andrew Reynolds is a
postdoctoral research fellow at Otago’s Dunedin School of Medicine.

</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1222" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases.jpg 678w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 678px) 100vw, 678px" /></figure>



<p>The
study was carried out by Reynolds and colleagues by examination of a
data that had 185 observational studies that included 135 million
person-years besides 58 clinical trials that involved the
participation of 4600 people.  The study analysis was carried across
40 years. 
</p>



<p>As
per prof. Mann, the motivation behind this study was analysis of
previous reviews and meta-analysis.  The scientists studied chronic
condition incidences as well as premature deaths resulting from them.
 The conditions included cardiovascular diseases, stroke, colon
cancer, type 2 diabetes, cancers such as esophageal cancer,
endometrial cancer, prostate cancer to name a few. 
</p>



<p>The
results of the study revealed that people who consume more fiber
daily are      15-30% less prone to premature deaths or any of the
aforementioned conditions. It also determined that daily consumption
of 25 -29 gms of fibre is good for health. Though consumption of more
than 29 gms of fibre could be even more beneficial. 
</p>



<p>Having
said that, the authors cleared that the study did not present any
side effects of fibre consumption but too much fibre could also be
harmful particularly for people with iron and mineral deficiencies.
Even consumption of whole grains in excess can lead to iron
deficiency as per researchers. 
</p>



<p>Lastly,
the study also found that consumption of high amount of fibre results
does relate to less weight and cholesterol levels. 
</p>



<p> Prof. Mann says “ Health benefits of fiber are supported by over 100 years of research into its chemistry, physical properties, physiology and effects on metabolism.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital, Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
