<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>medical colleges in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/medical-colleges-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 09:47:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 09:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Role Of Legumes In Heart Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1245</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes. Though it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual basis. But, recently &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer
by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find
out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes.  Though
it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual
basis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1246" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>Five color legumes for healthy , Soy bean, Navy bean or white bean, Black beam, Red bean and Green bean,</figcaption></figure>



<p>But,
recently researchers of the review called Advances in Nutrition took
up the task of understanding the significance of legumes like
lentils, peas and beans etc. around heart health. 
</p>



<p>Primarily, they focused on cardiovascular diseases like <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">coronary heart</a> disease, stroke, myocardial infarction besides looking into hypertension, obesity and diabetes. They chose cardiovascular diseases because it is one of the most common causes of mortality and even one of the most expensive ones. It is known to cause US 1 billion dollars a day. </p>



<p>They
used the data analysis of Eurpoean Association which recently carried
out a series of systematic reviews as well as meta-analysis for
Diabetics study. The researchers hope that these results could be
quite a help in updating the recommendations already made around the
role of legumes in preventing as well as treating cardio-metabolic
diseases. 
</p>



<p>The
data review and comparison with people with lowest and highest intake
of legumes revealed that dietary pulses that had legumes which either
did or did not include other legumes did decrease coronary heart
disease, obesity incidence and hypertension. 
</p>



<p>
Though the researchers were able to find a positive relationship
between intake of legumes in higher amounts and reduction in certain
parameters related to cardiovascular risks, the conclusion they came
to are muted relatively. 
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers “The overall certainty of the evidence was
graded as low for CVD incidence and ‘very low for all the other
outcomes.” 
</p>



<p>Therefore, the co author of the study Dr Hana Kahleova said “ Americans eat less than one serving of legumes per day, on average. Simply adding more beans to our plates could be a powerful tool in fighting heart disease and bringing down blood pressure.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><strong>Best Cardiologist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Board Games Can Keep Cognitive Degradation At Bay – A Study</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/board-games-can-keep-cognitive-degradation-at-bay-a-study/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 06:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best psychiatrist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1242</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know that board games are a fun way to be engaged in play in doors particularly for kids. But, here’s some news. A new study carried out by the Researchers at Edinburgh university of United Kingdom reveals that board games could actually help Older Adults avert off their cognitive decline. The paper was &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/board-games-can-keep-cognitive-degradation-at-bay-a-study/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Board Games Can Keep Cognitive Degradation At Bay – A Study"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know that board games are a fun way to be engaged in play in
doors particularly for kids. But, here’s some news. A new study
carried out by the Researchers at Edinburgh university of United
Kingdom reveals that board games could actually help Older Adults
avert off their cognitive decline. The paper was authored by Drew
Altschul of School of philosophy, Pscychology and Language sciences
in association with Professor Deary, director of Edinburgh Lothian
Birth Cohorts and published in the Journals of Gerontology. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1243" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games-300x233.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games-768x598.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>FBHDTJ Still-life selection of board games (Monopoly, Chess, Cluedo, Scrabble) with playing cards and gambling chips</figcaption></figure>



<p>The
study was carried out on 1091 subjects born in the year 1936 for
assessment of their mental and cognitive capabilities.  The
researchers did the evaluation for cognitive functioning across ages
11, 70, 73, 79 with the help of 14 different standard cognitive
tests.</p>



<p>The
study included asking questions to participants in the age group of
70 and 76 about how many times across the week they indulged in board
games like bingo, chess, crosswords, cards, bingo and more .  The
researchers also took into account confounding factors like
education, early life cognitive function, activity levels, sex and
health issues to name a few, as a part of their analysis. 
</p>



<p>The
results unleashed that the people who were more into board games in
their later year’s post 70’s were better off maintaining their
cognitive functioning. Particularly those older adults who indulged
in analog games post 70’s showed relative less decline in cognitive
abilities across 11 and 70 years and also between the age of 70 and
79. 
</p>



<p>Altschul,
one of the study leads says “ these latest findings add to evidence
that being more engaged in activities during the life course might be
associated with better thinking skills in later life”. 
</p>



<p>While coauthor thinks that there is a possibility that there is an interpretation of results as push to start playing board games and avoid cognitive decline.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/"><strong>Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best dermatologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1238</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Also known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and obesity. Many a times your skin shows you the symptoms and &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Also
known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do
not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a
very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and
obesity. 
</p>



<p>Many
a times your skin shows you the symptoms and it is preventable if you
exercise and maintain normal weight. As per reports around 90% of
cases of diabetes are apparently preventable if measures are taken on
time. Furthermore, if diabetes type 2 is left untreated then it could
also lead to life threatening health complications like heart attack,
kidney failure and strokes. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1239" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg 825w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>So,
why are the warning signs not taken seriously, is one question that
haunts many. The reason could be as simple as not taking them as
signs but simple health issues that could fade away with time or just
taking notice and delaying checkup till it’s forgotten. 
</p>



<p>Well,
let us run down some of the signs that could help you alert around
type 2 diabetes. 
</p>



<ol><li>

	 <strong>Frequent Washroom trips</strong>
	– high blood sugar means kidneys work hard to remove the excess
	sugar form the blood and hence it is considered to be an alarm for
	diabetes if one has to frequently wake up to go to pee. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Frequent urge to drink
	water</strong> – Due to frequent urination, even the urge to drink
	water increases due to dehydration
	</li><li>

	Fatigue – The energy levels
	of type 2 diabetes people are low due to deficiency of sugar through
	the blood stream to the body cells. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Hunger pangs</strong> – Due
	to lack of energy people suffering from type 2 diabetes tend to feel
	hungry on a constant basis even if they’d have eaten recently
	enough
	</li><li>

	<strong>Blurry Vision </strong>– At
	times high sugar could damage vision and result into blurred vision
	in one or both the eyes
	</li><li>

	<strong>Yeast Infections </strong>–
	Excess sugar in body could lead to yeast infection. The affected
	areas could get red, sore or itchy. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Tingling and Numbness</strong>
	– Due to rise in sugar levels people with this condition could
	experience tingling and numbess in their hands and feet. Known as
	neuropathy this condition has chances of worsening with time and
	hence early intervention is required.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Skin Darkening</strong> – For
	people suffering from diabetes, dark, velvety and soft patches
	appear on skin anywhere around the armpits, groin or neck. 
	
</li></ol>



<p> Perhaps, its not that difficult to be alarmed if we only pay attention at the signs. Early intervention could help deal with diabetes in a better way and also keep other life threatening conditions at bay.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 06:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Career In India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1234</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>
A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid
in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The
study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues
at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the
electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants in Partners
biobank for the study. The study was spread across 2 years wherein
the lead author Choi and his team studied through millions of data
points in order to look into people having any depression related
diagnosis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1235" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-768x511.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>
They also calculated the genetic risk score for every participant by
combining information around every participant complete genome to
come to score that determines their genetic risk for developing
depression. The data also revealed that people with high genetic risk
score could be diagnosed about it anytime in the coming 2 years. But,
those who were active physically even with higher genetic risk of
depression were less likely to experience depression. 
</p>



<p>
As per Choi an average 35 minutes of exercise on a daily basis could
help you reduce the risk of depression and even protect you against
depression bouts in future. The findings of the study Choi said that
“our findings strongly suggest that, when it comes to depression,
genes are not destiny and that being physically active has the
potential to neutralize the added risk of future episodes in
individuals who are genetically vulnerable”.</p>



<p> Well, exercise is always a good idea because it is useful and sparing out 30 to 35 minutes for yourself every day is the least you could do for your own wellness. A fit body definitely helps to keep you mind fit. So, invest in exercising atleast half and hour a day and you’ll see the difference in your overall fitness levels soon.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>&#8220;The <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/">department of physiotherapy</a> was established in 2003 at <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital</a> to cater to the preventive, creative, therapeutic and rehabilitation needs of the rural people need was felt to impart the much needed physiotherapy vocational and rehabilitation training programme. &#8220;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 10:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1231</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[No a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions. But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town, even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus. The &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>No
a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around
relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions.
But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and
global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town,
even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus.
</p>



<p>The
earlier studies primarily were carried out for a short period of time
and only have been able to identify  the links between mental health
as well as temperature but the research till date only involves short
time period and more focused on connection rather than causal
factors. Moreover, this findings have so far not yielded any
substantial conclusions. So, the researchers with this study are
hoping to get answers to their questions that are not answered as
yet. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1232" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png 860w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-300x160.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-768x411.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
researchers for their study has gathered data from various sources
including Californian emergency departments,  collecting data and
analyzing information from the data of mental health diagnosis visits
during the period of 2005 – 2016. 
</p>



<p>They
even mined for data around suicides in America during 1960 – 2016
period.  These information was based on statuses that were
individually self-reported.  After drilling the climatic temperature
in US down, the researchers managed to develop ‘’fine spatial and
temporal scales”.</p>



<p>From
the study the researchers concluded that the mental health outcomes
decrease as the temperatures cool and the increase mental health
issues with rise in temperatures. Statistically speaking they found
that there was a rise in 0.48% rise in mental health visits with a
rise in average monthly temperature of 1<sup>0</sup> F and even a
rise in suicides by 0.35%</p>



<p>In
short, the rise and drop in temperatures has a significant impact of
the mental health because the authors of the study also showed
stability in the estimates even when accounted for socio economic
status and air conditioning adoption. 
</p>



<p>As for suicide rate, it rises only if there is a rise in temperature amid the growing season because growing season is all about crop yields. If the temperature rises, the crop yield reduces and leads to financial issues that in turn increase the risk of suicides.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance – Check Out Their Amazing Health Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eat-indian-jujube-in-abundance-check-out-their-amazing-health-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 09:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Indian Jujube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1228</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The winter has almost arrived, and with it has arrived the season of Indian Jujube, or as we call them locally BER. Not many are aware that they are also known as the Korean date or Chinese date or even Indian Date. A bite sized fruit, it is relished by many but very few of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eat-indian-jujube-in-abundance-check-out-their-amazing-health-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance – Check Out Their Amazing Health Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The winter has
almost arrived, and with it has arrived the season of Indian Jujube,
or as we call them locally BER.  Not many are aware that they are
also known as the Korean date or Chinese date or even Indian Date. 
</p>



<p>A bite sized fruit, it is relished by many but very few of us really know about its umpteen health benefits.   Here’s a run down some of them –</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-1024x678.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1229" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-300x199.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-768x509.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Rich Source of Vitamin C</strong> – Jujube’s are known to be
	loaded with vitamin C as well as antioxidents and we all know the
	role of Vitamin C in revitalizing our skin, building immunity as
	well as fighting free radicals. Just consuming around 100 gms of
	Jujube can give you 69 mg of Vitamin C. Hence, eating jujube could
	be a great way of getting vitamin C as our body is not capable of
	producing the same. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Bone
	Strength</strong> – Want strong bones? Eat Jujubes. Yes, you read that
	right. Jujubes are also power packed with calcium, iron as well as
	phosphorous thus helping in improving. Hence, it’s a tasty
	alternative for people with oesteoprosis and bone degrading.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Anxiety
	soother</strong> – This fruit is known to have a calming effect on the
	brain as well as the nervous system. Jujube as well as its oil
	extract is known have sedative effects and relax your body down by
	working on the hormonal levels. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Constipation
	Relief</strong> – Jujube is known to provide great relief to people
	suffering from chronic constipation. As per statistics over 20%
	Indians suffer from chronic constipation and still its not been on
	the list of concerns. As jujube’s are a rich source of fibre, they
	help in digestion and regulation of bowel movements. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Sleep
	Well</strong> – Jujubes are rich in antioxidant pythochemicals,
	sapnins, flavonoids and polysaccharides known to have sedative
	properties. Hence, it helps in sleeping well by calming the nerves.
	So, people if you are suffering from insomnia, try jujubes.
</li></ol>



<p>Well, as this fruit is rich in fibre as well, its also considered to aid people looking at weight loss.  Perhaps, its high time you make it an integral part of your fruit consumption or diet may be.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Top Medical College in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Much Fiber Intake For Prevention Of Diseases</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-much-fiber-intake-for-prevention-of-diseases/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 06:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best neurologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how much fiber intake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1221</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A new study revealed exactly how much fiber is required for keeping the chronic conditions as well as premature mortality at bay. The objective of the study is to set the guideline for consumption of fiber besides bringing to light information around the carbs responsible for protection against non-communicable diseases as well as curb weight &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-much-fiber-intake-for-prevention-of-diseases/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Much Fiber Intake For Prevention Of Diseases"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
new study revealed exactly how much fiber is required for keeping the
chronic conditions as well as premature mortality at bay.  The
objective of the study is to set the guideline for consumption of
fiber besides bringing to light information around the carbs
responsible for protection against non-communicable diseases as well
as curb weight gain. 
</p>



<p>The
author of the study namely Professor Jim Mann, of Otago University
New Zealand and the author of the paper Andrew Reynolds is a
postdoctoral research fellow at Otago’s Dunedin School of Medicine.

</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1222" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases.jpg 678w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 678px) 100vw, 678px" /></figure>



<p>The
study was carried out by Reynolds and colleagues by examination of a
data that had 185 observational studies that included 135 million
person-years besides 58 clinical trials that involved the
participation of 4600 people.  The study analysis was carried across
40 years. 
</p>



<p>As
per prof. Mann, the motivation behind this study was analysis of
previous reviews and meta-analysis.  The scientists studied chronic
condition incidences as well as premature deaths resulting from them.
 The conditions included cardiovascular diseases, stroke, colon
cancer, type 2 diabetes, cancers such as esophageal cancer,
endometrial cancer, prostate cancer to name a few. 
</p>



<p>The
results of the study revealed that people who consume more fiber
daily are      15-30% less prone to premature deaths or any of the
aforementioned conditions. It also determined that daily consumption
of 25 -29 gms of fibre is good for health. Though consumption of more
than 29 gms of fibre could be even more beneficial. 
</p>



<p>Having
said that, the authors cleared that the study did not present any
side effects of fibre consumption but too much fibre could also be
harmful particularly for people with iron and mineral deficiencies.
Even consumption of whole grains in excess can lead to iron
deficiency as per researchers. 
</p>



<p>Lastly,
the study also found that consumption of high amount of fibre results
does relate to less weight and cholesterol levels. 
</p>



<p> Prof. Mann says “ Health benefits of fiber are supported by over 100 years of research into its chemistry, physical properties, physiology and effects on metabolism.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital, Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finances and Aging – The Connection</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/finances-and-aging-the-connection/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 06:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best dermatologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finances and Aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1217</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A recent study has revealed that people who have to suffer from economic hardships for even as less as 4 years are prone to ageing faster as compared to their peers who are economically stable. The researchers at the Department of Public health at the Copenhagen University of Denmark carried out a study to compare &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/finances-and-aging-the-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Finances and Aging – The Connection"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
recent study has revealed that people who have to suffer from
economic hardships for even as less as 4 years are prone to ageing
faster as compared to their peers who are economically stable.  The
researchers at the Department of Public health at the Copenhagen
University of Denmark carried out a study to compare economically
well to do, late middle aged adults and adults experiencing financial
issues. 
</p>



<p>The
study involved over 5575 adults in their late middle ages with a
benchmark hardship of 60% less than that of the national average over
22 years period. Out of these 5575, 18% were having financial
hardship during the period of 1987-2008. Lead by Rikki Lund, the team
studied and analyzed cognitive as well as physical functions like
chair rise, jump, balance, grip and strength. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Finances-and-Aging-–-The-Connection.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1218" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Finances-and-Aging-–-The-Connection.jpg 520w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Finances-and-Aging-–-The-Connection-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 520px) 100vw, 520px" /></figure>



<p>The
study found that people who experienced poverty over 4 years
performed less as compared to people of the same age who were living
without any financial problems. The findings suggest that the absence
of economic problems protects from aging faster while the opposite
not only increases ageing but also the blood CRP levels. 
</p>



<p>When
people are less capable of doing physical activities earlier than
then the others of the same age it is called accelerated aging. It
could be a result of higher inflammatory markers like C-reactive
protein (CRP) and IL-6 or poor cognitive functioning. 
</p>



<p>In
the Western society, aging population means more healthcare costs and
hence healthy ageing is promoted.  The study has results that match
the earlier studies with did show an inverse connection between
economic difficulties and physical abilities besides cognitive
difficulties that have been already reported. 
</p>



<p>Having said that, there is one story that has a different story to tell. It states that a human’s perception about economic hardships is more significant indicator and not their real financial condition.  The study does come with a few limitations though, which include factors like not considering data of various societies, not considering any other potential confounding factors responsible or even diseases and conditions that are not a result of poverty but still could affect longevity and speed ageing.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Genetic Components Related To Left Handedness – A Study</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetic-components-related-to-left-handedness-a-study/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best neurologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1205</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A recent study by scientists reveals about regions of the Human DNA and their association with left handedness. These regions are connected to the brains language related features. An earlier study around handedness had revealed that genes were responsible for 25% of it but the type or name of the genes was unknown. In India &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetic-components-related-to-left-handedness-a-study/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Genetic Components Related To Left Handedness – A Study"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
recent study by scientists reveals about regions of the Human DNA and
their association with left handedness. These regions are connected
to the brains language related features. An earlier study around
handedness had revealed that genes were responsible for 25% of it but
the type or name of the genes was unknown. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Genetic-Components-Related-To-Left-Handedness.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1206" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Genetic-Components-Related-To-Left-Handedness.jpg 685w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Genetic-Components-Related-To-Left-Handedness-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 685px) 100vw, 685px" /></figure>



<p>In
India and across the world there were has been a lot of stigma and
taboo around being left handed. But, today rarely anyone is of the
belief or even discriminates between left and right handed people. 
</p>



<p>10%
of the population in the world is known to be left handed and also
includes many well-known individuals like Alert Einstein and Leonardo
da Vinci amongst them.  
</p>



<p>The
recent study was published in the journal ‘Brain’ and involved
the participation of 40,000 people including 38000 left handed ones.
After doing the genetic analysis, the researchers found that it was
the DNA regions that linked to left handedness strongly.  
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers the three regions are inside or are responsible
for protein code of brain development and patterning.  Proteins play
a significant role in making microtubules which are scaffolding like
building block and are responsible for guiding cell construction. 
</p>



<p>Microtubules
are made up of long chained molecules making up the physical
structure of the cells throughout the body also known as cytoskeleton
and have the ability to respond to cell singals by quickly assembling
and disassembling. 
</p>



<p>The
scientists did study brain scan details of 9000 participants after
analyzing their DNA samples.  The findings indicate that in left
handed people right and left side for brain that deals with language
coordinate in a better way compared to right handed ones. These
findings thus pave the path for getting deeper into finding if left
handed people are better in tasks that involve verbal communication
compared to the right handed ones. 
</p>



<p>Well, as per Gwenaelle Dououad, associate professor at the Wellcome Centre for Integrative Neuroimaging that it was apparently for the first time that they had been able to establish that in humans the handedness is linked to cytoskeletal differences in the brain.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Know more about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Blood Test That Predicts How Long You Would Live</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/a-blood-test-that-predicts-how-long-you-would-live/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 10:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1196</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Even today with all the advancement in science and technology, doctors are not able to predict how long a person would live, well in advance. Probably the can predict it with some accuracy within a year of his/her death but not as early as 5-10 years. A recent study published in the journal Nature Communications &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/a-blood-test-that-predicts-how-long-you-would-live/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A Blood Test That Predicts How Long You Would Live"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Even
today with all the advancement in science and technology, doctors are
not able to predict how long a person would live, well in advance.
Probably the can predict it with some accuracy within a year of
his/her death but not as early as 5-10 years. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/A-Blood-Test-That-Predicts-How-Long-You-Would-Live.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1197" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/A-Blood-Test-That-Predicts-How-Long-You-Would-Live.jpg 636w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/A-Blood-Test-That-Predicts-How-Long-You-Would-Live-300x180.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></figure>



<p>A
recent study published in the journal Nature Communications the
researchers are in the process of developing a reliable predictive
tool that could pave the path towards predicting life span of a
person as early as 5-10 years before time.  As per the researchers
this would help the doctors design the course of treatment and take
important decisions related to them.  Like for example doctors could
be able to identify between patients in need of medicine or surgery
and also help scientists in monitoring the impact of intervention on
mortality risk that so without running clinical trials.</p>



<p>Presently,
doctors are able to have a fair idea about the general life span of
people through their cholesterol and blood pressure levels. Through
this study the researching scientists from Leiden University Medical
Center of Netherlands as well as Brunel University London researched
around identification of biomarkers for managing the same. 
</p>



<p>The study included 44, 168 participants between the age group of 10 -109 years of which 5512 passed away. The study began by creating mortality metabolic marker followed by  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <strong><a href="https://college.rrmch.org/">Medical Colleges in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
