<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Karvaan &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/karvaan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 08:41:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>RajaRajeswari Dental College and Hospital celebrates its 17th Graduation Day</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/rajarajeswari-dental-college-and-hospital-celebrates-its-17th-graduation-day/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 08:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karvaan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RajaRajeswari Dental College and Hospital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=73</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Bangalore, October 5th, 2012: RajaRajeswari Dental College and Hospital celebrated its 17th Graduation Day and spearheaded ‘Karvaan’, the cultural event, 2012 at its Mysore Road campus with actor Ragini Dwivedi. The graduation day was graced by honored dignitaries such as Sri A.C. Shanmugam, Chairman, RajaRajeswari Group of Institutions and renowned dentist, Professor Dr. Ramananda Shetty, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/rajarajeswari-dental-college-and-hospital-celebrates-its-17th-graduation-day/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "RajaRajeswari Dental College and Hospital celebrates its 17th Graduation Day"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/bin/slideshow.swf" width="600" height="400" flashvars="host=picasaweb.google.com&#038;hl=en_US&#038;feat=flashalbum&#038;RGB=0x000000&#038;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fpicasaweb.google.com%2Fdata%2Ffeed%2Fapi%2Fuser%2F107027427731342112081%2Falbumid%2F5797554057710151377%3Falt%3Drss%26kind%3Dphoto%26authkey%3DGv1sRgCLPUqPbnw4K4bQ%26hl%3Den_US" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer"></embed><br />
<br />
<strong>Bangalore, October 5th, 2012</strong>: RajaRajeswari Dental College and Hospital celebrated its 17th Graduation Day and spearheaded ‘<strong>Karvaan</strong>’, the cultural event, 2012 at its Mysore Road campus with actor Ragini Dwivedi. The graduation day was graced by honored dignitaries such as Sri A.C. Shanmugam, Chairman, RajaRajeswari Group of Institutions and renowned dentist, Professor Dr. Ramananda Shetty, Vice Chancellor of NITTE in Mangalore who was the chief guest of the event delivered the convocation address.<span id="more-73"></span></p>
<p>Congratulating the students who graduated as dentists this year, <strong>Sri A.C. Shanmugam, Chairman, RajaRajeswari Dental College and Hospital</strong> said, “Karnataka is highly regarded nationally as a  state that provides quality education specially in the field of Medical and dental science. Graduation Day is extremely significant for all of you and it feels great to see that each one of you look really confident to apply their skills for the service of mankind. This is a career that gives you the option to bring a change in the social order. So, I would like to convey my best wishes to all the graduates believing that you will make us proud. People in our nation requires dental care and you have to shoulder the responsibility to guide them.”</p>
<p>The Chief Guest, <strong>Professor Dr. Ramananda Shetty, Vice Chancellor of NITTE in Mangalore</strong> said, “We have 307 institutions in the country that coach dentistry and around 30,000 dentists are produced annually from these institutions. In a country like India where we have a huge population, the number of dentists is really less. Hence, in order to fill this gap we need to produce quality dentists. Our chief focus should be on providing the country with qualified dentists.” He added, “Another striking aspect that we witnessed in this institution is that among all the students 60% students are girls. This shows that huge development that we have made in the education front.”  The students of the college highlighted the graduation day with cultural activities aimed at developing the cultural talents through constructive expression of art. The activities included group dance performances, singing (solo &#038; group) and local theatrical arts.<br />
<strong>For further media query please contact</strong>: Tejasvi / Nivedita<br />
9742023272 / 9901576620 tejasvi@brand-comm.com / niveditaghosh@brand-comm.com<br />
<strong><br />
About RajaRajeswari Group of Institutions:</strong><br />
RajaRajeswari Group of Institutions is looking at engaging the students in overall developmental processes. The dedicated staff is devoted to the task of incorporating latest teaching methods with modern equipments and electronic gadgets for the benefit of the students. These proactive teaching methodologies have resulted in higher performance in academics, industry interface and placement activity.<br />
The main focus of RajaRajeswari Group of institutions is to empower students with sound knowledge, wisdom, experience and training both in the academic level and in the highly competitive global industrial scenario. The infrastructure facilities and state-of-the-art equipments contribute to an enjoyable and an easy learning experience. Moogambigai Charitable and Educational Trust was established in the year 1992 by the chairman Sri A.C. Shanmugam, B.A.L.L.B. with the sole objective for starting higher educational institution of exemplary stature to serve the people of Karnataka.<br />
<strong><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/gallery/Graduation_Day-2012.html">Go to Photo Gallery</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
