<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>laser eye treatment in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/laser-eye-treatment-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 06:22:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dark Spot on the sclera of eye? What is it!</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dark-spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-what-is-it/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 06:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser eye operations in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=878</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When there is any spot on the sclera, it is prominent because of the white background. Hence, it catches your notice mostly within no time of surfacing. So, if you are one of those who has recently discovered a spot on the white area of your eye or sclera as it is called, then here’s &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dark-spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-what-is-it/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dark Spot on the sclera of eye? What is it!"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">When there is any spot on the sclera, it is prominent because of the white background. Hence, it catches your notice mostly within no time of surfacing. So, if you are one of those who has recently discovered a spot on the white area of your eye or sclera as it is called, then here’s what you need to know about the same.<br />
Usually, these freckles or spots are harmless but if it has occurred suddenly out of the blue, then it’s advisable to consult an ophthalmologist because it could be a sign of something critical or cancer as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Dark-Spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-879" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Dark-Spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-1-1.jpg" alt="Dark Spot on the sclera of eye" width="600" height="451" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>SPOTS, TYPES AND CAUSES</strong><br />
These spots unlike moles are more of a lesion or nevus, mostly flat or may be slightly raised in either black, pink or brown color. Sometimes this nevus could be pigmentation free as well. This nevus could also occur in tissue beneath the retina and needs a special lamp to view.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also known as pigmented tumors, these spots or freckles are almost harmless. The most common of the eye tumors is Congenital nevi besides others like conjunctival melanoma and melanosis. Nevi is caused due pigmentation cells or over-growth of melanocytes. Most of the people who have nevi have it since their birth or it surfaces in their early childhood itself. Usually, the spot might not be noticeable until puberty because at this age it becomes bigger and darker too.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While primary acquired melanosis usually occurs in the middle to people with fair skin and suddenly too, the rarest form is the Conjunctival melanosis and it either occurs suddenly or as primary acquired melanosis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
As per the eye cancer network most eye pigmented lesions are benign in nature and practically harmless. But, the eye specialists need to monitor these lesions to check for any signs of shape change and growth. Particular attention needs to be paid on whether the lesion extends to the cornea or develops an increase in blood supply. As compared to malignant lesions the benign nevi grow at a slower rate. In case there is any change in the shape or size of the lesion the doctor might advise a biopsy but congenital nevi becoming cancerous is extremely rare even if it shows a change in shape or size.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, dark spots in the sclera are usually not a matter of grave concern but it’s always advisable that you consult your<a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank"> ophthalmologist</a> to get a clear idea of the lesion or nevi and further line of action.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
