<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons at Glasgow in United Kingdom &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/royal-college-of-physicians-and-surgeons-at-glasgow-in-united-kingdom/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 05:59:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Chairman of RRMCH, Mr. A.C Shanmugam felicitates Dr. Ian Anderson</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/chairman-of-rrmch-mr-a-c-shanmugam-felicitates-dr-ian-anderson/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 05:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dr. Ian Anderson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dr. John Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overseas universities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons at Glasgow in United Kingdom]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=110</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Bangalore: The RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital has joined hands with overseas universities of high repute to enhance its educational standards to higher levels. In an event of great splendor, the Chairman of  RRMCH, Mr. A.C Shanmugam felicitated Dr. Ian Anderson, the President of the prestigious Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons at Glasgow in &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/chairman-of-rrmch-mr-a-c-shanmugam-felicitates-dr-ian-anderson/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Chairman of RRMCH, Mr. A.C Shanmugam felicitates Dr. Ian Anderson"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Bangalore: </strong>The RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital has joined hands with overseas universities of high repute to enhance its educational standards to higher levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In an event of great splendor, the Chairman of  RRMCH, Mr. A.C Shanmugam felicitated<strong> </strong>Dr. Ian Anderson, the President of the prestigious Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons at Glasgow in United Kingdom and the Chief Executive Officer of the institution, Dr. John Cooper in the college campus at Mysore Road. This is a glorious example for the efforts of RRMCH to go beyond boundaries to promote high standard education..</p>
<p><object width="600" height="400" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="src" value="https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/bin/slideshow.swf" /><param name="flashvars" value="host=picasaweb.google.com&amp;hl=en_US&amp;feat=flashalbum&amp;RGB=0x000000&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fpicasaweb.google.com%2Fdata%2Ffeed%2Fapi%2Fuser%2F107027427731342112081%2Falbumid%2F5818315363848979777%3Falt%3Drss%26kind%3Dphoto%26authkey%3DGv1sRgCPyckKyO8va8RQ%26hl%3Den_US" /><param name="pluginspage" value="http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer" /><embed width="600" height="400" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/bin/slideshow.swf" flashvars="host=picasaweb.google.com&amp;hl=en_US&amp;feat=flashalbum&amp;RGB=0x000000&amp;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fpicasaweb.google.com%2Fdata%2Ffeed%2Fapi%2Fuser%2F107027427731342112081%2Falbumid%2F5818315363848979777%3Falt%3Drss%26kind%3Dphoto%26authkey%3DGv1sRgCPyckKyO8va8RQ%26hl%3Den_US" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer" /></object></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span id="more-110"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Speaking at the occasion, <strong>A. C Shanmugam, Chairman of RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital </strong>said, “Over the years, there have been our best efforts to develop some of the most efficient new generation medical practitioners in the country. We have maintained close communication with foreign medical universities to match up with the global standards offering our students the latest technologies, infrastructure and facilities.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">With an earnest effort to initiate cross country knowledge sharing platform, the RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital has always maintained liberal views in the field of education.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Chief Guest at the occasion, <strong>Dr. Ian Anderson, President, College of Physicians and Surgeons at Glasgow in United Kingdom </strong>said, “Within a brief period of time, we have realized that India is a leading nation with some of the most reputed world class medical institutions that produce top notch medical practitioners. This energy and legendary achievement of has attracted us to come and visit such institutes like the RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital. We are not hesitant to enter a partnership with such institutions to exchange scientific knowledge with them.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Apart from the medical students and faculties, some of the most eminent figures of Indian medical fraternity Dr. Jagadeesan, President of IMSA World Head Quarters and Padmashri R.M. Vasagam, Pro-Chancellor of Dr.M.G.R. Educational and Research Institute were also present at the felicitation program.</p>
<p><strong>About Rajarajeswari Group of Institutions:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Rajarajeswari Group of Institutions is aiming at engaging the students in overall developmental processes. Their exemplary staff is devoted to the task of incorporating latest teaching methods into the conventional system, with the use of modern equipments and electronic gadgets that will benefit the students. These proactive teaching methodologies have resulted in a higher performance in academics, industry interface and placement activities.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The main focus of Rajarajeswari Group of institutions is to empower the students with sound knowledge, wisdom, and experience and train them both in the academic level and in highly competitive global industrial scenario. The intelligent infrastructure and state-of-the-art equipments of RRMCH help to create an enjoyable and an easy learning experience for students. ‘Moogambigai Charitable and Educational Trust’ was established in the year 1992 by the chairman Sri A.C. Shanmugam, B.A.L.L.B. with a sole objective of contributing a higher educational institution of exemplary stature to the people of Karnataka.</p>
<p><strong>For further media query please contact:</strong></p>
<p>Nivedita / 9901576620</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">niveditaghosh@brand-comm.com</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe width="525" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X1KwQByjlUw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
