<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Narayana Hrudayalaya &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/narayana-hrudayalaya/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 06:53:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital hosts IMSA DR. R. R THUKRAL SOUTHERN CHAPTER</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/rajarajeshwari-medical-college-and-hospital-hosts-imsa-dr-r-r-thukral-southern-chapter/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 06:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dr. M. Ramanathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Executive Director]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IMSA DR. R. R THUKRAL SOUTHERN CHAPTER]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Medical Sciences Academy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manipal hospital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health and Neurosciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Narayana Hrudayalaya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NIMHANS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vice-chancellor of Annamalai University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vijay Anand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=59</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Bangalore, August 7, 2012: RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital recently hosted the inauguration of the R.R Thukral Southern chapter of the International Medical Sciences Academy in the city. The two day conference happened on 3rd and 4th August 2012 received a footfall of innumerable eminent doctors and medical advisors across the country. The platform has &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/rajarajeshwari-medical-college-and-hospital-hosts-imsa-dr-r-r-thukral-southern-chapter/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital hosts IMSA DR. R. R THUKRAL SOUTHERN CHAPTER"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/bin/slideshow.swf" width="610" height="408" flashvars="host=picasaweb.google.com&#038;captions=1&#038;hl=en_US&#038;feat=flashalbum&#038;RGB=0x000000&#038;feed=https%3A%2F%2Fpicasaweb.google.com%2Fdata%2Ffeed%2Fapi%2Fuser%2Frrhospitalblr%2Falbumid%2F5774238369659831985%3Falt%3Drss%26kind%3Dphoto%26authkey%3DGv1sRgCN6ysLywn5GREg%26hl%3Den_US" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer"></embed></p>
<p><strong>Bangalore, August 7, 2012: RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital</strong> recently hosted the inauguration of the R.R Thukral Southern chapter of the International Medical Sciences Academy in the city.  The two day conference happened on 3rd and 4th August 2012 received a footfall of innumerable eminent doctors and medical advisors across the country.<span id="more-59"></span></p>
<p>The platform has been created to discuss and resolve varied health related issues,  which is witnessing a vertical rise amongst people where in a  paradigm shift in the health care solutions also needed to be addressed.</p>
<p>Several renowned medical institutions like National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences (NIMHANS), Manipal hospital, Narayana Hrudayalaya and many more participated at the conference to share their experiences in the medical field.  Among the most eminent speakers were, Dr. Somashekar, specialist in Oncosurgery of MANIPAL HOSPITAL, Dr. Prathima Murthy, Professor of Psychiatry at NIMHANS, Dr. MuraliManohar specialist in Cardio-Thoracic and Vascular Surgery of Narayana Hrudayalaya delivered outstanding lectures based on their experiences in their respective specializations. They also shared their practical experiences in the profession and interacted with the audiences addressing their queries. </p>
<p>On the occasion, <strong>Vijay Anand, Executive Director, RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital </strong>said, “This conference has given our institution a whole new dimension to explore wider diversities in medical sciences. It has given our medical students a national exposure which will help them in progressing further as medical practitioners.”</p>
<p>The chief guest of the conference, <strong>Dr. M. Ramanathan, Vice-chancellor of Annamalai University</strong> said, “The aspiring medical students who have been a part of this platform are privileged that they have been given such an exposure at such a young stage of their professional lives. I am also delighted to see the immense growth of the institution and I believe this is the right step in the right direction to produce some of the most efficient doctors in the county.” </p>
<p>The conference, an initiative taken in the state by <strong>RRMCH</strong>, has been an enriching and enlightening experience for the audience and the institution was appreciated and applauded for the same.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
