<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>kidney pain &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/kidney-pain/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 08:53:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Lower Back Pain vs Kidney Pain &#8211; The Difference</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lower-back-pain-vs-kidney-pain-the-difference/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 08:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lower back pain vs kidney pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=697</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many of us fail to figure out the difference when we experience pain particularly when its either kidney or lower back pain. So, to begin get down to the definition of lower back pain and kidney pain. It’s called lower back pain when it occurs anywhere from the buttocks upto the lower back. While kidney &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lower-back-pain-vs-kidney-pain-the-difference/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Lower Back Pain vs Kidney Pain &#8211; The Difference"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Many of us fail to figure out the difference when we experience pain particularly when its either<em> kidney or lower back pain</em>. So, to begin get down to the definition of<em> lower back pain and kidney pain</em>.</p>
<p align="justify">It’s called <strong>lower back pain</strong> when it occurs anywhere from the buttocks upto the lower back. While <strong>kidney pain</strong> is said to occur between the hips or flanks and the ribs. At times you may experience it in the upper abdominal region as well. Well, this is the basic difference in back pain and kidney pain but otherwise also there are many other difference that can help you figure out which kind of pain you are suffering from. Here’s a sneak peek into a few other differences between kidney pain and lower back pain.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-698 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-300x147.jpg" alt="LOWER BACK PAIN VS KIDNEY PAIN" width="300" height="147" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-300x147.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-768x377.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1.jpg 996w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Kidney Pain</strong><br />
Kidney pain is the result of a kidney infection or a kidney stone usually. Kidney infection can cause mild pain but kidney stone pain is very severe in nature and often compared to labor pain.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
The causes of kidney pain include kidney infection and kidney stones as mentioned before besides the pain could also be a result of renal infarction, kidney cancer and glomerulonephritis.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Lower Back Pain</strong><br />
Lower back pain is further divided as acute pain and chronic pain. While acute pain lasts for around 4 to 12 weeks, chronic back pain can easily last over 12 weeks. Also known as lumbago it affects people of all age groups.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
Lower back pain is a result of muscle sprain, spasm or tear leading to disc bulge or herniation, spinal stenosis, osteoporosis or sciatica. It could also be due to vertebral body, pedicle fracture or fracture of lamina. It can be caused due to Paravertebral muscle spasm or metastatic vertebral cancer.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Pain Management</strong><br />
<em>Kidney Pain –</em> Kidney pain treatment depends of its causes and usually involves use of antibiotics and medications if its infection but in case of kidney stones if that does not work a laser surgery or a minimally invasive surgery could be carried out.</p>
<p align="justify"><em>Back Pain</em> – For relief against lower back pain issues treatment could include suitable therapies like heat and cold, physical and massage therapies to name a few. In case with complications based on the diagnosis surgical procedures might be advised.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, its always advisable to visit your doctor if you suffer from back pain in order to figure out the root cause of the problem, be it <em>kidney or lower back</em>.</p>
<p align="justify">know about <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">best hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
