<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>best hospitals in india &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/best-hospitals-in-india/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 04:43:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Top 5 Ongoing Trends in Healthcare Sector</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-ongoing-trends-in-healthcare-sector/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 05:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=912</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Gone are the times when healthcare sector had a reputation of almost negative customer experiences. Nowadays, healthcare companies are going all guns blazing about their approach towards their customers. The approach also includes the optimum use of advanced technology besides newer approaches in-order to create a progressive change in the healthcare industry. Let us run &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-ongoing-trends-in-healthcare-sector/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Top 5 Ongoing Trends in Healthcare Sector"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Gone are the times when healthcare sector had a reputation of almost negative customer experiences. Nowadays, healthcare companies are going all guns blazing about their approach towards their customers. The approach also includes the optimum use of advanced technology besides newer approaches in-order to create a progressive change in the healthcare industry. Let us run through some of the upcoming trends in the healthcare eco-system.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-913 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1.jpg" alt="Trends in Healthcare Sector" width="600" height="300" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1-300x150.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tailored Medicine</strong> – Medicine is all about observation based diagnosis with evidence to support the same. Today, <a title="Health care Services in India" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/health-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">healthcare centers</a> are equipped with the latest in technology that results into accurate and speedy diagnosis. For example, with the help of radiology clinicians can investigate structures deep inside the body and with techniques like histopathology, clinicians can identify virus and tumors using microscopes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Virtual Reality</strong> &#8211; Virtual reality is working well in the management and treatment of pain. As per a study of the recent times, children responded to chemotherapy better when they played games while undergoing the same. This was because their attention got concentrated from the treatment part to the play part and hence even resulted in them requiring less dosage. Side effects like nausea and hypertension were also reduced compared to children who were advised to rest.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Patient Customization</strong> &#8211; Data has grown and so has the ability of the healthcare facilities to provide their customers with an experience that is absolutely personalized. Based on the history of the patient, these clinics provide facilities like potential health issues, doctors preferred by the patient, patient preference in terms of remote treatment or walk in, to name a few. This can help avoid the complexities involved with the navigation through health care professional web and makes patients information available readily for speedy and accurate treatment solutions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Augmented Reality</strong> – Besides other fields, augmented reality is playing a crucial role in healthcare and is fast turning out to be one of the most effective applications in medical training. AR helps doctors while monitoring diagnosis with the treatment procedure options to look forward too. They don’t have to spend time in honing their medical knowledge further because treatment options can simply pop up on their screen with options and suggestions. For example, while doing a child checkup the growth chart can pop up on the monitor itself, thus helping the doctor with seamless treatment procedures.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Smart Technology in Hospitals</strong> – <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Smart Technology in Hospitals</a> has actually helped better patient experience, comfort, and care. For example, many hospitals have started using smart technology in hospitals. In a few countries, certain healthcare outfits use self-adjusting beds for pressure and support customization for patients. Many are also making use of man free facilities where robots carry out the monitoring process of the patient in the room. Smart technology is available in different forms and works in reducing risks while increasing comfort and efficiency. Affirmatively, the use of smart technology across the healthcare ecosystem is poised to grow day by day, obviously so.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
