<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>blood banks in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/blood-banks-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 11:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Encephalitis (CHAMKI Fever) The Deadly Fever That Has Killed Over 150 Children In Bihar And Jharkhand Already</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/encephalitis-chamki-fever-the-deadly-fever-that-has-killed-over-150-children-in-bihar-and-jharkhand-already/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 11:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood banks in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1145</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The news of around 150 children dead due to the chamki fever is already a topic of concern present day. The Supreme Court also has taken notice of this serious or grave situation and directed Center to immediately form a medical expert team for the treatment of children having AES. An inflammation of brain, encephalitis &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/encephalitis-chamki-fever-the-deadly-fever-that-has-killed-over-150-children-in-bihar-and-jharkhand-already/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Encephalitis (CHAMKI Fever) The Deadly Fever That Has Killed Over 150 Children In Bihar And Jharkhand Already"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The
news of around 150 children dead due to the chamki fever is already a
topic of concern present day. The Supreme Court also has taken notice
of this serious or grave situation and directed Center to immediately
form a medical expert team for the treatment of children having AES. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1146" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar.jpg 700w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar-300x172.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /></figure>



<p>An
inflammation of brain, encephalitis commonly known as chamki fever is
the inflammation of brain. It is caused by viral infection and
affects the nervous system. There are two main types of Encephalitis
namely Primary and Secondary. This fever usually occurs in kids and
youngsters below 15 years of age.   
</p>



<p>The
primary is caused due to direct viral infection to the brain while
secondary is a result of a weak immune system and can be a result of
infection in any part of the body.  Presently, there’s an outbreak
of this fever in Bihar and Jharkhand. Recently, even Bengal has
reported three cases of AES or Chamki of which one is critical.  
</p>



<p><strong>Causes
</strong>
</p>



<p>AES
is known to be a viral infection but can occur due to mosquito borne
viruses, Zika or Nipah Virus, Rabis virus, childhood infections,
enteroviruses and herpes virus as well. In India the most commonly
known AES causing virus is the Japanese Encephalitis (JE) as almost 5
-35% cases are that of JE Virus AES. Though, this year only two cases
are due to the JE Virus and exact cause of so many deaths is not
known. What is known is that the deaths were caused by hypoglycemia
(low blood sugar levels) 
</p>



<p>
<strong>Symptoms </strong>
</p>



<p>At
the initial stage the symptoms are similar to mild flu and include
fever, headache, fatigue, muscle or joint pain. Though in the later
or severe stage it leads to hallucinations, agitation, confusion,
muscle weakness, hearing difficulties paralysis, sensation loss,
vomiting, poor eating, body stiffness, skull bulging and more.    
</p>



<p><strong>Treatment
</strong>
</p>



<p>There
is not medicine yet for this fever and the mild one can be brought
down through adequate rest and continuous fluid intake. Drugs like
Tylenol, Aleve and Advil also can be used. Medications like Foscavir,
Cytoven and Zovirax can be used for the viral Encephalitis only on
prescription basis. Do not consume any medications with Doctors
consult. At times supportive care like breathing assistance,
intravenous fluids to keep the person hydrated, anti-convulsant and
anti-inflammatory drugs against seizures and swelling could be
required. 
</p>



<p><strong>Prevention
</strong>
</p>



<p>Prevention is always better and hence to avoid getting this condition try to maintain hygiene at home, clean your hands properly after you visit the toilet and before eating food. Also, drink clean water and use mosquito nets and repellants when sleeping.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about The  <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dementia Risk and Blood Magnesium Levels</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dementia-risk-and-blood-magnesium-levels/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 06:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best psychiatrist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood banks in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dementia Risk and Blood Magnesium Levels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rajarajeswari hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=710</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Before we talk about risk factors associated with dementia lets just polish our information around the condition. This condition usually occurs at an older age and causes memory loss. Alzheimers is one of the most common forms of dementia known. Apparently, its not a condition by a symptoms or group of symptoms rather. You should &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dementia-risk-and-blood-magnesium-levels/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dementia Risk and Blood Magnesium Levels"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Before we talk about risk factors associated with dementia lets just polish our information around the condition. This condition usually occurs at an older age and causes memory loss. Alzheimers is one of the most common forms of dementia known. Apparently, its not a condition by a symptoms or group of symptoms rather. You should also know that it does hamper our day to day routines because we tend to forget a lot. Dementia symptoms are also caused due to vitamin deficiencies and thyroid problems. Dementia occurs due to brain cell damage and most of them are generally permanent or increase with time.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Dementia-Risk-and-Blood-Magnesium-Levels-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-711" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Dementia-Risk-and-Blood-Magnesium-Levels-1-1.jpg" alt="Dementia Risk and Blood Magnesium Levels" width="600" height="320" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Now, a study has found out that the levels of magnesium in your blood can associated to the risk of dementia later in life. The people with lower or higher levels of minerals in the body were subject to dementia more compared to the ones with middle levels. It has yet to be proved and nowhere confirm that it causes dementia but definitely magnesium levels do have a link with dementia. There are apparently two ways in which magnesium levels could be called as risk factor for dementia.</p>
<p align="justify">Coming back to the study, around 10,000 participant around 65 years of age were studied across 8 years span and their magnesium levels were checked at the beginning of the test. They were divided in 5 groups. The study findings showed that those with low and high level magnesium had 30% greater risk of dementia compared to mid level magnesium level participants. The lower and higher magnesium range is below 0.85 millimoles per liter and 1.10 mmol/L respectively. Though as the magnesium levels were not measure post eight years the results could have associated limitations.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, to prove that magnesium levels do determine the risk of dementia in later stages of life, further detailed study is required.</p>
<p align="justify">Know about <a title="Blood Banks in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/giving/donate-blood/" target="_blank">Blood Banks in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>All You Need To Know About Blood Donation In India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-blood-donation-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 05:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood banks in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood banks in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood donation in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[demands of blood in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=443</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[It’s been a daunting task for a long time for the blood banks to meet the ever rising demands of blood in India. Figuratively, the need for blood in India arises every 2 seconds and is a mammoth 5 crore units in all. This makes for a requirement of around 40K blood donations every single &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-blood-donation-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All You Need To Know About Blood Donation In India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">It’s been a daunting task for a long time for the <strong>blood banks</strong> to meet the ever rising demands of<strong> blood in India</strong>. Figuratively, the need for blood in India arises every 2 seconds and is a mammoth 5 crore units in all. This makes for a requirement of around 40K blood donations every single day. Obviously, forget meeting the requirements, even coming to terms with these figures isn’t easy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">So, apparently, India is in need of donors all the time, 24&#215;7. However, cliche or preachy it may sound, but donating blood is a moral responsibility, each one of us should take up if not regularly atleast occasionally during blood donation camps in your area or blood donation day or week may be!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/2-11-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignright wp-image-356 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/2-11-1-300x199.jpg" alt="Blood Donation In India - Blood Banks in Bangalore" width="300" height="199" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Here are a few facts about blood donation to clear off any doubts or queries on the same &#8211;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>BLOOD &amp; TYPES</strong><br />
You can’t make blood, but what you can do is donate. It forms 7% your body weight.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>O -ve donors blood cells can be used by patients of all blood groups, but has a low shelf life, hence is in high demand.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>AB positive plasma can also be used by patients of all blood types, and has good shelf life.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Due to the short shelf life of blood components, a constant supply has to be provided, thus increasing the use of auto-transfusion methods.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Platelets need to be used up within 5 days, RBC’s in around 40 days, while plasma can be stored for almost a year, under refrigeration.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Due to a drastic shoot up of cancer cases and patients opting for chemotherapy, the need for blood has also gone up. Even accident cases are in dire need of high quantities of blood.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>BLOOD DONATION</strong><br />
Blood donation is not only good for others but good for you too because it reduces the risk of heart diseases in men other than glucose and pressure reduction. It also helps patients with iron overload prevent toxic accumulation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The blood banks, hospitals or social service organizations organize blood donation camps and are involved in associated procedures. From the whole blood donated, red blood cells, plasma, platelets and cryoprecipitate components can be transfused, thus a blood bottle is worth many lives.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Potential blood donors have to undergo physical examination before donating blood. The basic requirements include minimum weight of 50 kg and age of 18 years.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Blood donation is extremely safe and either sterile needles or disposable needles are used for the purpose.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You can donate only 1 unit of red blood cells at a time at an interval of 56 or 112 days and as for platelets only 24 times a year that too only once in 7 days.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>If you start donating blood at 18, once every three months by the age of 60 years, you would have saved over 500 lives – being a super hero is sure an extraordinary feat, but you can achieve it buy donating blood regularly, thus saving their lives.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>Donate Blood and Save Life &#8211; <a title="Blood Banks in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/giving/donate-blood/" target="_blank">Best Blood Banks in Bangalore </a></strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
