<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>bangalore hospitals &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/bangalore-hospitals/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best dermatologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1238</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Also known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and obesity. Many a times your skin shows you the symptoms and &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Also
known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do
not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a
very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and
obesity. 
</p>



<p>Many
a times your skin shows you the symptoms and it is preventable if you
exercise and maintain normal weight. As per reports around 90% of
cases of diabetes are apparently preventable if measures are taken on
time. Furthermore, if diabetes type 2 is left untreated then it could
also lead to life threatening health complications like heart attack,
kidney failure and strokes. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1239" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg 825w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>So,
why are the warning signs not taken seriously, is one question that
haunts many. The reason could be as simple as not taking them as
signs but simple health issues that could fade away with time or just
taking notice and delaying checkup till it’s forgotten. 
</p>



<p>Well,
let us run down some of the signs that could help you alert around
type 2 diabetes. 
</p>



<ol><li>

	 <strong>Frequent Washroom trips</strong>
	– high blood sugar means kidneys work hard to remove the excess
	sugar form the blood and hence it is considered to be an alarm for
	diabetes if one has to frequently wake up to go to pee. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Frequent urge to drink
	water</strong> – Due to frequent urination, even the urge to drink
	water increases due to dehydration
	</li><li>

	Fatigue – The energy levels
	of type 2 diabetes people are low due to deficiency of sugar through
	the blood stream to the body cells. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Hunger pangs</strong> – Due
	to lack of energy people suffering from type 2 diabetes tend to feel
	hungry on a constant basis even if they’d have eaten recently
	enough
	</li><li>

	<strong>Blurry Vision </strong>– At
	times high sugar could damage vision and result into blurred vision
	in one or both the eyes
	</li><li>

	<strong>Yeast Infections </strong>–
	Excess sugar in body could lead to yeast infection. The affected
	areas could get red, sore or itchy. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Tingling and Numbness</strong>
	– Due to rise in sugar levels people with this condition could
	experience tingling and numbess in their hands and feet. Known as
	neuropathy this condition has chances of worsening with time and
	hence early intervention is required.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Skin Darkening</strong> – For
	people suffering from diabetes, dark, velvety and soft patches
	appear on skin anywhere around the armpits, groin or neck. 
	
</li></ol>



<p> Perhaps, its not that difficult to be alarmed if we only pay attention at the signs. Early intervention could help deal with diabetes in a better way and also keep other life threatening conditions at bay.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zika Virus &#8211; Symptoms, Causes and treatment</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/zika-virus-symptoms-causes-and-treatment/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 08:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zika Virus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zika Virus - Symptoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zika Virus causes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zika Virus treatment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1040</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Recently, Zika virus has taken a toll in Jaipur with over 42 confirmed cases. A fatal virus, Zika finds its roots in Uganda, where it was discovered in the year 1947. The same mosquito responsible for tracing yellow fever, chikungunya and dengue virus is known to transmit Zika. Thought it can be transmitted through the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/zika-virus-symptoms-causes-and-treatment/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Zika Virus &#8211; Symptoms, Causes and treatment"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Recently, Zika virus has taken a toll in Jaipur with over 42 confirmed cases. A fatal virus, Zika finds its roots in Uganda, where it was discovered in the year 1947. The same mosquito responsible for tracing yellow fever, chikungunya and dengue virus is known to transmit Zika. Thought it can be transmitted through the following besides mosquito –</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>Pregnant women to her unborn child</li>
<li>Blood Transfusion</li>
<li>Sexual intercourse</li>
<li>Possibly through saliva while kissing (may or may not)</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Zika virus can cause various disorders/ Complications like Premature birth, severe dehydration, hearing impairment, eye problems in infants, Acute Disseminated Encephalomyelitis (ADEM) and the following as well &#8211;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1041" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Zika-Virus.jpg" alt="Zika Virus - Symptoms, Causes and treatment" width="755" height="382" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Zika-Virus.jpg 755w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Zika-Virus-300x152.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Congenital malformations</strong><br />
When the virus is transmitted to the unborn child through a pregnant woman, it is bound to attack the nervous system of the child and cause microcephaly or prevent brain growth. It may damage the fetus, which could not be visible immediately but many years of birth. This virus is present in the milk of an infected mother as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Guillain Barre Syndrome</strong><br />
After the Zika virus enters the nervous system, some people tend to suffer from a disorder known as Guillain Barre Syndrome. It can also get into the brain and cause other neurological symptoms. This virus has the ability to not directly attack but get the immune system to attack the nervous system.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong><br />
The symptoms of people infected by Zika include the following</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>Fever</li>
<li>Joint pain</li>
<li>Rash</li>
<li>Nausea</li>
<li>Headache</li>
<li>Conjunctivitis</li>
<li>Chills</li>
<li>Bloodshot eyes</li>
<li>Sweating</li>
<li>Cheek Swelling</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diagnosis</strong><br />
The diagnosis of Zika can be done using a blood, saliva , semen and urine test.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Zika Treatment</strong><br />
As on date there is not treatment or vaccination available for Zika. You only can treat the symptoms using fever reducers and medicines for reducing vomiting or rash.</p>
<p><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img class="size-full wp-image-995 aligncenter" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg" alt="" width="397" height="41" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg 397w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore-300x31.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 397px) 100vw, 397px" /></a></p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Be Aware of the Silent Killer Called Ovarian Cancer</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/be-aware-of-the-silent-killer-called-ovarian-cancer/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 11:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[be aware of Ovarian Cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ovarian Cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ovarian Cancer awareness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1009</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many women aren’t aware that ovarian cancer is also known as the Silent Killer because generally no visible symptoms indicate the presence of this cancer and the symptoms surface only during the final stages. This cancer has known to affect as many as over 20K women across the world every year and due to the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/be-aware-of-the-silent-killer-called-ovarian-cancer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Be Aware of the Silent Killer Called Ovarian Cancer"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Many women aren’t aware that <strong>ovarian cancer</strong> is also known as the Silent Killer because generally no visible symptoms indicate the presence of this cancer and the symptoms surface only during the final stages. This cancer has known to affect as many as over 20K women across the world every year and due to the lack of visible symptoms indicating the cancer, it makes this cancer even scarier.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>CAUSES AND RISKS</strong><br />
The causes of this cancer are not clear as yet but family history is one of the risk factors and the women having a family member or relative with ovarian cancer or breast cancer are definitely at a higher risk of the same. Age can also be termed as one of the risk factors because most women get it after 60 -63 years. Also, the women who have had one or more pregnancies before the age of 26 are at a lower risk. The risk is lower if the number of pregnancies is higher. Even using contraceptives frequently tends to lower the risk of ovarian cancer. As per doctors there is this contraceptive hormone called DMPA or Depo pro-vera CI that if injected of more than 3 years, reduces the risk of ovarian cancer even further. Women who make use of infertility treatment drugs over a period of one year are also known to have a high risk of getting ovarian cancer. Other risk factors include obesity, hormone therapy and gynecologic surgery as in surgery of reproductive organs and getting endometriosis at the age of 30 years.</p>
<p><img class="wp-image-1010 size-medium alignleft" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-300x300.jpg" alt="Ovarian Cancer" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DIAGNOSIS AND STAGES</strong><br />
The doctor on examination will ask for some tests that include blood test, a CT scan or MRI as well as Laparoscopy, biopsy, abdominal fluid aspiration test or colonoscopy for that matter.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Stages</strong><br />
As per the American Cancer society ovarian cancer has four stages<br />
<strong>Stage 1</strong> – This is the preliminary stage of ovarian cancer where only the ovary or the ovaries are affected.<br />
<strong>Stage 2</strong> – This is the secondary stage where the cancer is out of the ovaries and spread around the areas like fallopian tubes, uterus, rectum or the bladder.<br />
<strong>Stage 3</strong> – This is a later stage of cancer where the cancer affects the lymph nodes, abdominal lining or even the back of the abdomen.<br />
<strong>Stage 4</strong> – The last stage of cancer where the cancer has spread to other parts of the body outside the peritoneal cavity viz. abdomen or pelvis upto the liver, fluid around the lungs or the spleen.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><b>SYMPTOMS</b><br />
The initial symptoms of<em> ovarian cancer</em> are easy to miss because they are very much similar to premenstrual syndrome. So, you have to be alert and if you find any of the below mentioned symptoms that persist for a long time then good idea is to go for checkup.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Recurring Abdominal Pain</strong><br />
If you have been experiencing stomach ache for a long time even if you don’t have your monthly cycles then its time you get it tested.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Appetite loss and Nausea</strong><br />
When ovarian cancer starts spreading around, it affects the bowel system and causes nausea. If you feel you have been experiencing and loss in your appetite or feeling full sooner than ever, check it out.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Bloating and Constipation</strong><br />
When a tumor is growing inside you even when you do not eat much you feel fuller and bloated. It can also affect your bowel movement leading to regular constipation issues.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Irregular monthly cycles</strong><br />
A tumor in the ovary will cause your monthly period to become irregular or sorts. So, if you haven’t been experiencing any irregularity in your monthly periods earlier but only lately for a while, good idea to meet up with your doctor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Frequent urination</strong><br />
If you have been making frequent trips to the bathroom for peeing then this could be the sign. Do not ignore and visit your doctor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
The treatment is based on the diagnosis of the stage of the cancer and includes procedures like surgery, chemotherapy, radiation therapy, targeted therapy as well as hormonal therapy. One or more treatments in combination are usually used depending upon the stage of the cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Surgery types</strong><br />
The extent of surgery is also based on the stage and includes removal of ovaries, fallopian tubes, uterus as well the affected surrounding tissues. Then there is de-bulking surgery and lymph node dissections also which is done to reduce the cancerous tissues if the cancer is spread beyond the pelvic region and removal of lymph nodes near the aorta respectively.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Therapy types</strong><br />
Chemotherapy is generally done post-surgery to kill the remaining cancer cells. A medication known as cytotoxic medication poisonous drugs to the cells in-order to prevent growth and division. This is a recurring process based on the cancer growth. Targeted Chemotherapy is another treatment that involves target specific function or pathways of cancer cells. Another therapy that is used as a part to treatment is <strong>Hormone therapy</strong>. It is done to cut the supply of estrogen from the cancer cells in order to slow their growth. Radiation therapy is also used for treatment of cancer and is generally used in advanced form of cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Survival</strong><br />
As the stage increases the survival rate decreases. While for Stage I there is a 90% chance of survival, for stage IV, the chance is 17%.</p>
<p>Know more about <strong><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Cancer Hospital in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Compulsive Doing Syndrome  &#8211; Do you Have It?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/compulsive-doing-syndrome-do-you-have-it/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 11:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compulsive Doing Syndrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1004</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Do you feel that you are very busy and occupied most of the times. Do you answer in a negative when someone asks you to meet up, hangout or for any other meet? Is the answer to most questions about availability as ‘Sorry, Busy’. Then, you have a compulsive doing syndrome. The symptoms of this &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/compulsive-doing-syndrome-do-you-have-it/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Compulsive Doing Syndrome  &#8211; Do you Have It?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Do you feel that you are very busy and occupied most of the times. Do you answer in a negative when someone asks you to meet up, hangout or for any other meet? Is the answer to most questions about availability as ‘Sorry, Busy’. Then, you have a compulsive doing syndrome. The symptoms of this syndrome include –</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1007" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Compulsive-Doing-Syndrome.png" alt="Compulsive Doing Syndrome" width="750" height="518" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Compulsive-Doing-Syndrome.png 750w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Compulsive-Doing-Syndrome-300x207.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;">No time for family affairs</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Not time to eat</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Your to do list goes on increasing</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Sleepless nights for a long time</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">You might seem busy and hardworking but nothing out of the box</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Now, for the reason. This syndrome is because we are brought up believing that being busy means being worthy. This is the most common causes of Compulsive doing syndrome too.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Another reason is that we tend to overburden ourselves until there is no time left for anything to fit in. Many times it can be a sign of running away from problems, situations and issues. So, if you feel that you are busy all the time, know it once and for all that it is apparently a lifestyle issue and needs to be worked up.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Being over occupied without any time to spare apparently show that your time management skills are not good enough. Besides, it also points to clarity or work and focus issues. If you are focused on your work you can finish off your work faster and ample time left for other priorities.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Exercising Breathing for 5 minutes every day helps you calm down, distress and relax. Doing it will certainly help you manage yourself better. Have time allocated for activities that help you feel well mentally, physically and spiritually. Could be a jog, or exercise or music or some extra-curricular activity.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Try to get away from gadgets be it your phone, laptop or television and concentrate on eating while having your meals. Give your family the attention they deserve and not non-living objects over them. Sparing some time out for meditation is definitely a food idea for mental health and overall wellness.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, compulsive doing syndrome can be worked up if you are willing to understand that being busy is very much about time management, concentration and clarity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do You Legs Pain All Night? Know Why</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/legs-pain-all-night-know-why/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1001</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many of us experience leg pain at night. But, ever thought about the reasons behind it. Many of us should have and many should have not. So, if you are also amongst the ones who do experience leg pain at night on a regular basis and have been ignoring it or just bearing it through, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/legs-pain-all-night-know-why/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Do You Legs Pain All Night? Know Why"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Many of us experience leg pain at night. But, ever thought about the reasons behind it. Many of us should have and many should have not. So, if you are also amongst the ones who do experience leg pain at night on a regular basis and have been ignoring it or just bearing it through, here are a few reasons that could be the reason, perhaps.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1002" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Do-You-Legs-Pain-All-Night.jpg" alt="Do You Legs Pain All Night" width="614" height="408" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Do-You-Legs-Pain-All-Night.jpg 614w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Do-You-Legs-Pain-All-Night-300x199.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 614px) 100vw, 614px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Deficiency of vital nutrients</strong><br />
Many of us never know if our diet is a balanced one of not. With a hectic life schedule and not time for to spare towards caring for health besides a diet that is more of junk and less of nutrient rich food, deficiency of vital nutrients like calcium, potassium and magnesium as well as Vitamin D can lead to leg pain.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Dehydration</strong><br />
Nocturnal leg pain is also known to be caused due to dehydration. Due to the electrolyte imbalance in blood, it can lead to nocturnal cramps. So keep yourself hydrated throughout the day and even if you tend to wake up at night stay hydrated.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Standing long hours</strong><br />
Standing for long hours can lead to leg pain at night. The reason is that standing for along time tends to accumulate the blood and water in your lower body causing fluid imbalance and cramping.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Health Conditions</strong><br />
If you are suffering from other health conditions that you are not aware of then, you could be having leg pain due to the same.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Aging</strong><br />
As you age your bones become weak and nocturnal leg pain is pretty common then. It is after 50 years that you may start experiencing this condition because you start losing neurons and get frequent cramps due to it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, health is wealth and ignoring it can lead to an irreversible or life threatening damage to the body. So, if you are experiencing the symptoms get yourself checked and do the needful. Why compromise on quality of life.</p>
<p>Know more about <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>All you Need to know about Brain Tumor</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-brain-tumor/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 10:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brain Tumor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=884</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A brain tumor is a condition that is caused when abnormal cells in the brain grow within the brain or the spinal cord. It can be life threatening because it can disrupt brain functioning. There are two types of brain tumors, ones that are benign (cancerous) and the other malignant (malignant). The life expectancy varies &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-brain-tumor/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All you Need to know about Brain Tumor"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A brain tumor is a condition that is caused when abnormal cells in the brain grow within the brain or the spinal cord. It can be life threatening because it can disrupt brain functioning. There are two types of brain tumors, ones that are benign (cancerous) and the other malignant (malignant). The life expectancy varies depending upon the stage of the cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Benign Tumor</strong> – This tumor grows slowly and does not spread to other tissues, thus is not cancerous in nature.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Malignant Tumor</strong> – This tumor grows very fast and contains cancerous cells that invade other parts of the brain and is considered to be life-threatening condition.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Brain Tumors are also classified as primary and secondary tumors depending on their origin. If the tumor starts in the brain it is known as primary tumor and if it originates from some other part of the body, it is known as a secondary or metastatic tumor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-885 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-300x169.jpg" alt="Brain Tumor - signs" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Brain-Tumor-signs-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong></p>
<p>The symptoms of a brain tumor depend upon the type of tumor and the origin of it. The symptoms are mild initially and gradually increase. Sometimes there may be no symptoms at all. Some common symptoms &#8211;</p>
<p>A headache that persists<br />
Nausea, vomiting, and drowsiness<br />
Speech issues<br />
Memory Issues<br />
Seizures or convulsions<br />
Personality Change<br />
Coordination Change</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diagnosis</strong><br />
Diagnosis involves various tests to be carried out including the following-</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>EEG</strong> &#8211; An electroencephalogram is used to record brain activities for abnormalities if any using electrodes that are attached to the head.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>CT Scan</strong> – It gives a detailed X ray picture of the patient’s brain</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>MRI Scan</strong> &#8211; It makes use of magnetic field as well as radio waves and provides a detailed image of the brain<br />
Even biopsy is used to further confirm the presence of a tumor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
The treatment depends on the diagnosis. It includes factors like the type of tumor, the age of the patient, size of the tumor, tolerance levels of the patient to name a few.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Surgery</strong> – The first course of treatment for Cancer starts with surgery and removal of the tumor or a part of it as much as possible. Due care is taken to avoid any harm to the neighboring tissues. The remaining tumor is removed with the help of various cancer therapies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Chemotherapy</strong> &#8211; Chemotherapy is used for treating a serious type of malignant tumor. It stops the cells from multiplying or duplicating.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Radiation Therapy</strong> &#8211; Radiotherapy uses intense energy beams to destroy the tumor and prevent it from growing. It attacks the tumor cells, leading to shrinkage in the tumor, which can further be managed using an immune system of a person.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Radio Surgery</strong> – Also known as stereotactic radiosurgery (SRS), this treatment involves giving a targeted and precise dose in the form of an X-ray radiation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Risk Factors</strong> &#8211; There is no definite reason behind brain tumors. It might be hereditary but in rare cases. The only risk factor associated with the brain tumor is radiation exposure.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Survival</strong> – The survival rate post the diagnosis also depends on a lot of factors but for malignant tumors of a primary type, the 5-year survival rate is even less than 35%.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">RRMCH is one the best hospitals in Bangalore and amongst the <a title="Best Neuro Hospital in India" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best Neuro hospitals in India</a>. Equipped with the latest in Medical Technology, it also offers the expertise of the best neurologist in Bangalore.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Health Tips For Women Above 40</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/health-tips-for-women-above-40/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 05:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health tips for women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=846</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As women age and surpass the middle age milestone called 40, even though age is just a number, practically the body does have to deal with certain issues that crop up as we enter this phase. So what can you do to keep your health in optimal condition? Here are few tips that might just &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/health-tips-for-women-above-40/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Health Tips For Women Above 40"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">As women age and surpass the middle age milestone called 40, even though age is just a number, practically the body does have to deal with certain issues that crop up as we enter this phase. So what can you do to keep your health in optimal condition? Here are few tips that might just help you out.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Health First</strong> – Many a times while keeping the family needs as a priority women forget to check on their health issues or ignore It most of the times. One needs to understand that only when one is healthy then only can they take care of their loved ones.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Health-Tips-For-Women-Above-40-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-847" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Health-Tips-For-Women-Above-40-1-1.jpg" alt="Health Tips For Women Above 40" width="702" height="336" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Body Check</strong> – If you haven’t done a <a title="Health Checkup packages in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/health-checkups/" target="_blank">medical checkup its time</a>. Once you hit 40 do it once every two to three years. Check for deficiencies in your body particularly Calcium, Vitamin D and B12. Vitamin D and Calcium are needed for strong bones and in your 40’s you require 1000mg of calcium and 400 to 800 UI of vitamin D every single day so either you have to switch to that sort of diet or go for supplements. The checks you need at this age include eye testing, BP test, Mole check, Mammogram, Glucose test Pap and pelvic test as well as thyroid. All these need to be done every 2 – 3 years approximately.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Exercise</strong> – Exercise is good for all but more so once you turn 40. You are aging and you need to exercise to stay fit. Kick start your day with strength training and see the change within 6 months. Just dedicate 30 minutes a day to it.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Diet Check</strong> – It’s time you revamp your diet and go for a balanced one which will help you cope with your deficiencies and keep your cholesterol levels under check. Having breakfast daily can help greatly against skipping it. A study reveals that over a period of time people who take good breakfast lose more weight than the ones who make breakfast their smallest meal. Get in a lot of protein as they are mood boosters and help you relieve yourself from poor memory, excessive thinking or depression.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Get good Sleep</strong> – Sleeping helps you reduce stress and hence a good sleep is important. Particularly women don’t care about it much and it ultimately takes a toll on their health. Also try to control your stress through meditation and yoga. This will help you stay fit physically and mentally.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Spend time with Girl Friends</strong> – Ya, you might be busy to the core but take out time to hangout with your girl buddies because it is found that women with socialization or hobby activities have less risk of heart disease or less blood pressure and diabetes issues.</p>
<p align="justify"><a title="Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> has got the <a title="Master Health Checkup in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/health-checkups/" target="_blank">best health checkup packages in Bangalore</a>. You can check out the pricing packages of 4 plans available for all employees and individuals.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fungal Infections &#8211; An Over View</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/fungal-infections-an-over-view/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 10:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysore road hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=645</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Fungal infections are very common part of our day to day lives. When our immune system is unable to handle the invasions of infection causing fungus, is when we get prone to the condition called fungal infection. There are usually two kinds of fungi that reside on human body. The helpful one and the harmful &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/fungal-infections-an-over-view/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Fungal Infections &#8211; An Over View"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Fungal infections are very common part of our day to day lives. When our immune system is unable to handle the invasions of infection causing fungus, is when we get prone to the condition called fungal infection. There are usually two kinds of fungi that reside on human body. The helpful one and the harmful one. The invasion of harmful fungi causes infections as they cannot be killed easily and can rebound as well.<a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Fungal-Infections-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignright wp-image-646 size-thumbnail" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Fungal-Infections-1-150x150.jpg" alt="Fungal Infections " width="150" height="150" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Fungal-Infections-1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Fungal-Infections-1-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><em>The most common types of fungal infections in humans include &#8211;</em></strong><br />
<em>Ringworm</em> &#8211; This infection is caused by a fungus that lives on dead tissues of skin, nails and hair. It is also responsible for causing athlete’s foot and jock itch but if it occurs on other parts of the body it is known as ringworm. Generally, doctors</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Jock itch</em> &#8211; A mildly contagious infection by nature, it is caused by fungus that breed in damp and warm regions of the body like groin, inner thighs and buttocks. It causes redness of skin accompanied by itching, chafing or burning. Doctors usually prescribe some topical anti-fungal ointments and advise patients to maintain proper body hygiene.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Athlete’s foot</em> &#8211; As the name suggests this infection is very common with sports people and athletes. The reason for it being so common with athletes is breeding environments like shoes, sports equipments, locker rooms, socks. Though it can happen to anyone as well. Athletes feet is also treated with topical anti-fungal oinments but some serious infections need oral medicinal intake as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Now, that we are aware of some of the common form of fungal infections let us run down some nutrients that can help us fight fungal infections and are commonly available.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Garlic</em> – Garlic does limit the growth of fungus called candida to a large extent as it is highly sensitive to particularly the purified extract of garlic called allyl alcohol that produced oxidative stress thus supressing the growth of it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Tea Tree Oil</em> – This oil is effective on candida and various other fungal isolates. It treats candida and paronychia infections effectively as well. The tea tree oil disrupts the yeast cell wall thus inhibiting its growth.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Another way of to protect yourself from the unhealthy fungus, maintaining good population of the healthy fungus particularly to avoid vaginal infections, in women. Yogurt and pro-biotics are a good source of friendly bacteria in the vagina or rectum. Even fructooligosaccharides, a form of sugar is known to boost the levels of the good bacteria in the body, so adding one teaspoon daily to your diet should help you a lot in proliferation of friendly bacteria.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Contact to <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">best hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
