<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Eat Indian Jujube &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/eat-indian-jujube/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 09:32:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance – Check Out Their Amazing Health Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eat-indian-jujube-in-abundance-check-out-their-amazing-health-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 09:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Indian Jujube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1228</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The winter has almost arrived, and with it has arrived the season of Indian Jujube, or as we call them locally BER. Not many are aware that they are also known as the Korean date or Chinese date or even Indian Date. A bite sized fruit, it is relished by many but very few of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eat-indian-jujube-in-abundance-check-out-their-amazing-health-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance – Check Out Their Amazing Health Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The winter has
almost arrived, and with it has arrived the season of Indian Jujube,
or as we call them locally BER.  Not many are aware that they are
also known as the Korean date or Chinese date or even Indian Date. 
</p>



<p>A bite sized fruit, it is relished by many but very few of us really know about its umpteen health benefits.   Here’s a run down some of them –</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-1024x678.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1229" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-300x199.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-768x509.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Rich Source of Vitamin C</strong> – Jujube’s are known to be
	loaded with vitamin C as well as antioxidents and we all know the
	role of Vitamin C in revitalizing our skin, building immunity as
	well as fighting free radicals. Just consuming around 100 gms of
	Jujube can give you 69 mg of Vitamin C. Hence, eating jujube could
	be a great way of getting vitamin C as our body is not capable of
	producing the same. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Bone
	Strength</strong> – Want strong bones? Eat Jujubes. Yes, you read that
	right. Jujubes are also power packed with calcium, iron as well as
	phosphorous thus helping in improving. Hence, it’s a tasty
	alternative for people with oesteoprosis and bone degrading.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Anxiety
	soother</strong> – This fruit is known to have a calming effect on the
	brain as well as the nervous system. Jujube as well as its oil
	extract is known have sedative effects and relax your body down by
	working on the hormonal levels. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Constipation
	Relief</strong> – Jujube is known to provide great relief to people
	suffering from chronic constipation. As per statistics over 20%
	Indians suffer from chronic constipation and still its not been on
	the list of concerns. As jujube’s are a rich source of fibre, they
	help in digestion and regulation of bowel movements. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Sleep
	Well</strong> – Jujubes are rich in antioxidant pythochemicals,
	sapnins, flavonoids and polysaccharides known to have sedative
	properties. Hence, it helps in sleeping well by calming the nerves.
	So, people if you are suffering from insomnia, try jujubes.
</li></ol>



<p>Well, as this fruit is rich in fibre as well, its also considered to aid people looking at weight loss.  Perhaps, its high time you make it an integral part of your fruit consumption or diet may be.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Top Medical College in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
