<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>A healthy mind in a healthy body &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/a-healthy-mind-in-a-healthy-body/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 10:09:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Swimming Can Reduce Mental Stress &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/swimming-can-reduce-mental-stress-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 09:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A healthy mind in a healthy body]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best psychiatrist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming Can Reduce Mental Stress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1046</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As per a new study swimming can help reduce symptoms of anxiety or depression. Mental Illness is not a taboo anymore as it used to be in the earlier times. Today mental health is being given as much importance as physical health not only worldwide but in India too. Due to the hectic lifestyles of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/swimming-can-reduce-mental-stress-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Swimming Can Reduce Mental Stress &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">As per a new study swimming can help reduce symptoms of anxiety or depression. Mental Illness is not a taboo anymore as it used to be in the earlier times. Today mental health is being given as much importance as physical health not only worldwide but in India too. Due to the hectic lifestyles of Indians with extensive workloads and deadlines to match, people suffer from a lot of stress and anxiety. It has already affected millions of people worldwide. Mental health foundation statistics say that in Britain one fifth of the adult population is known to be affected by Mental Health Issues.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Swimming-Can-Reduce-Mental-Stress.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1047" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Swimming-Can-Reduce-Mental-Stress.jpg" alt="Swimming Can Reduce Mental Stress" width="800" height="403" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Swimming-Can-Reduce-Mental-Stress.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Swimming-Can-Reduce-Mental-Stress-300x151.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Swimming-Can-Reduce-Mental-Stress-768x387.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While discussions are already rife around methods that could help in reducing symptoms of stress and anxiety, there are many different methods and ways coming to light for the same. This includes taking help of mental health professionals, following a proper balanced diet and even swimming. Apparently, an organisation call Swim England carried out a YouGov poll on around 1.4 million adults in UK, to find that Swimming did have a positive effect on their mental health. Almost half a million people of UK who swim and also have faced mental health issues have mentioned that swimming on a regular basis has shown a positive effect and reduced the number of visits they do to the mental health specialist. 43 percent said that swimming made them happy, while 26 percent of the swimmers said that they feel motivated and 15 of them said swimming helps them cope up with the stress that comes along in their daily lives.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As per the head of mental health activities, Hayley Jarvis, engaging into physical activities on a regular basis is good for the body. What the mind says shows the significance of exercising for physical as well as mental well-being. The more active you are physically, the lower are the levels of stress on a daily basis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This voting campaign was launched on the ‘<strong>World Mental Health Day</strong>’, as a part of the global initiative in celebrating mental health and creating awareness about reducing the taboo around the same.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As per Ian Cumming, chair of the Swimming and Health Commission in UK, swimming is a very useful activity for the body and research is a good proof of the same. Simply being in water works well for restoration of the body, particularly outdoor swimming. In UK due to the rising population experiencing stress and anxiety issues,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>The <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/department/psychiatry/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">department of Psychiatry</a> at <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</a> strives to achieve and follow “<strong>A healthy mind in a healthy body</strong>&#8216;. Our dedicated team</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
