<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>advanced ambulance services in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/advanced-ambulance-services-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 06:13:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 09:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1213</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market of heart conditions. As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers
in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports
in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus
reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market
of heart conditions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1214" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png 620w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits-300x179.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></figure>



<p> As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">cardiovascular</a> conditions increases significantly in women and lipid profile is a reliable marker to measure heart health.  He and his colleagues investigated around 193 menopausal women participants of the age group 47-55 from Finland, registered for the Estrogenic Regulation of Muscle Apoptosis (ERMA) study.  The study is co-authored by Dr Mathew Jergenson of Minnesota Medical School and University in Minneapolis. The reason behind conducting the study as per him was to explore if physical activity did have a role in cardiovascular risk factors.  </p>



<p>
He says “It is well known that physical activity has health
benefits, yet it is less clear to what extent physical activity
prevents negative changes in lipid profile while women are in their
menopausal transition.  The participants were monitored for physical
activity levels in leisure time, generally and specifically also,
using accelerometers and had to answer questions as well.</p>



<p>
Leisure is the time that is not related to routine daily work be it
housework or commuting and includes sport or recreation activities in
free time. 
</p>



<p>The
researchers found out that there was indeed a connection between more
activities during leisure time and lowering of cholesterol levels
particularly (LDL) as well as with high levels of cholesterol (HDL). 
Karvin reports that indeed the leisure time physical activities were
related to healthy lipid profiles. But, that does not mean that the
negative changes in lipid profile during menopause can be fully done
away with due to leisure time sports activities. 
</p>



<p>The author also said that leisure time physical activities will underscore the adverse atherogenic changes in the cardiovascular risk factors in middle aged women who are healthy. Hence, sport related activities in leisure are good.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is having <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/"><strong>Top most Physiotherapist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1209</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them. It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them.  It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of us know that a declining oral health could be an indication of other risky health conditions that can also affect the quality of life of a human being.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1210" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>An article published in the <a href="http://www.jisponline.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology (opens in a new tab)">Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology</a> shows that there is a link between tooth loss as well as gum disease with stroke occurrence.  </p>



<p>As
per the conclusions of this article of 2010, gum disease is
responsible for increase in the risk of heart attack by 20%. Well,
there’s another team at the University of New Brunswick, NJ are
focusing on a connection between oral health and cognitive decline. 
</p>



<p>Even
a research team from Rutgers University carried out a two separate
studies around perceived stress and cognitive decline and published
the reports of two separate studies in the Journal of American
Geriatrics Society.</p>



<p>Talking
about other parts of the world like for example China, XinQi Dong,
the director of Rutgers University’s Institute for Health,
healthcare policy and aging research says that in china it was the
ethnic and racial minorities who were typically vulnerable to
consequences of poor oral health.  The reason being that already
there are barriers like socio economic status and language plus
access to preventive dental care is less. Particularly, the old
Chinese Americans are at a risk of oral health problems because of
lack of regular dental checkup and dental insurance. These studies
were carried out on Chinese elderly in Chicago of 60 years and above
age. The study involved quizzing question around oral health and then
asking them to complete five cognitive tests.  The second study asked
people if they had faced issues like dry mouth besides measuring
their social strain levels, social support and perceived stress with
the help of pre-defined scales. 
</p>



<p>The study involved 2700 Chinese Americans and results revealed that around half of them did had symptoms of tooth related issues. Also, there was not significant relationship between congnitive issues and gums but researchers believe that the participants may not have reported gum problems and ignored them as they do not cause major problems to health.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a> is one of the <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/">best neuro hospital in india</a></strong> </p>



<p>know more about <a href="https://www.rrdch.org"><strong>Top Dental Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diverticulitis – Know More About The Stomach Condition</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diverticulitis-know-more-about-the-stomach-condition/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 09:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diverticulitis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1202</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A common condition of stomach that, many people are unaware of diverticulitis. It affects the large intestine or colon and occurs when the mucosa or muscous membrane forms small pouches bulging inside the gastrointestinal tract pushes out via a weak muscle area in the larger intestine. Though over 80% of the people suffering from divurticulitis &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diverticulitis-know-more-about-the-stomach-condition/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Diverticulitis – Know More About The Stomach Condition"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
common condition of stomach that, many people are unaware of
diverticulitis. It affects the large intestine or colon and occurs
when the mucosa or muscous membrane forms small pouches bulging
inside the gastrointestinal tract pushes out via a weak muscle area
in the larger intestine.  Though over 80% of the people suffering
from divurticulitis do not show any symptoms of it, some of them do
feel severe pain and need surgery. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Diverticulitis-–-Know-More-About-The-Stomach-Condition.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1203" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Diverticulitis-–-Know-More-About-The-Stomach-Condition.jpg 722w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Diverticulitis-–-Know-More-About-The-Stomach-Condition-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 722px) 100vw, 722px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Causes </strong>&#8211; Though
the primary cause of this condition is unknown, some of the risk
factors include obesity, smoking, red meat, high saturated fat and
low fibre diet. 
</p>



<p><strong>Symptoms</strong> &#8211; Though
symptoms vary depending upon the severity of the condition, people
experience symptoms like fever, bloating, nausea, vomiting, abdominal
pain, constipation, Vitamin D deficiency and genetics to name a few. 
</p>



<p><strong>Diagnosis</strong> &#8211; The
diagnosis depends on physical examination and a few tests including
urine and stool test, colonoscopy, MRI, CT scan or X ray of the GI
tract, to name a few. 
</p>



<p><strong>Complications</strong>: Generally
this condition does not have complication in over 75% of the cases
but in 25% of the cases there are chances of developing
complications.  The complications of divertulitis include – 
</p>



<p><strong>Abscess
</strong>– It is the formation of pus inside the diverticula 
</p>



<p><strong>Scarring
</strong>– This condition causes intestinal blockage</p>



<p><strong>Perforation
inside Intestine</strong> – This causes holes in the intestine and is a
severe condition that leads to leakage into the abdominal cavity</p>



<p><strong>Fistula</strong>
– In this condition, the infection spreads through other organs 
</p>



<p><strong>Phlegmon</strong>
– It’s the inflammation of the soft tissues under the skin</p>



<p><strong>Prevention</strong>– Eating foods that are rich in fibre are advisable in order to prevent the condition. These include Vegetables like Spinach, Peas, high-fibre fruits, ground Psyllium Seed, low fibre animal protiens like eggs and fish etc. Avoid foods like popcorn, fried foods, saturated fats, popcorn and refined grains.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Kmow more about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celiac Disease Detection Now Made Faster With Blood Test –AN Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/celiac-disease-detection-now-made-faster-with-blood-test-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 05:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1183</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As per All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Celiac disease is known to affect around 6 – 8 million people across India. Also known as gluten sensitive enteropathy or celiac sprue, Celiac disease is known to be an emerging health condition. Celiac disease is a disease where in there is sensitivity against gluten, a &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/celiac-disease-detection-now-made-faster-with-blood-test-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Celiac Disease Detection Now Made Faster With Blood Test –AN Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As per All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Celiac disease is known to affect around 6 – 8 million people across India. Also known as gluten sensitive enteropathy or celiac sprue, Celiac disease is known to be an emerging health condition. Celiac disease is a disease where in there is sensitivity against gluten, a protein that is found in wheat, rye and barley. It does not mean allergy to gluten or intolerance to it at all. It is an auto immune disorder that occurs in 1 in 1000 genetically disposed people. This disorder is not very common in Southern India but is prevalent in North and North eastern parts of India.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1184" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg 754w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test-300x212.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></figure>



<p>Now
coming to the detection of this condition. The present method used to
diagnose it consumes weeks or months. As the time taken to detect the
condition is prolonged, people with the condition have to bear with
the side effects of it.  With the blood test, this time could be
reduced to just a few hours.  Scientists who are working on the same
have been able to pick some of the biomarkers forming the blood test
basis. They have found that when people are exposed to gluten, there
is an increase inflammatory molecules in the blood stream that can
associate with the symptoms that are in common. 
</p>



<p>Known
to affect 1 percent of the population across the western world,
Celiac disease is a condition one has to live with. In India there is
limited awareness about celiac disease and there is a dire need for
awareness around the condition and its prevention as well. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Now-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1185" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Now-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg 480w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Now-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test-300x218.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /></figure>



<p>As per Dr Robert P Anderson, who is the Chief Scientific Officer at ImmusanT, it was the first time that their team has been able to describe the inflammatory reaction that the patients experience when they are exposed to gluten. He also stated that the findings could also help differentiate people who have similar symptoms but do not suffer from the condition and ensure that proper treatment pertaining to their condition is given to them.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p></p>



<p>Just know about the <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Midlife Stress Responsible For Alzheimer’s In Women</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/is-midlife-stress-responsible-for-alzheimers-in-women/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 07:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1193</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Though, the reason behind Alzheimer’s affecting women more than men is not clear, a research does bring to light the effects of stress on cognitive functions of the mind. Alzheimer’s is a common condition particularly in the elderly people and like the cause is unknown, there is no cure to for it. But, a research &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/is-midlife-stress-responsible-for-alzheimers-in-women/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Is Midlife Stress Responsible For Alzheimer’s In Women"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Though,
the reason behind Alzheimer’s affecting women more than men is not
clear, a research does bring to light the effects of stress on
cognitive functions of the mind. 
</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Is-Midlife-Stress-Responsible-For-Alzheimer’s-In-Women.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1194"/></figure></div>



<p>Alzheimer’s
is a common condition particularly in the elderly people and like the
cause is unknown, there is no cure to for it.  But, a research has
shed light on the stress aspect and its effect on the mind’s
cognitive functioning. 
</p>



<p>Past
researches around the effect of stress on women have stated that
there is a high impact on stress response of females and stress can
result into memory and cognitive problems, though of temporary
nature. 
</p>



<p>The
objective of the recent research conducted at the John Hopkins
University School of Medicine was to find out the relation between
stress and long-time decline in cognitive functioning.  Cynthia
Munro, PH.D and associate professor of Psychiatry and behavioral
sciences said that the stress hormones like cortisol increased when
there someone was under normal stress and then the levels returned to
the baseline. But if there was stress on a regular basis or if the
sensitivity to stress was high, there is a increased and sustained
responses in the hormones and the recovery is also delayed. It’s a
fact that an increase in stress hormones for a consistent basis then
it is not good for brain’s hippocampus – the seat of memory. 
</p>



<p>
The study included the data of
over 900 residents of Baltimore found that there was link that could
play a significant role in stating why women over 65 have more chance
of getting Alzheimer’s. 
</p>



<p>The findings of this study are already published in the International Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry.  The study began in the 1980’s and the participants had to take part in interviews as well as checkups over three times in a span of 1982 -2004. The first was in 1982, the second 1993-1996 and the last in 2003-2004. The participants were of around 47 years old on an average and over 63% were women.  </p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH Bangalore</strong></a></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Changes In Diet That Help You Reduce The Risk Of Cancer</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/changes-in-diet-that-help-you-reduce-the-risk-of-cancer/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1179</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As per statistics cancer is the causes the second highest number of deaths in India every year. Out of the 9.6 mn, over 8% are from India. Well, that’s not a small number. One of the most common cancers in India today is breast cancer. We all know that with all the innovations and advances &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/changes-in-diet-that-help-you-reduce-the-risk-of-cancer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Changes In Diet That Help You Reduce The Risk Of Cancer"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As
per statistics cancer is the causes the second highest number of
deaths in India every year.  Out of the 9.6 mn, over 8% are from
India. Well, that’s not a small number. One of the most common
cancers in India today is breast cancer. We all know that with all
the innovations and advances in Science, even today cancer does
affect the life expectancy negatively and also quality of life. So,
trying to prevent it seems a better idea. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1180" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer-300x160.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer-768x409.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>A
new study has revealed that the foods that are rich in flavonoids are
helpful in decreasing the risk of cancer and extending longevity. The
study was carried out over 50,000 participants across a span of 20
years. Finding out the impact of single compounds on health
conditions as well as mortality is not an easy study, even though
food does form the most important part of our lives.  
</p>



<p>Researchers
have already brought to light that eating vegetables and fruits
factually reduce the risk of cardiovascular conditions and increase
life span too. Though, the details on how they do it is under
research phase yet. Many researchers believe that it is rich in
flavonoids play a vital role in the same. 
</p>



<p>Flavonoids
are found in different natural food likes vegetables, dark
chocolates, fruits and tea are form a chemical class known as
polyphenols. These compounds are further divided into six sub classes
namely Flavonols, flavanones, flavan-3-ols, anthocyanins, flavones
and isoflavones.</p>



<p>A group of scientists from Edith Cowan University of Australia did begin a research in order to find out how the compounds could help increasing life span and help protect against health conditions. They also wanted to look into the effects of alcohol and smoking around the benefits of flavonoids. For investigation of the same, the scientists used the Danish Diet data of over 56048 adults across 23 years. During the process over 14083 participants passed away too. The researchers concluded that it was true that flavonoid rich diets with individual flavonoid subclasses do actually reduce the risk of cancer and cardiovascular diseases also increasing longevity.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/"><strong>Best Cancer Hospital Treatment in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>After 50 Alcohol Consumption Ain’t That Risky?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/after-50-alcohol-consumption-aint-that-risky/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 09:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[full health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1176</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Addiction to alcohol ain’t good for your health, is what we are all aware off. The consequences of the same include cancers of certain type, liver damage, and heart as well as brain disease too. Having said that there are studies about health benefits of drinking in limit as well. One such recent study has &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/after-50-alcohol-consumption-aint-that-risky/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "After 50 Alcohol Consumption Ain’t That Risky?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Addiction
to alcohol ain’t good for your health, is what we are all aware
off.  The consequences of the same include cancers of certain type,
liver damage, and heart as well as brain disease too.  Having said
that there are studies about health benefits of drinking in limit as
well. One such recent study has found that alcohol intake in
moderation does protect against mortality due to cardiovascular
diseases. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/After-50-Alcohol-Consumption-Ain’t-That-Risky.jpg" alt="After 50 Alcohol Consumption" class="wp-image-1177" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/After-50-Alcohol-Consumption-Ain’t-That-Risky.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/After-50-Alcohol-Consumption-Ain’t-That-Risky-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/After-50-Alcohol-Consumption-Ain’t-That-Risky-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
study published in Journal of Alcohol and Drugs and lead by a team of
Boston medical center in Massachusetts presents a fresh approach
towards the long going debate on whether moderate drinking is good
for health. 
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers, the studies carried out earlier were not
accurate enough. The reason was that the study included participants
of age above 50. The researchers argue that people who have passed
away before 50 due to alcohol consumption are not included in the
study. Hence, people who aren’t alive cannot participate in a
cohort study. 
</p>



<p>As
per Dr. Timothy Naimi, alcohol addicts who are alive at 50 could have
been healthy before and also could have been drinking within limits
also. The authors were of the opinion that around 40 percent of the
deaths due to alcohol intake were before the age of 50 years, meaning
the deaths due to alcohol intake are not taken into consideration at
all leading to ignoring the dangers of it. 
</p>



<p>The
analysis showed that age played a major role in the risk levels
associated with alcohol.  The rate of alcohol related deaths in
people between the age group of 20 – 49 was 35.8 percent.  They
also studied individual of age above 65 years.  The study did show
that over 35 percent of the deaths occurred due to alcohol intake but
they also found that around 80 percent of the deaths in this age
group. 
</p>



<p>They also found a vast difference when they took into consideration the age group of 20-49 years and the lost number of years. The number of years saved by drinking were around 14.5 percent only.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monsoon And Child Health Issues</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 05:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monsoon And Child Health Issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1173</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera, Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Monsoon And Child Health Issues"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Well,
everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you
hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on
your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along
health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera,
Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. Here’s
a run-down five of the most common illness viral/bacteria borne, that
you need to protect your child from – 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1174" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg 975w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-768x451.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Dengue</strong>
– Caused by the Aedes aegypti mosquito, Dengue mosquitos breed in
stagnant water be it flower pots, buckets, tree holes or drums etc.
The incubation period is four to seven days after being bitten. The
symptoms include high grade fever with decreasing platelet count as
well as rashes. To prevent dengue try to keep your body covered as
much as possible and use mosquito repellents. Citronella is a good
mosquito repellent plant. 
</p>



<p><strong>Diarrhoea</strong>
– This is one
condition that can be prevented with proper precautions as it is
caused because of unhygienic food and water consumption. The best way
to prevent it is to drink boiled water and eat home cooked food. Both
the types of diarrhea, chronic as well as acute can be managed
through appropriate and timely treatment. 
</p>



<p><strong>Typhoid
</strong><strong>– </strong>This is
another waterborne condition that is caused by S typhi bacteria. The
main reason is poor sanitation. The symptoms include weakness, pain,
fever as well as sore throat to name a few. This condition can also
be prevented by avoiding street food, keeping your hands clean and
keeping yourself hydrated with healthy fluids. 
</p>



<p><strong>Malaria
– </strong>This is also a
water borne condition that is caused due to the female anopheles
mosquito. This mosquito breeds in water logged areas and hence is a
common condition in monsoon. The symptoms include fever with chills
or shivering, body ache and weakness, etc. The best way to prevent
the cause of malaria is to keep surroundings clean especially water
tanks. 
</p>



<p style="text-align:left">Jaundice – Jaundice is also a water borne disease that could go serious if not treated properly.  This is again a result of consuming contaminated food and water. The symptoms of jaundice include yellow eyes and urine, weakness and liver dysfunction.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Second Hand Smoke Is Also Dangerous To Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/second-hand-smoke-is-also-dangerous-to-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 09:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second hand smoke]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1169</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We are aware how dangerous smoking is for health, but second hand smoke viz. the smoke that we inhale when someone else is smoking could be life threatening too. As per statistics second hand smoke is known to cause over 3000 deaths due to heart disease to non-smokers. Second hand smoke can be particularly harmful &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/second-hand-smoke-is-also-dangerous-to-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Second Hand Smoke Is Also Dangerous To Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
are aware how dangerous smoking is for health, but second hand smoke
viz. the smoke that we inhale when someone else is smoking could be
life threatening too. As per statistics second hand smoke is known to
cause over 3000 deaths due to heart disease to non-smokers. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1170" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health.jpg 948w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health-768x575.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>Second
hand smoke can be particularly harmful to children because their
lungs are still under development.   Many children inhale this
dangerous smoke at home if their parents or family members smoke,
primarily. Even parents who smoke outside risk their children to
harmful chemicals because of second hand smoke. 
</p>



<p>Also,
known as environmental tobacco smoke, the smoke that is breathed out
as well as the smoke that is released from pipes, cigars, burning
cigarettes, cigars or pipes contains around 4000 chemicals. Almost 50
of these chemicals are carcinogenic and are known to increase the
risk of cancer. 
</p>



<p>The
American Academy of pediatrics (AAP) did a research on third hand
smoke also. Third hand smoke is the smoke that is left behind in
areas where people smoke. Though people leave the place after
smoking, the harmful toxins remain for a while for example in bars,
upholstery, even child’s hair if the care taker smokes. 
</p>



<p>Well,
second hand smoke and third hand smoke both are harmful to adults,
children and even the unborn developing ones. Unborn and children are
at a higher risk. Children whose parents smoke cough more than
children generally do. They are at the risk of getting coughs and
colds, tooth decay, ear infections and respiratory problems. Children
suffering from asthma are particularly prone to second hand smoke as
it can lead to asthma attacks that to frequent and severe leading to
a rise in hospital visits. 
</p>



<p>Well, so if you think that only smoking is injuries to health, you are certainly not right, its also the people around the smokers that are at the risk inspite of being not guilty of smoking. Take care. Quit now.</p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Private Medical Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Encephalitis (CHAMKI Fever) The Deadly Fever That Has Killed Over 150 Children In Bihar And Jharkhand Already</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/encephalitis-chamki-fever-the-deadly-fever-that-has-killed-over-150-children-in-bihar-and-jharkhand-already/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 11:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood banks in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1145</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The news of around 150 children dead due to the chamki fever is already a topic of concern present day. The Supreme Court also has taken notice of this serious or grave situation and directed Center to immediately form a medical expert team for the treatment of children having AES. An inflammation of brain, encephalitis &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/encephalitis-chamki-fever-the-deadly-fever-that-has-killed-over-150-children-in-bihar-and-jharkhand-already/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Encephalitis (CHAMKI Fever) The Deadly Fever That Has Killed Over 150 Children In Bihar And Jharkhand Already"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The
news of around 150 children dead due to the chamki fever is already a
topic of concern present day. The Supreme Court also has taken notice
of this serious or grave situation and directed Center to immediately
form a medical expert team for the treatment of children having AES. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1146" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar.jpg 700w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar-300x172.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /></figure>



<p>An
inflammation of brain, encephalitis commonly known as chamki fever is
the inflammation of brain. It is caused by viral infection and
affects the nervous system. There are two main types of Encephalitis
namely Primary and Secondary. This fever usually occurs in kids and
youngsters below 15 years of age.   
</p>



<p>The
primary is caused due to direct viral infection to the brain while
secondary is a result of a weak immune system and can be a result of
infection in any part of the body.  Presently, there’s an outbreak
of this fever in Bihar and Jharkhand. Recently, even Bengal has
reported three cases of AES or Chamki of which one is critical.  
</p>



<p><strong>Causes
</strong>
</p>



<p>AES
is known to be a viral infection but can occur due to mosquito borne
viruses, Zika or Nipah Virus, Rabis virus, childhood infections,
enteroviruses and herpes virus as well. In India the most commonly
known AES causing virus is the Japanese Encephalitis (JE) as almost 5
-35% cases are that of JE Virus AES. Though, this year only two cases
are due to the JE Virus and exact cause of so many deaths is not
known. What is known is that the deaths were caused by hypoglycemia
(low blood sugar levels) 
</p>



<p>
<strong>Symptoms </strong>
</p>



<p>At
the initial stage the symptoms are similar to mild flu and include
fever, headache, fatigue, muscle or joint pain. Though in the later
or severe stage it leads to hallucinations, agitation, confusion,
muscle weakness, hearing difficulties paralysis, sensation loss,
vomiting, poor eating, body stiffness, skull bulging and more.    
</p>



<p><strong>Treatment
</strong>
</p>



<p>There
is not medicine yet for this fever and the mild one can be brought
down through adequate rest and continuous fluid intake. Drugs like
Tylenol, Aleve and Advil also can be used. Medications like Foscavir,
Cytoven and Zovirax can be used for the viral Encephalitis only on
prescription basis. Do not consume any medications with Doctors
consult. At times supportive care like breathing assistance,
intravenous fluids to keep the person hydrated, anti-convulsant and
anti-inflammatory drugs against seizures and swelling could be
required. 
</p>



<p><strong>Prevention
</strong>
</p>



<p>Prevention is always better and hence to avoid getting this condition try to maintain hygiene at home, clean your hands properly after you visit the toilet and before eating food. Also, drink clean water and use mosquito nets and repellants when sleeping.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about The  <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
