<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>best eye hospital in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/best-eye-hospital-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 06:22:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dark Spot on the sclera of eye? What is it!</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dark-spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-what-is-it/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 06:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser eye operations in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=878</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When there is any spot on the sclera, it is prominent because of the white background. Hence, it catches your notice mostly within no time of surfacing. So, if you are one of those who has recently discovered a spot on the white area of your eye or sclera as it is called, then here’s &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dark-spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-what-is-it/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dark Spot on the sclera of eye? What is it!"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">When there is any spot on the sclera, it is prominent because of the white background. Hence, it catches your notice mostly within no time of surfacing. So, if you are one of those who has recently discovered a spot on the white area of your eye or sclera as it is called, then here’s what you need to know about the same.<br />
Usually, these freckles or spots are harmless but if it has occurred suddenly out of the blue, then it’s advisable to consult an ophthalmologist because it could be a sign of something critical or cancer as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Dark-Spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-879" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Dark-Spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-1-1.jpg" alt="Dark Spot on the sclera of eye" width="600" height="451" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>SPOTS, TYPES AND CAUSES</strong><br />
These spots unlike moles are more of a lesion or nevus, mostly flat or may be slightly raised in either black, pink or brown color. Sometimes this nevus could be pigmentation free as well. This nevus could also occur in tissue beneath the retina and needs a special lamp to view.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also known as pigmented tumors, these spots or freckles are almost harmless. The most common of the eye tumors is Congenital nevi besides others like conjunctival melanoma and melanosis. Nevi is caused due pigmentation cells or over-growth of melanocytes. Most of the people who have nevi have it since their birth or it surfaces in their early childhood itself. Usually, the spot might not be noticeable until puberty because at this age it becomes bigger and darker too.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While primary acquired melanosis usually occurs in the middle to people with fair skin and suddenly too, the rarest form is the Conjunctival melanosis and it either occurs suddenly or as primary acquired melanosis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
As per the eye cancer network most eye pigmented lesions are benign in nature and practically harmless. But, the eye specialists need to monitor these lesions to check for any signs of shape change and growth. Particular attention needs to be paid on whether the lesion extends to the cornea or develops an increase in blood supply. As compared to malignant lesions the benign nevi grow at a slower rate. In case there is any change in the shape or size of the lesion the doctor might advise a biopsy but congenital nevi becoming cancerous is extremely rare even if it shows a change in shape or size.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, dark spots in the sclera are usually not a matter of grave concern but it’s always advisable that you consult your<a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank"> ophthalmologist</a> to get a clear idea of the lesion or nevi and further line of action.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cataract Surgery &#8211; What All You Need To Know?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cataract-surgery-what-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 08:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore eye hospital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cataract Surgery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lasik operations in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=868</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Though cataracts are a common amongst people over 65 years, they can happen in one or both even in the age group of 50 plus. Cataracts are common because they are only a result of aging process. Cataract causes the lens in our eye to become cloudy and results into vision loss inspite of wearing &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cataract-surgery-what-all-you-need-to-know/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Cataract Surgery &#8211; What All You Need To Know?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Though cataracts are a common amongst people over 65 years, they can happen in one or both even in the age group of 50 plus. Cataracts are common because they are only a result of aging process. Cataract causes the lens in our eye to become cloudy and results into vision loss inspite of wearing spectacles. This can happen in one eye or both as well. The cataract surgery is performed to remove the cloudy lens and replace it with an artificial lens known as intraocular lens in order to restore clarity in vision. It is a very simple and speedy surgery which requires just around 15-20 minutes of time. No overnight stay is required and the patient is discharged the same day within few hours of the surgery.</p>
<p align="justify">The cataract surgery performed these days is a very advanced one known a phacoemulsification or ‘phaco’ carried out using a high frequency ultrasound device that has the ability to break down the cloudy lens into pieces. These are then removed gently from the eye with the help of suction. ‘Phaco’ has greatly reduced the complications of eyes which the earlier surgeries had a risk part of it, besides the advantage of faster healing.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Cataract-Surgery-RRMCH-Bangalore-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-869" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Cataract-Surgery-RRMCH-Bangalore-1-1.jpg" alt="Cataract Surgery " width="500" height="362" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">The process typically includes the surgeon removing the cloudy lens from the eye and then inserting the intraocular lens and positioning is properly behind the pupil and iris exactly at the location of the natural lens. It very rare but sometimes in special cases the lens is placed in the front of the iris and pupil instead of the back. The procedure is concluded by closing the incision in the eye with a stitch or sometimes without it. In order to further protect the eye in the early stages of the surgery, a shield is placed over it as well.</p>
<p><strong>Cataract Surgery &#8211; After Care</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The eye drops provided by the doctor have to be used as per the doctor’s recommendation so as to avoid watering or itching.</li>
<li>Regular day to day activities can be performed as usual but some of them need to be restricted. Activities like reading, watching TV, walking and writing can be done but activities like lifting heavy loads, bending a lot and likes need to be restricted.</li>
<li>Do not perform strenuous exercises but light can do.</li>
<li>Wear your protective eye covering all the time even when sleeping. Do not sleep on the side of the operated eye.</li>
<li>Avoid water contact with the eyes during bath or shower.</li>
<li>Do not rub your eyes because it can cause infection.</li>
<li>Restrict yourself from swimming for atleast two weeks.</li>
<li>Do not drive for atleast 24 hours after surgery.</li>
<li>Avoid wearing any kind of eye makeup as well until your doctor permits.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>RRMCH one of the <strong><a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">best ophthalmology/eye hospitals in Bangalore</a></strong> for LASIK operations, Dr Vijay Kumar Srivastava eye specialist in bangalore</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eye Lid Surgery in India &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eye-lid-surgery-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 12:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=833</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As we age, it shows and one area that is show clearly is the region around the eyes. One of the prominent difference we see is in the upper eyelids, under eyes and eye brows, which tend to sag with age. Here is the good news, even if age causes the mentioned differences in eyes, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eye-lid-surgery-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Eye Lid Surgery in India &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">As we age, it shows and one area that is show clearly is the region around the eyes. One of the prominent difference we see is in the upper eyelids, under eyes and eye brows, which tend to sag with age. Here is the good news, even if age causes the mentioned differences in eyes, they can be corrected with a surgery called blepharoplasty. It is popularly known as eye lift and is done by women specifically for enhancement of their looks or appearance by fixing their droopy and dull eyelids. The surgery procedure involves removal of fat pockets and excess skin from upper and lower lids. Though, patients who already have ophthalmic issues are excluded from taking up this surgery.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-834 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-300x144.jpg" alt="Eye Lid Surgery in India" width="300" height="144" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-300x144.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-768x370.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1.jpg 889w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">This is a sort of cosmetic surgery done for alteration of eye aesthetics in a way. Here what kind of corrections it can do for your eyes.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>1. Dull or fatigued eyes</strong> – With this eyelift surgery the work on correcting eyes that make the person look older and tired than actually she is</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>2. Excess skin on upper eye lid</strong> &#8211; If you have excess skin on upper eye lid it can also obstruct your eyesight. So, this surgery helps in removing the excess skin or the fat pockets there that can obstruct the eyesight.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>3. Puffy Upper Eyelids</strong> – Sometimes puppy eyes are result of genetics than sleeplessness. Blepharoplasty surgery can fix this issue</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>NON INVASIVE OPTION</strong><br />
For some doctors might recommend the non-invasive procedure as compared to the invasive one. This is considered to be a more appropriate course of treatment as well compared to the invasive one. The non -invasive treatment involves usage of Botox injections for enhancing looks by reducing wrinkles. Even facial fillers are used in this treatment for the purpose of reducing the dark circles and eye bags.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>RESULTS</strong><br />
The results of the surgery are never instant. Primarily, you may see inflammation and swelling around the area where it is done and it would generally take a couple of days to a week to subside. Once the healing occurs best results are seen.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong><a title="medical colleges in bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> <a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">Ophthalmology(eye) department</a></strong> is registered under District Blindness Control Society and has a successful record of offering the best possible care for our patients. We conduct eye screening camps every month at Mudaliar Sangha, Rajajinagar in Bangalore. We also provide treatment free for patients who can’t afford to pay their daily bills. We provide services to about 100 patients every day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
