<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Depression and Anxiety &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/depression-and-anxiety/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 11:35:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Depression and Anxiety can be as Harmful to Health as Smoking</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/depression-and-anxiety-can-be-as-harmful-to-health-as-smoking/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 11:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Depression and Anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1068</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A recent study has revealed that people who have high anxiety levels as well as depression are at 65% higher risk of developing a heart condition, 64% at a higher risk of developing a stroke, 50% high risk of developing high blood pressure and 87% higher risk of developing arthritis. Comparatively, even people who smoke &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/depression-and-anxiety-can-be-as-harmful-to-health-as-smoking/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Depression and Anxiety can be as Harmful to Health as Smoking"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A recent study has revealed that people who have high anxiety levels as well as depression are at 65% higher risk of developing a heart condition, 64% at a higher risk of developing a stroke, 50% high risk of developing high blood pressure and 87% higher risk of developing arthritis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Comparatively, even people who smoke and are obese are at the same level of risk thus pointing out the importance of mental health condition with respect to physical health. The lead author Andrea Niles of the University of California San Francisco said that hence smoking and obesity as well as mental health conditions like depression and anxiety pose the same risk.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1069" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking.jpg" alt="Depression and Anxiety can be as Harmful to Health as Smoking" width="936" height="624" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking.jpg 936w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Yet, cancer is not included in the list of conditions that are a result of depression and anxiety. The co-author Aoife O Donovan from UCSF has said that the study is similar to the other studies in terms of the psychological distress being a strong predictor of many types of cancers. She also asked people not to attribute <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/">cancer diagnosis</a> to stress, depression and anxiety history.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Niles also said that the study was the first one that compared between anxiety and depression with smoking and obesity as potential risk factors for health conditions that could be life threatening.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In a nutshell, the study is only brings to light the fact that mental health is to be cared for equally and has the ability to do equal harm as addictions or unfit habits do. And that it is time that people shun away the taboo around mental health and habits and take a step to consult mental health practitioners if they are facing issues like depression, anxiety or more so that they can be treated not only for it but also to avoid their physical health being affected.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is of the <a href="http://college.rrmch.org/">best medical colleges in Bangalore</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
