<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>H1N1 Swine Flu in Bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/h1n1-swine-flu-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 05:21:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Swine Flu on the Prawl Again &#8211; Beware Bengaluru</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/swine-flu-on-the-prawl-again-beware-bengaluru/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 05:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H1N1 Swine Flu in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swine Flu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swine Flu in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symptoms of H1N1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1034</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[H1N1 has again begun to spread its wings across Karnataka. Over 207 case have been registered already across the state and a staggering 46 in Bengaluru itself in the past one week. Besides, there are reports of chikungunya and dengue too. The IT corridor of the state particularly the eastern region of the city is &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/swine-flu-on-the-prawl-again-beware-bengaluru/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Swine Flu on the Prawl Again &#8211; Beware Bengaluru"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">H1N1 has again begun to spread its wings across Karnataka. Over 207 case have been registered already across the state and a staggering 46 in Bengaluru itself in the past one week. Besides, there are reports of chikungunya and dengue too. The IT corridor of the state particularly the eastern region of the city is badly affected after September 29th, 2018.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As per the health officials, it is worrisome because, these many cases were last reported in 2015. The district surveillance officer clearly stated that the virus was presence in the city and people will low or not immunity are definitely at the risk of catching the life threatening condition.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1035" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Swine-Flu-H1N1-Flu.jpg" alt="Swine Flu - H1N1 Flu" width="835" height="547" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Swine-Flu-H1N1-Flu.jpg 835w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Swine-Flu-H1N1-Flu-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Swine-Flu-H1N1-Flu-768x503.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A pandemic now, this highly contagious respiratory disorder finds its roots in Mexico in 2009, spreading at a high intensity across the world. The condition is caused through the influenza A virus transmitted from pigs to humans. It can turn out to be a life threatening condition and hence requires great care.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>SYMPTOMS</strong><br />
The symptoms of H1N1 are very similar to that of flu –</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>Fever</li>
<li>Body aches</li>
<li>Sore Throat</li>
<li>Stuff or Runny nose</li>
<li>Cough</li>
<li>Chills</li>
<li>Fatigue</li>
<li>Headache</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Though the symptoms are similar to flu, it can cause serious problems like lung infection, breathing problems and pneumonia. It also has the ability to worsen the health of people suffering from diabetes or asthma. If you observe symptoms like dizziness, severe vomiting, breathing issues, pain in your stomach or sides or confusion, take immediate medical help.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DIAGNOSIS</strong><br />
Only a lab test can confirm the presence of H1N1. For the test, the doctor will use a swab to take samples from inside your nose and throat back. Not every is needs to undergo the test. Only the ones admitted to the hospital and at a high risk of developing the life threatening problems need to do it. These include</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>Children below the age of 5 years</li>
<li>Elders above 65</li>
<li>Under 18 teens and kids who have been using aspirin</li>
<li>Pregnant women</li>
<li>Children and Adults with a weak immune system and HIV infected people</li>
<li>People housed in nursing homes and care facilities from long</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
The antiviral drugs used for treating seasonal flue are used for treatment of H1N1 as well and include medicines like Oseltamivir (Tamiflu), Zanamivir (Relenza), Pearamivir (Rapivab). Some types of swine flu doesn’t respond to Oseltamivir. These drugs are effective and will help you get well soon. The only catch is that they need to be given within 48 hours of the symptoms. Though its not that they don’t work at all but the earlier the better.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Antibiotics won’t work here because it ain’t a bacterial infection, it’s viral. To relieve yourself from headache and body ache you may try over the counter medicines. Avoid giving aspiring to children under 18 because it could increase the risk of Reye’s syndrome. Also, do be careful to check that over the counter medicines you give do not have any content of aspirin.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>VACCINE</strong><br />
The vaccine for influenza and swine flu is the same. It’s available as spray or shot form and prepares your body to attack the real virus.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">RRMCH is one of <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Hospitals in Bangalore</a>. RRMCH have well experienced doctors. It works <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/24-hours-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24*7 for all emergency and health care services</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
