<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>karnataka medical college &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/karnataka-medical-college/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 06:35:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Monsoon And Child Health Issues</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 05:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monsoon And Child Health Issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1173</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera, Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Monsoon And Child Health Issues"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Well,
everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you
hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on
your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along
health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera,
Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. Here’s
a run-down five of the most common illness viral/bacteria borne, that
you need to protect your child from – 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1174" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg 975w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-768x451.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Dengue</strong>
– Caused by the Aedes aegypti mosquito, Dengue mosquitos breed in
stagnant water be it flower pots, buckets, tree holes or drums etc.
The incubation period is four to seven days after being bitten. The
symptoms include high grade fever with decreasing platelet count as
well as rashes. To prevent dengue try to keep your body covered as
much as possible and use mosquito repellents. Citronella is a good
mosquito repellent plant. 
</p>



<p><strong>Diarrhoea</strong>
– This is one
condition that can be prevented with proper precautions as it is
caused because of unhygienic food and water consumption. The best way
to prevent it is to drink boiled water and eat home cooked food. Both
the types of diarrhea, chronic as well as acute can be managed
through appropriate and timely treatment. 
</p>



<p><strong>Typhoid
</strong><strong>– </strong>This is
another waterborne condition that is caused by S typhi bacteria. The
main reason is poor sanitation. The symptoms include weakness, pain,
fever as well as sore throat to name a few. This condition can also
be prevented by avoiding street food, keeping your hands clean and
keeping yourself hydrated with healthy fluids. 
</p>



<p><strong>Malaria
– </strong>This is also a
water borne condition that is caused due to the female anopheles
mosquito. This mosquito breeds in water logged areas and hence is a
common condition in monsoon. The symptoms include fever with chills
or shivering, body ache and weakness, etc. The best way to prevent
the cause of malaria is to keep surroundings clean especially water
tanks. 
</p>



<p style="text-align:left">Jaundice – Jaundice is also a water borne disease that could go serious if not treated properly.  This is again a result of consuming contaminated food and water. The symptoms of jaundice include yellow eyes and urine, weakness and liver dysfunction.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Burnout – A Medical Condition Or Not?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/burnout-a-medical-condition-or-not/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 06:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Burnout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs admissions in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1117</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Do not misunderstand burnout to be a medical condition says WHO, that erroneously stated that it was a medical condition. The clarification comes as stating it as a “chronic workplace stress that hasn’t been managed successfully”. So, what is burnout exactly and what are the symptoms of this condition that has been termed as permanent &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/burnout-a-medical-condition-or-not/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Burnout – A Medical Condition Or Not?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Do not misunderstand burnout to be a medical condition says WHO, that erroneously stated that it was a medical condition. The clarification comes as stating it as a “chronic workplace stress that hasn’t been managed successfully”. So, what is burnout exactly and what are the symptoms of this condition that has been termed as permanent stress of work. Let’s explore –</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1118 aligncenter" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout.jpg" alt="Burnout" width="485" height="312" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout.jpg 485w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout-300x193.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 485px) 100vw, 485px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><b>Burnout – Definition, Symptoms and Causes</b></p>
<p align="justify">A state of being in permanent stress as a result of work is what Burnout means. It is more of a psychological problem rather than a physical issue. The symptoms usually include work anxiety, aggression and anger outbursts, detachment from work, feeling unworthy, aloofness, mood swings, insomnia, fatigue, stomach ache, appetite loss, breathlessness, headaches, chest pain, drug or alcohol addiction and lack of interest in the job, to name a few . It is a gradual process and not an out of the blue sorts. With time the symptoms worsen.</p>
<p align="justify"><b>Risk Factors</b></p>
<p align="justify">People who are workaholics and too much into their work tend to suffer from it and most of them are known to be high achievers at work and perfectionists. Their passion about work is so fueled that they even ignore the symptoms of Burnout.</p>
<p><b>Behavioral Indications </b></p>
<p>Burnout is definite to bring in some symptoms like withdrawal from responsibilities, coming late to office and leaving early, slowing down when it comes to work, to name a few. There is a visible difference between Burnout and Stress like stress is about losing energy while burnout is about losing motivation, hope and ideals. It causes anxiety while burnout causes depression and detachment. Stress leads to physical damage while burnout to emotional one.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_957" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-957" style="width: 422px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/medical-admission-mbbs-ms-md-phd/"><img class="wp-image-957 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/rrmch-logo-1.png" alt="RRMCH - Medical Admissions " width="422" height="101" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/rrmch-logo-1.png 422w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/rrmch-logo-1-300x72.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 422px) 100vw, 422px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-957" class="wp-caption-text">MBBS MS MD Admissions in 2019-20</figcaption></figure></p>
<p><b>Dealing with it</b></p>
<p align="justify">One of the most effective ways to deal with it is to speak to someone who is very dear or close to you and also is a good listener. This will help you calm down. Try spending quality time with your dear ones. Socialize a bit with the people you are working with, participate in activities in workplace. Indulge yourself into some hobby or outdoor activity or take a break from work. You could be at a phase where you might just have to consider quitting your job and taking a break before you begin again. Alternatively, joining a support community with cause can help you connect with like-minded people and help you de-tress on a regular basis. If nothing else seem to find you a way out it’s never too late to find new friends. With internet at your help finding friends is not a difficult task.</p>
<p align="justify">Know more about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH </a></strong></p>
<p align="justify">*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medicine As a Career in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forensic science colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio diagnosis course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=688</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Medicine As a Career in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices that are available around the medicine field apart from MBBS. So, students who aren’t able to crack the NEET can try to opt for some related courses that include BDS, Physiotherapy, Phsychiatry, Pharmacy and more. So, as per your area of interest you may choose a course. One major advantage of NEET being brought into effect is that intelligent students coming from lower income groups can try to get entry into medical without paying hefty donations to colleges.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-689 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg" alt="Medicine As a Career in India" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">In case you opt for <a title="MBBS Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/course/mbbs/" target="_blank">MBBS</a>, a masters is always a good idea considering future growth. You could either opt for a MD or MS. Though being a surgeon isnt a cake walk and invovles daily encounters with patients fighting for their lives. Its a great responshibility to shoulder and a time costing too.</p>
<p align="justify">As a surgeon or a masters degree holder you need to be available to your patients anytime. It could be in the wee hours of the night as well. So, its quite a stressful and hectic work schedule that you’ll have to manage. But, the perks include immense work satisfaction with successful medical procedures and blessing from families. If surgery is not your cup of tea then you might as well opt for MD in areas like radiology, anaesthesiology, paediatrics, forensic medicine and more.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, if not MBBS than the option of <a title="Physiotherapy Career in India" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/" target="_blank">Physiotherapy</a>, <a title="Dental College in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrdch.org/" target="_blank">BDS</a>, Ayurvedic medicine, Homeopathy, Veterinary and Pharmacy are definitely some of the good choices around medicine. A masters degree with these streams can offer rewarding career prospects.</p>
<p align="justify">Coming down to the bottom line, medical education does blow a hole into your pocket and for students coming from middle income and lower income groups, its not an easy way ahead. But, with the help of student loans, you may as well manage to realize your medical education dreams. Though, it is important to have indepth information on the student loan interest, payback procedure and time for repayment in detail, needs to be known particularly when you are planning to pursue higher education abroad.</p>
<p align="justify">Medical is undoubtedly a lucrative career but having said that it does come with its own cons which need to be considered before taking a plunge into it.</p>
<p align="justify">know about leading <a title="Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">medical colleges in Bangalore </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
