<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FORENSICON – 2015 &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/forensicon-2015/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 09:25:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>FORENSICON – 2015</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/forensicon-2015/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 09:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FORENSICON – 2015]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rrmch.org/blog/?p=294</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We are glad to inform that 23rd annual state conference and pre conference CME was organized by Department of Forensic Medicine and Toxicology, RRMCH in association with Karnataka Medicolegal Association under the title ‘FORENSICON 2015’ from 3rd to 5th December 2015. The pre conference CME was held on 3rd December 2015, with the theme “LEARNING &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/forensicon-2015/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "FORENSICON – 2015"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">We are glad to inform that 23rd annual state conference and pre conference CME was organized by Department of Forensic Medicine and Toxicology, RRMCH in association with Karnataka Medicolegal Association under the title ‘FORENSICON 2015’ from 3rd to 5th December 2015. The pre conference CME was held on 3rd December 2015, with the theme “LEARNING FROM MISTAKES”. 346 delegates registered for the CME. The CME was inaugurated by Shri N.C Srinivas, Principal District &amp; Session Judge Ramanagara as chief guest, along with Dr. T.S Shiva Shankar, Rtd. Prof and HOD, KIMS Hubbali as presiding officer. A series of guest lecturer: Dr. Shanta Kumar, Dr. V.G Nayak, Dr. Kantikar, Justice Anand and Dr Veera Nagi Reddy followed by the inaugural function. The guest lecture given by Dr. Shanta Kumar, Dean, GMC, Tutukudi Medical college received a great response for his fantastic lecture. Welcome dinner was arranged at Guhantara.</p>
<p align="justify">First day of conference was held on 4th December, begin with ATS Iyenger oration by Dr. Jayaprakash K on the topic Ethics in clinical practice followed by guest lecturers by Dr. Indrajit Khandekar and Dr. Tanuj Kanchan. Scientific sessions includes paper presentations by faculty and post graduate students. Interactions during the session were healthy and enriched with knowledge. Inauguration of conference was done by Hon’ble Shri Justice A.V Chandrashekar, Judge High court Karnataka, Administrative Judge for Ramanagara District and by Dr. L.Thirunavukkarasu Rtd. Prof &amp; HOD, BMRCI, Bengaluru. First day event ended with general body meeting of Karnataka Medicolegal Society. Banquet was arranged at Eagleton, Bidadi.</p>
<p align="justify">Second day of conference started with guest lecturers by Dr. Clifford Perara, Dr. Girish Chandra and Dr. S Venkat Raghava. Scientific sessions include 20 paper presentations and 29 poster presentations by faculty and post graduate students. Interactions during the session were healthy and enriched with knowledge. Events concluded by valedictory function with prize distribution for toppers in UG and PG, best paper and poster presentations under faculty and post graduates. The feedback was good regarding the events of all three days.</p>
<p align="justify">Download:<a href="http://college.rrmch.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2015/07/FORENSICON-BROCHURE-%E2%80%93-2015.pdf" target="_blank"> Brochure</a></p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://college.rrmch.org/gallery/forensicon-2015/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-295" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/FORENSICON-–-2015-1-1.jpg" alt="FORENSICON – 2015" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
