<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>top medical colleges in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/top-medical-colleges-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 06:05:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp – A Rare Pregnancy Rash</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/plaques-of-pregnancy-or-puppp-a-rare-pregnancy-rash/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 05:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obg specialist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaques of Pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1248</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know that pregnancy can bring along a lot of side effects also like fatigue, nausea, vomiting and more. But, one rare condition that only a few or say 1 in 160 women get are pregnancy PUPPPs. Though, it is known to be a common condition experienced by pregnant women, not all are aware &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/plaques-of-pregnancy-or-puppp-a-rare-pregnancy-rash/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp – A Rare Pregnancy Rash"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know that pregnancy can bring along a lot of side effects also
like fatigue, nausea, vomiting and more. But, one rare condition that
only a few or say 1 in 160 women get are pregnancy PUPPPs. Though, it
is known to be a common condition experienced by pregnant women, not
all are aware of it. Here’s and over view of Pruritic Urticarial
Papules or PUPPPS, also known as plaques or Pregnancy. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp.jpg" alt="Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp" class="wp-image-1249" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Though
as on day scientists and medical experts aren’t really sure of the
reason behind the surfacing of such itchy rashes in women during
pregnancy but believe that it could be due to excessive stretching of
skin in the months nearing to delivery. 
</p>



<p>Also,
there is no cure. The rashes tend to appear in the third semester and
disappear within 2 weeks post birthing. The rashes start mostly from
the stomach and spread across your thighs, legs, hands and neck area.
They look like red swollen patches and are extremely itchy. 
</p>



<p>Another
reason cited by experts around rash is the circulation of immune
fetal cells through the body. These cells spark an immune response
that in turn leads to the rash surfacing. The theory finds support in
the fact that the fetal cells do stay in the body for short time
after delivery. But, it’s not proved yet. 
</p>



<p>The
itching could get worse if you tend to scratch it. Better to avoid
scratching. In hotter regions the itching and pain is much worse and
proper care needs to be taken for relief. Here are a few tips around
relief from rashes 
</p>



<ol><li>

	Ice – Cool ice compresses
	can help relieve the itching. Wrap the ice compress in a cloth and
	apply few time during the day. 
	
	</li><li>

	Oatmeal – Oatmeal baths are
	known to be effective home remedy for may skin conditions including
	this one. 
	
	</li><li>

	Peppermint – Peppermint
	comes with menthol and it is known to have cooling effects. Use
	peppermint oil on the rashes or you might consume the prescribed
	quantity after consulting your doctor. 
	
	</li><li>

	Moisturiser –
	</li><li>

	Clove oil &#8211;  Clove oil is
	also known to have  cooling effects because it contains
	antimicrobials and antioxidants, phenol eugenol to be specific. 
	
</li></ol>



<p>
A study in 2017 revealed that
around 25 participants who applied petroleum jelly followed by clove
oil on rash prone areas show a reduction in symptoms compared to the
group that used on petroleum jelly.</p>



<p> Having said that, not every pregnant woman gets these itchy rashes but those who get could use the above tips for relief purpose because these rashes could get itchy to hell and frustrate you to the core. But, be calm, this will pass off and there is not known effects to the fetus due to their occurrence as yet.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Know more about  <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/"><strong>Best Gynecologist in Bangalore </strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Board Games Can Keep Cognitive Degradation At Bay – A Study</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/board-games-can-keep-cognitive-degradation-at-bay-a-study/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 06:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best psychiatrist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1242</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know that board games are a fun way to be engaged in play in doors particularly for kids. But, here’s some news. A new study carried out by the Researchers at Edinburgh university of United Kingdom reveals that board games could actually help Older Adults avert off their cognitive decline. The paper was &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/board-games-can-keep-cognitive-degradation-at-bay-a-study/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Board Games Can Keep Cognitive Degradation At Bay – A Study"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know that board games are a fun way to be engaged in play in
doors particularly for kids. But, here’s some news. A new study
carried out by the Researchers at Edinburgh university of United
Kingdom reveals that board games could actually help Older Adults
avert off their cognitive decline. The paper was authored by Drew
Altschul of School of philosophy, Pscychology and Language sciences
in association with Professor Deary, director of Edinburgh Lothian
Birth Cohorts and published in the Journals of Gerontology. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1243" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games-300x233.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games-768x598.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>FBHDTJ Still-life selection of board games (Monopoly, Chess, Cluedo, Scrabble) with playing cards and gambling chips</figcaption></figure>



<p>The
study was carried out on 1091 subjects born in the year 1936 for
assessment of their mental and cognitive capabilities.  The
researchers did the evaluation for cognitive functioning across ages
11, 70, 73, 79 with the help of 14 different standard cognitive
tests.</p>



<p>The
study included asking questions to participants in the age group of
70 and 76 about how many times across the week they indulged in board
games like bingo, chess, crosswords, cards, bingo and more .  The
researchers also took into account confounding factors like
education, early life cognitive function, activity levels, sex and
health issues to name a few, as a part of their analysis. 
</p>



<p>The
results unleashed that the people who were more into board games in
their later year’s post 70’s were better off maintaining their
cognitive functioning. Particularly those older adults who indulged
in analog games post 70’s showed relative less decline in cognitive
abilities across 11 and 70 years and also between the age of 70 and
79. 
</p>



<p>Altschul,
one of the study leads says “ these latest findings add to evidence
that being more engaged in activities during the life course might be
associated with better thinking skills in later life”. 
</p>



<p>While coauthor thinks that there is a possibility that there is an interpretation of results as push to start playing board games and avoid cognitive decline.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/"><strong>Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 10:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1231</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[No a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions. But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town, even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus. The &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>No
a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around
relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions.
But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and
global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town,
even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus.
</p>



<p>The
earlier studies primarily were carried out for a short period of time
and only have been able to identify  the links between mental health
as well as temperature but the research till date only involves short
time period and more focused on connection rather than causal
factors. Moreover, this findings have so far not yielded any
substantial conclusions. So, the researchers with this study are
hoping to get answers to their questions that are not answered as
yet. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1232" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png 860w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-300x160.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-768x411.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
researchers for their study has gathered data from various sources
including Californian emergency departments,  collecting data and
analyzing information from the data of mental health diagnosis visits
during the period of 2005 – 2016. 
</p>



<p>They
even mined for data around suicides in America during 1960 – 2016
period.  These information was based on statuses that were
individually self-reported.  After drilling the climatic temperature
in US down, the researchers managed to develop ‘’fine spatial and
temporal scales”.</p>



<p>From
the study the researchers concluded that the mental health outcomes
decrease as the temperatures cool and the increase mental health
issues with rise in temperatures. Statistically speaking they found
that there was a rise in 0.48% rise in mental health visits with a
rise in average monthly temperature of 1<sup>0</sup> F and even a
rise in suicides by 0.35%</p>



<p>In
short, the rise and drop in temperatures has a significant impact of
the mental health because the authors of the study also showed
stability in the estimates even when accounted for socio economic
status and air conditioning adoption. 
</p>



<p>As for suicide rate, it rises only if there is a rise in temperature amid the growing season because growing season is all about crop yields. If the temperature rises, the crop yield reduces and leads to financial issues that in turn increase the risk of suicides.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Horns Of The Dilemma – Dairy Good Or Bad For Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/horns-of-the-dilemma-dairy-good-or-bad-for-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 06:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1224</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Though fruits and veggies are known to be healthy options as far as food is concerned there are conflicting views over dairy products and even their consumption levels on a regular basis. Milk and milk products in plenty are a must for kids and adolescents as milk is a rich source of calcium. Though milk &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/horns-of-the-dilemma-dairy-good-or-bad-for-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Horns Of The Dilemma – Dairy Good Or Bad For Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Though
fruits and veggies are known to be healthy options as far as food is
concerned there are conflicting views over dairy products and even
their consumption levels on a regular basis.  Milk and milk products
in plenty are a must for kids and adolescents as milk is a rich
source of calcium.  Though milk is good, it comes under saturated
fats and hence for people on a diet skimmed milk is a better option. 
</p>



<p> As per global standards the average consumption is around 2 to 2.5 servings a day for children.  Organizations like USDA and <strong>National Institute of Health (NIH)</strong> dairy is a vital source of magnesium, phosphorous, Protein and Vitamin D. A deficiency in calcium could raise the risk of osteoporosis as bones become weak and brittle.  </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Horns-Of-The-Dilemma-–-Dairy-Good-Or-Bad-For-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Horns-Of-The-Dilemma-–-Dairy-Good-Or-Bad-For-Health.jpg 512w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Horns-Of-The-Dilemma-–-Dairy-Good-Or-Bad-For-Health-300x208.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px" /></figure></div>



<p>Having
said that there are conflicting views around consumption of dairy
products.  As per a systematic review as well as meta-analysis says
that increase in dairy consumption increases the risk of
osteoporosis. But, not all studies are included in the said analysis.
 
</p>



<p>Another
long term study of Sweden that included 61000 women and 45000 men
revealed a potential link between high milk consumption as well as
high rate of bone fractures.  Though a Japanese study carried out
over 94,980 people revealed that a rise in consumption of milk did
lower the mortality risk. 
</p>



<p>Even the <strong>American heart Institution (AHA)</strong> has said that saturated fats could lead to increase in cholesterol as well as heart disease. Hence, some full fat dairy products do not come in the list of heart healthy diet recommendations. Furthermore, the national lung and blood institute has advised people to limit their dairy intake and use low fat dairy in their diet.  </p>



<p>There
is an article with umpteen analyses as well as reviews that do not
believe that saturated fats cause heart disease. It also states that
the saturated fats could decrease the risk of diabetes that is linked
to obesity.</p>



<p> So, while there is conflict with studies to support, dairy could be a healthy option if taken in limit. It could be helpful for people suffering from type 2 diabetes.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a> is one of the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Best Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Much Fiber Intake For Prevention Of Diseases</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-much-fiber-intake-for-prevention-of-diseases/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 06:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best neurologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how much fiber intake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1221</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A new study revealed exactly how much fiber is required for keeping the chronic conditions as well as premature mortality at bay. The objective of the study is to set the guideline for consumption of fiber besides bringing to light information around the carbs responsible for protection against non-communicable diseases as well as curb weight &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-much-fiber-intake-for-prevention-of-diseases/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Much Fiber Intake For Prevention Of Diseases"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
new study revealed exactly how much fiber is required for keeping the
chronic conditions as well as premature mortality at bay.  The
objective of the study is to set the guideline for consumption of
fiber besides bringing to light information around the carbs
responsible for protection against non-communicable diseases as well
as curb weight gain. 
</p>



<p>The
author of the study namely Professor Jim Mann, of Otago University
New Zealand and the author of the paper Andrew Reynolds is a
postdoctoral research fellow at Otago’s Dunedin School of Medicine.

</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1222" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases.jpg 678w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 678px) 100vw, 678px" /></figure>



<p>The
study was carried out by Reynolds and colleagues by examination of a
data that had 185 observational studies that included 135 million
person-years besides 58 clinical trials that involved the
participation of 4600 people.  The study analysis was carried across
40 years. 
</p>



<p>As
per prof. Mann, the motivation behind this study was analysis of
previous reviews and meta-analysis.  The scientists studied chronic
condition incidences as well as premature deaths resulting from them.
 The conditions included cardiovascular diseases, stroke, colon
cancer, type 2 diabetes, cancers such as esophageal cancer,
endometrial cancer, prostate cancer to name a few. 
</p>



<p>The
results of the study revealed that people who consume more fiber
daily are      15-30% less prone to premature deaths or any of the
aforementioned conditions. It also determined that daily consumption
of 25 -29 gms of fibre is good for health. Though consumption of more
than 29 gms of fibre could be even more beneficial. 
</p>



<p>Having
said that, the authors cleared that the study did not present any
side effects of fibre consumption but too much fibre could also be
harmful particularly for people with iron and mineral deficiencies.
Even consumption of whole grains in excess can lead to iron
deficiency as per researchers. 
</p>



<p>Lastly,
the study also found that consumption of high amount of fibre results
does relate to less weight and cholesterol levels. 
</p>



<p> Prof. Mann says “ Health benefits of fiber are supported by over 100 years of research into its chemistry, physical properties, physiology and effects on metabolism.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital, Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 09:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1213</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market of heart conditions. As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers
in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports
in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus
reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market
of heart conditions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1214" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png 620w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits-300x179.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></figure>



<p> As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">cardiovascular</a> conditions increases significantly in women and lipid profile is a reliable marker to measure heart health.  He and his colleagues investigated around 193 menopausal women participants of the age group 47-55 from Finland, registered for the Estrogenic Regulation of Muscle Apoptosis (ERMA) study.  The study is co-authored by Dr Mathew Jergenson of Minnesota Medical School and University in Minneapolis. The reason behind conducting the study as per him was to explore if physical activity did have a role in cardiovascular risk factors.  </p>



<p>
He says “It is well known that physical activity has health
benefits, yet it is less clear to what extent physical activity
prevents negative changes in lipid profile while women are in their
menopausal transition.  The participants were monitored for physical
activity levels in leisure time, generally and specifically also,
using accelerometers and had to answer questions as well.</p>



<p>
Leisure is the time that is not related to routine daily work be it
housework or commuting and includes sport or recreation activities in
free time. 
</p>



<p>The
researchers found out that there was indeed a connection between more
activities during leisure time and lowering of cholesterol levels
particularly (LDL) as well as with high levels of cholesterol (HDL). 
Karvin reports that indeed the leisure time physical activities were
related to healthy lipid profiles. But, that does not mean that the
negative changes in lipid profile during menopause can be fully done
away with due to leisure time sports activities. 
</p>



<p>The author also said that leisure time physical activities will underscore the adverse atherogenic changes in the cardiovascular risk factors in middle aged women who are healthy. Hence, sport related activities in leisure are good.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is having <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/"><strong>Top most Physiotherapist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1209</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them. It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them.  It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of us know that a declining oral health could be an indication of other risky health conditions that can also affect the quality of life of a human being.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1210" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>An article published in the <a href="http://www.jisponline.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology (opens in a new tab)">Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology</a> shows that there is a link between tooth loss as well as gum disease with stroke occurrence.  </p>



<p>As
per the conclusions of this article of 2010, gum disease is
responsible for increase in the risk of heart attack by 20%. Well,
there’s another team at the University of New Brunswick, NJ are
focusing on a connection between oral health and cognitive decline. 
</p>



<p>Even
a research team from Rutgers University carried out a two separate
studies around perceived stress and cognitive decline and published
the reports of two separate studies in the Journal of American
Geriatrics Society.</p>



<p>Talking
about other parts of the world like for example China, XinQi Dong,
the director of Rutgers University’s Institute for Health,
healthcare policy and aging research says that in china it was the
ethnic and racial minorities who were typically vulnerable to
consequences of poor oral health.  The reason being that already
there are barriers like socio economic status and language plus
access to preventive dental care is less. Particularly, the old
Chinese Americans are at a risk of oral health problems because of
lack of regular dental checkup and dental insurance. These studies
were carried out on Chinese elderly in Chicago of 60 years and above
age. The study involved quizzing question around oral health and then
asking them to complete five cognitive tests.  The second study asked
people if they had faced issues like dry mouth besides measuring
their social strain levels, social support and perceived stress with
the help of pre-defined scales. 
</p>



<p>The study involved 2700 Chinese Americans and results revealed that around half of them did had symptoms of tooth related issues. Also, there was not significant relationship between congnitive issues and gums but researchers believe that the participants may not have reported gum problems and ignored them as they do not cause major problems to health.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a> is one of the <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/">best neuro hospital in india</a></strong> </p>



<p>know more about <a href="https://www.rrdch.org"><strong>Top Dental Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Genetic Components Related To Left Handedness – A Study</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetic-components-related-to-left-handedness-a-study/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best neurologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1205</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A recent study by scientists reveals about regions of the Human DNA and their association with left handedness. These regions are connected to the brains language related features. An earlier study around handedness had revealed that genes were responsible for 25% of it but the type or name of the genes was unknown. In India &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetic-components-related-to-left-handedness-a-study/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Genetic Components Related To Left Handedness – A Study"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
recent study by scientists reveals about regions of the Human DNA and
their association with left handedness. These regions are connected
to the brains language related features. An earlier study around
handedness had revealed that genes were responsible for 25% of it but
the type or name of the genes was unknown. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Genetic-Components-Related-To-Left-Handedness.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1206" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Genetic-Components-Related-To-Left-Handedness.jpg 685w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Genetic-Components-Related-To-Left-Handedness-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 685px) 100vw, 685px" /></figure>



<p>In
India and across the world there were has been a lot of stigma and
taboo around being left handed. But, today rarely anyone is of the
belief or even discriminates between left and right handed people. 
</p>



<p>10%
of the population in the world is known to be left handed and also
includes many well-known individuals like Alert Einstein and Leonardo
da Vinci amongst them.  
</p>



<p>The
recent study was published in the journal ‘Brain’ and involved
the participation of 40,000 people including 38000 left handed ones.
After doing the genetic analysis, the researchers found that it was
the DNA regions that linked to left handedness strongly.  
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers the three regions are inside or are responsible
for protein code of brain development and patterning.  Proteins play
a significant role in making microtubules which are scaffolding like
building block and are responsible for guiding cell construction. 
</p>



<p>Microtubules
are made up of long chained molecules making up the physical
structure of the cells throughout the body also known as cytoskeleton
and have the ability to respond to cell singals by quickly assembling
and disassembling. 
</p>



<p>The
scientists did study brain scan details of 9000 participants after
analyzing their DNA samples.  The findings indicate that in left
handed people right and left side for brain that deals with language
coordinate in a better way compared to right handed ones. These
findings thus pave the path for getting deeper into finding if left
handed people are better in tasks that involve verbal communication
compared to the right handed ones. 
</p>



<p>Well, as per Gwenaelle Dououad, associate professor at the Wellcome Centre for Integrative Neuroimaging that it was apparently for the first time that they had been able to establish that in humans the handedness is linked to cytoskeletal differences in the brain.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Know more about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diverticulitis – Know More About The Stomach Condition</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diverticulitis-know-more-about-the-stomach-condition/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 09:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diverticulitis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1202</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A common condition of stomach that, many people are unaware of diverticulitis. It affects the large intestine or colon and occurs when the mucosa or muscous membrane forms small pouches bulging inside the gastrointestinal tract pushes out via a weak muscle area in the larger intestine. Though over 80% of the people suffering from divurticulitis &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diverticulitis-know-more-about-the-stomach-condition/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Diverticulitis – Know More About The Stomach Condition"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
common condition of stomach that, many people are unaware of
diverticulitis. It affects the large intestine or colon and occurs
when the mucosa or muscous membrane forms small pouches bulging
inside the gastrointestinal tract pushes out via a weak muscle area
in the larger intestine.  Though over 80% of the people suffering
from divurticulitis do not show any symptoms of it, some of them do
feel severe pain and need surgery. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Diverticulitis-–-Know-More-About-The-Stomach-Condition.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1203" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Diverticulitis-–-Know-More-About-The-Stomach-Condition.jpg 722w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Diverticulitis-–-Know-More-About-The-Stomach-Condition-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 722px) 100vw, 722px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Causes </strong>&#8211; Though
the primary cause of this condition is unknown, some of the risk
factors include obesity, smoking, red meat, high saturated fat and
low fibre diet. 
</p>



<p><strong>Symptoms</strong> &#8211; Though
symptoms vary depending upon the severity of the condition, people
experience symptoms like fever, bloating, nausea, vomiting, abdominal
pain, constipation, Vitamin D deficiency and genetics to name a few. 
</p>



<p><strong>Diagnosis</strong> &#8211; The
diagnosis depends on physical examination and a few tests including
urine and stool test, colonoscopy, MRI, CT scan or X ray of the GI
tract, to name a few. 
</p>



<p><strong>Complications</strong>: Generally
this condition does not have complication in over 75% of the cases
but in 25% of the cases there are chances of developing
complications.  The complications of divertulitis include – 
</p>



<p><strong>Abscess
</strong>– It is the formation of pus inside the diverticula 
</p>



<p><strong>Scarring
</strong>– This condition causes intestinal blockage</p>



<p><strong>Perforation
inside Intestine</strong> – This causes holes in the intestine and is a
severe condition that leads to leakage into the abdominal cavity</p>



<p><strong>Fistula</strong>
– In this condition, the infection spreads through other organs 
</p>



<p><strong>Phlegmon</strong>
– It’s the inflammation of the soft tissues under the skin</p>



<p><strong>Prevention</strong>– Eating foods that are rich in fibre are advisable in order to prevent the condition. These include Vegetables like Spinach, Peas, high-fibre fruits, ground Psyllium Seed, low fibre animal protiens like eggs and fish etc. Avoid foods like popcorn, fried foods, saturated fats, popcorn and refined grains.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Kmow more about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Blood Test That Predicts How Long You Would Live</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/a-blood-test-that-predicts-how-long-you-would-live/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 10:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1196</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Even today with all the advancement in science and technology, doctors are not able to predict how long a person would live, well in advance. Probably the can predict it with some accuracy within a year of his/her death but not as early as 5-10 years. A recent study published in the journal Nature Communications &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/a-blood-test-that-predicts-how-long-you-would-live/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A Blood Test That Predicts How Long You Would Live"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Even
today with all the advancement in science and technology, doctors are
not able to predict how long a person would live, well in advance.
Probably the can predict it with some accuracy within a year of
his/her death but not as early as 5-10 years. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/A-Blood-Test-That-Predicts-How-Long-You-Would-Live.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1197" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/A-Blood-Test-That-Predicts-How-Long-You-Would-Live.jpg 636w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/A-Blood-Test-That-Predicts-How-Long-You-Would-Live-300x180.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></figure>



<p>A
recent study published in the journal Nature Communications the
researchers are in the process of developing a reliable predictive
tool that could pave the path towards predicting life span of a
person as early as 5-10 years before time.  As per the researchers
this would help the doctors design the course of treatment and take
important decisions related to them.  Like for example doctors could
be able to identify between patients in need of medicine or surgery
and also help scientists in monitoring the impact of intervention on
mortality risk that so without running clinical trials.</p>



<p>Presently,
doctors are able to have a fair idea about the general life span of
people through their cholesterol and blood pressure levels. Through
this study the researching scientists from Leiden University Medical
Center of Netherlands as well as Brunel University London researched
around identification of biomarkers for managing the same. 
</p>



<p>The study included 44, 168 participants between the age group of 10 -109 years of which 5512 passed away. The study began by creating mortality metabolic marker followed by  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <strong><a href="https://college.rrmch.org/">Medical Colleges in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
