<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>eye treatment in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/eye-treatment-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best dermatologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1238</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Also known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and obesity. Many a times your skin shows you the symptoms and &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Also
known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do
not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a
very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and
obesity. 
</p>



<p>Many
a times your skin shows you the symptoms and it is preventable if you
exercise and maintain normal weight. As per reports around 90% of
cases of diabetes are apparently preventable if measures are taken on
time. Furthermore, if diabetes type 2 is left untreated then it could
also lead to life threatening health complications like heart attack,
kidney failure and strokes. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1239" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg 825w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>So,
why are the warning signs not taken seriously, is one question that
haunts many. The reason could be as simple as not taking them as
signs but simple health issues that could fade away with time or just
taking notice and delaying checkup till it’s forgotten. 
</p>



<p>Well,
let us run down some of the signs that could help you alert around
type 2 diabetes. 
</p>



<ol><li>

	 <strong>Frequent Washroom trips</strong>
	– high blood sugar means kidneys work hard to remove the excess
	sugar form the blood and hence it is considered to be an alarm for
	diabetes if one has to frequently wake up to go to pee. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Frequent urge to drink
	water</strong> – Due to frequent urination, even the urge to drink
	water increases due to dehydration
	</li><li>

	Fatigue – The energy levels
	of type 2 diabetes people are low due to deficiency of sugar through
	the blood stream to the body cells. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Hunger pangs</strong> – Due
	to lack of energy people suffering from type 2 diabetes tend to feel
	hungry on a constant basis even if they’d have eaten recently
	enough
	</li><li>

	<strong>Blurry Vision </strong>– At
	times high sugar could damage vision and result into blurred vision
	in one or both the eyes
	</li><li>

	<strong>Yeast Infections </strong>–
	Excess sugar in body could lead to yeast infection. The affected
	areas could get red, sore or itchy. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Tingling and Numbness</strong>
	– Due to rise in sugar levels people with this condition could
	experience tingling and numbess in their hands and feet. Known as
	neuropathy this condition has chances of worsening with time and
	hence early intervention is required.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Skin Darkening</strong> – For
	people suffering from diabetes, dark, velvety and soft patches
	appear on skin anywhere around the armpits, groin or neck. 
	
</li></ol>



<p> Perhaps, its not that difficult to be alarmed if we only pay attention at the signs. Early intervention could help deal with diabetes in a better way and also keep other life threatening conditions at bay.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eye Lid Surgery in India &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eye-lid-surgery-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 12:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=833</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As we age, it shows and one area that is show clearly is the region around the eyes. One of the prominent difference we see is in the upper eyelids, under eyes and eye brows, which tend to sag with age. Here is the good news, even if age causes the mentioned differences in eyes, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eye-lid-surgery-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Eye Lid Surgery in India &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">As we age, it shows and one area that is show clearly is the region around the eyes. One of the prominent difference we see is in the upper eyelids, under eyes and eye brows, which tend to sag with age. Here is the good news, even if age causes the mentioned differences in eyes, they can be corrected with a surgery called blepharoplasty. It is popularly known as eye lift and is done by women specifically for enhancement of their looks or appearance by fixing their droopy and dull eyelids. The surgery procedure involves removal of fat pockets and excess skin from upper and lower lids. Though, patients who already have ophthalmic issues are excluded from taking up this surgery.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-834 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-300x144.jpg" alt="Eye Lid Surgery in India" width="300" height="144" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-300x144.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-768x370.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1.jpg 889w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">This is a sort of cosmetic surgery done for alteration of eye aesthetics in a way. Here what kind of corrections it can do for your eyes.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>1. Dull or fatigued eyes</strong> – With this eyelift surgery the work on correcting eyes that make the person look older and tired than actually she is</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>2. Excess skin on upper eye lid</strong> &#8211; If you have excess skin on upper eye lid it can also obstruct your eyesight. So, this surgery helps in removing the excess skin or the fat pockets there that can obstruct the eyesight.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>3. Puffy Upper Eyelids</strong> – Sometimes puppy eyes are result of genetics than sleeplessness. Blepharoplasty surgery can fix this issue</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>NON INVASIVE OPTION</strong><br />
For some doctors might recommend the non-invasive procedure as compared to the invasive one. This is considered to be a more appropriate course of treatment as well compared to the invasive one. The non -invasive treatment involves usage of Botox injections for enhancing looks by reducing wrinkles. Even facial fillers are used in this treatment for the purpose of reducing the dark circles and eye bags.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>RESULTS</strong><br />
The results of the surgery are never instant. Primarily, you may see inflammation and swelling around the area where it is done and it would generally take a couple of days to a week to subside. Once the healing occurs best results are seen.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong><a title="medical colleges in bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> <a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">Ophthalmology(eye) department</a></strong> is registered under District Blindness Control Society and has a successful record of offering the best possible care for our patients. We conduct eye screening camps every month at Mudaliar Sangha, Rajajinagar in Bangalore. We also provide treatment free for patients who can’t afford to pay their daily bills. We provide services to about 100 patients every day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
