<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Nose and Emotions &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/nose-and-emotions/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 09:40:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Nose and Emotions &#8211; The Inter Relationship</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/nose-and-emotions-the-inter-relationship/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 09:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best ent hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ent hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ent hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nose and Emotions]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=724</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Now, here is some news related to the ability to expressing emotions. A study has found that the rare condition experience by 10% of the healthy population called alexithymia leads to difficulty in understanding emotions, talking or relating to them or even expressing them. The researching scientists adopted a completely untested approach of study which &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/nose-and-emotions-the-inter-relationship/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Nose and Emotions &#8211; The Inter Relationship"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Nose-and-Emotions-The-Inter-Relationship-1-1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-727" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Nose-and-Emotions-The-Inter-Relationship-1-1.png" alt="Nose and Emotions - The Inter Relationship" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Now, here is some news related to the ability to expressing emotions. A study has found that the rare condition experience by 10% of the healthy population called alexithymia leads to difficulty in understanding emotions, talking or relating to them or even expressing them.</p>
<p align="justify">The researching scientists adopted a completely untested approach of study which included testing 62 individuals divided into categories based of severity of alexithymia as low, medium and high. The testing was known as olfactory tests and were carried out to find out their reactions on different kinds of stimulation.</p>
<p align="justify">The scientists were also explained the reason behind using the olfactory test’s suitability in studying this psychological conditions. According to them, between the areas in the brain there is a partial develop that deals with olfactory perception besides with those that are into processing emotions.</p>
<p align="justify">One of the important finding of the test were that scientists found the alexithymic patients react differently than others when it comes to smells. Apparently, its a result of their psychological parameters like accelarated heart rate or electrical skin conductivity. Additionally, the scientists also observed difference in reactions in subjects suffering from affective alexithymia and effective alexithymia wherein the areas of imagination, sensation and creativity are restricted compared to subjects with congnitive alexithymia, wherein identification, expression and distinguishing ability is compromised.</p>
<p align="justify">The results clearly stated that altered psychological response to olfactory stimuli is one of the characteristics of alexithymia. The test also brought to light an interesting fact that The psychological reactions of individuals suffering from alexithymic conditions to smell induced emotions are apparently more intense, contradicting general expectations on the same.</p>
<p align="justify">A significant observation as it may be and counter intuitive too, subjects with alexithymia become insensitive to difference, changes or color shades that are said to enrich our routine lives scientifically due to the situation of extreme perpetual activation with respect to emotions, they are said to be in.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, now you know how nose and emotions are interconnected or interdependent for that matter.</p>
<p align="justify">Know more about <a title="ENT Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ent/" target="_blank">ENT Hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
<p align="justify">
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
