<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Food Poisoning &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/food-poisoning/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 04:43:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What is Food Poisoning? An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/what-is-food-poisoning-and-more/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Poisoning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=916</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Recently, there was news of over 100 prisoners in Delhi falling sick suddenly and being admitted to the hospital. The reason cited for the same is either food poisoning, drug poisoning or contaminated water. Food poisoning is a common term and you hear people and kids suffering from it every now and then. It is &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/what-is-food-poisoning-and-more/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "What is Food Poisoning? An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Recently, there was news of over 100 prisoners in Delhi falling sick suddenly and being admitted to the hospital. The reason cited for the same is either food poisoning, drug poisoning or contaminated water. Food poisoning is a common term and you hear people and kids suffering from it every now and then. It is a very uncomfortable condition that leads to nausea, vomiting or diarrhea and is caused due to the intake of toxic, contaminated or spoiled food.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
Food poisoning can either be caused by bacteria, viruses or parasites. The most common though is through bacteria like Listeria, E coli and salmonella. The latter is said to be the biggest cause of serious food poisoning cases. Another rare or lethal bacteria responsible for food poisoning includes the C. botulism and Campylobacter. Norovirus is a virus type which can also lead to food poisoning but is not fatal mostly. Others include Rotavirus, Astrovirus, Sapovirus and Hepatitis A, wherein the latter can be serious. Toxoplasma is a parasite which causes food poisoning. Parasites live within your digestive tract but can go undetected for years.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-1-Main-blog-image-550x410-1-1.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-942 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410-1.png" alt="Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410" width="550" height="410" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410-1.png 550w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410-1-300x224.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong><br />
Usually, food poisoning is detectable based on the symptoms. The symptoms differ as per the infection source. The symptoms appear anytime within 1 hour or 28 days depending on the infection source again. Most people suffering from food poisoning show atleast three of the following symptoms.</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Headache</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Weakness</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Nausea</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Mild fever</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Loss of appetite</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Diarrhea</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Abdominal cramps</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Food poisoning ain&#8217;t life-threatening. But, this does not mean that you take the condition lightly. There is always a rare possibility of it getting life-threatening as well. Look out for the following symptoms and initiate immediate medical assistance &#8211;</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Fever of 105 or higher</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Severe dehydration, dry mouth, no urine passage</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Difficulty speaking or seeing</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Diarrhea that does not go for 3 or more days</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Blood in urine</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
Food poisoning generally does not require any treatment and can easily be managed at home. It can take three to five days to subside but the most important part is to stay hydrated all along. Consumption of Sports drink that has electrolyte in them works really well in dealing with the condition. To help yourself out of fatigue try natural drinks like coconut water and fruit juice.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Know about <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best Hospitals in Bangalore</a>, Karnataka.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
