<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>How Do Deal With The Headache Called Dandruff &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/how-do-deal-with-the-headache-called-dandruff/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 10:41:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How Do Deal With The Headache Called Dandruff</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-do-deal-with-the-headache-called-dandruff/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 10:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How Do Deal With The Headache Called Dandruff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=717</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Dandruff is a common condition amongst us and yes it is a headache of sorts when its about dealing with this devil of a kind called dandruff. Primarily, it keeps coming back and secondarily it many times becomes difficult find an ultimate solution to the problem, causing headache. So, let us discuss out a reliable &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-do-deal-with-the-headache-called-dandruff/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Do Deal With The Headache Called Dandruff"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Dandruff is a common condition amongst us and yes it is a headache of sorts when its about dealing with this devil of a kind called dandruff. Primarily, it keeps coming back and secondarily it many times becomes difficult find an ultimate solution to the problem, causing headache. So, let us discuss out a reliable solution that can really cure our headache of dandruff and help us manage it well.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/How-Do-Deal-With-The-Headache-Called-Dandruff-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-718" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/How-Do-Deal-With-The-Headache-Called-Dandruff-1-1.jpg" alt="How Do Deal With The Headache Called Dandruff" width="602" height="334" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Dandruff or Flaky Scalp</strong> – Now, many of us are not able to figure out what we have actually got on our heads, is it dandruff or a flaky scalp. Dandruff occurs after an overreaction of yeast resulting into excess production of oil. As a result you experience irritation and get visible waxy and oily flakes. Besides, even skin conditions like eczema and psoriasis can also cause flaky scalps. Everyday stress, aging and an improper diet is also responsible for flakiness in the scalp.</p>
<p align="justify">Actually, to figure out how do deal with dandruff or a flaky scalp you need to visit a dermatologist first and get diagnosed. The remedies would depend on the condition and the severity. Here are some tips on getting rid of flakiness in scalp.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Tea Tree Oil</strong> – We all know that tea tree oil is used in many skin related products and health foods due to its vitamin content and use as an astringent on skin. It also works well in providing relief against oil and itchiness.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Balanced Diet</strong> – Many a times nutrient deficiences lead to scalp issues. These deficiences are caused to do an improper diet schedule. If you are consuming high amount of trans and saturated fats, its high time your do away with it or atleast reduce it to a bare minimum because they are the ones that trigger your sebaceous glands to produce more oil. Foods like avocados, safflower oil, olives and nuts are very good for your scalp health.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Stress Relief</strong> – Dandruff has also caused due to severe stress. Stress tends to weaken you immune system and the body is not able to fight the dandruff attack. According to some experts stress could also cause an itchy dandruff cycle which keeps on aggravating as you keep on scratching. Therefore, it is advisable to work on solutions or remedies that help reduce stress levels. Some of these include walking, jogging, exercise, yoga, meditation or pursuing a hobby regularly.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Using Appropriate Shampoo</strong> &#8211; Buying shampoos just watching ads and trying one after the other is okay but its also better that you try to find out the ingredients inside the shampoo which are usually mentioned on pack. The three main ingredients to look for in an anti-dandruff or scalp care shampoo is ketoconazole which helps reduce scalp yeast, selenium sulphide or zince pyrithione which helps reduce inflammation and certain bacterias besides yeast and salicylic acid, which helps in exfoliaton of scales.</p>
<p align="justify">Steriods – Your deramtologist could prescribe your certain relevant topical steriods for reducing scalp inflammation</p>
<p align="justify">Know More About <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
