<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Common Food Allergens in India &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/common-food-allergens-in-india/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 05:51:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 Common Food Allergens in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-common-food-allergens-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 05:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Common Food Allergens in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[common food allergies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Allergens in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[full health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good medical colleges in bangalore]]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1083</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Allergies are very common amongst us. Either we know we are allergic to stuff based on our experience post consumption of these foods or we aren’t. Many people have hiccups on eating spicy stuff like a chilly, while many get a runny nose. There are people who suffer from lactose intolerance and suffer from diarrhea &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-common-food-allergens-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "5 Common Food Allergens in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Allergies are very common amongst us. Either we know we are allergic to stuff based on our experience post consumption of these foods or we aren’t. Many people have hiccups on eating spicy stuff like a chilly, while many get a runny nose. There are people who suffer from lactose intolerance and suffer from diarrhea after consuming foods like milk or cheese. But, if you think all these are allergies, then you aren’t completely right. These can be categorized under food intolerance or insensitivity. A food allergy is not the same. It occurs when your body considers harmless food to apparently harm the body. Food allergies could range from creating simple reactions like rashes on skin, or irritation to eyes or breathing problems to turn out to be life threatening if immediate steps are not taken. The best way to keep yourself safe is to be aware of such triggers and avoid them.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1084" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India.jpg" alt="5 Common Food Allergens in India" width="800" height="600" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Let’s look through 10 different food allergens and their side effects or reactions they cause. The most common allergens are as follows &#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Eggs</strong> &#8211; The trigger that causes food allergies in eggs is egg protein like conalbumin, ovumucoid and ovalbumin. This allergy is found mostly in children than in adults. Some of the allergens are destroyed when the eggs are cooked but not all. This allergy can also cause anaphylaxis. The allergy can vary from person to person. While some might be allergic to yoke, some to egg white and some to all.</p>
<p><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-995 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg" alt="" width="397" height="41" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg 397w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore-300x31.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 397px) 100vw, 397px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Fish</strong> &#8211; Fish allergy could be really harmful. It can be life threatening and lead to anaphylaxis. The allergy can show reactions like throat swelling, diarrhea and puking, skin irritations, blood pressure drop and anaphylaxis as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Milk</strong> – Many children may be allergic to cow’s milk. It can also be passed to the child indirectly through breast feeding. Many children out-grow of the allergy once adults but one fifth of them are said to have it in their adulthood too. The presence of the milk antibodies can be determined with the help of the blood test.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Soyabean</strong> &#8211; Soy bean is also one of the common allergy to have. The reactions of soya bean allergy includes vomiting, diarrhea, ashes as well as stomach cramps. Sometimes it could also cause swelling of the tongue, lips as well as hand, feet and puffed eyes too. Other reactions include bloating, flatulence. Though, it rarely gets life threatening and cause anaphylaxis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Shellfish</strong> – Shell fish includes aquatic life like shrimp, oyster, crabs, mussels, clams, scallops, to name a few. This allergy can get serious and even vapor of the cooking shell fish can be allergic. The reaction are very much similar to other allergic reactions</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As far as allergens go, prevention is always the best idea. So be aware of allergies if you have any and avoid food that can cause allergies primarily. Also, in case you get one for the first time, take immediate action and consult a doctor without wasting much of a time.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about <strong><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/">Top Private Hospitals in Bangalore, Karnataka</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
