<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>kidney hospitals in Bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/kidney-hospitals-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 23:08:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Chronic Kidney Disease</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/chronic-kidney-disease/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 23:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best kidney hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysore road hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=825</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Chronic Kidney disease or CKD is s result of loss of kidney function over a period of time. Practically, the kidneys fail, if you may say so. There are though, five stages of CKD depending upon the severity. When the kidneys fail the waste, water and toxic substances accumulate in the body because the kidneys &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/chronic-kidney-disease/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Chronic Kidney Disease"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chronic Kidney disease or CKD is s result of loss of kidney function over a period of time. Practically, the kidneys fail, if you may say so. There are though, five stages of CKD depending upon the severity. When the kidneys fail the waste, water and toxic substances accumulate in the body because the kidneys are not able to excrete them. This can further result in conditions like acidosis (excessive acidity of body fluids), disorders related to fatty acids and cholesterol, anemia and high blood pressure.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-828 size-large" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-1024x576.jpg" alt="Chronic Kidney Disease" width="615" height="345" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Chronic-Kidney-Disease-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" /></a></p>
<p>While Stage five is obviously the end stage known as kidney or renal failure which results in complete kidney function failure. At this stage the person needs dialysis to survive or kidney transplantation.<br />
Acute kidney failure can also lead to loss of kidney function but it’s faster over a period of few days or weeks. But, this condition is reversible many times and there is a possibility of complete recovery of kidney function. But sometimes, it could end up as irreversible and require dialysis.</p>
<p><strong>STAGES</strong><br />
Here’s a run-down the stages of chronic kidney diseases.<br />
1. Slight damage with normal or increased filtration      GFR &gt; 90<br />
2. Mild decrease in kidney function                                GFR range 60-90<br />
3. Moderate decrease in kidney function                       GFR range 30 -59<br />
4. Severe decrease in kidney function                           GFR range 15-29<br />
5. Kidney Failure                                                            GFR &lt;15 / Dialysis</p>
<p><strong>DIAGNOSIS</strong><br />
To check for kidney damage, you need to undergo a few tests that include checking the level of waste products like creatinine and urea, in blood and urine test for abnormalities that indicate kidney damage cause. You may have to undergo an ultrasound for kidney structure assessment and biopsy for determining the cause of kidney problem. The diagnosis is based on results of Glomerular filtration rate and includes details like patient’s age, gender, race and serum creatinine levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="best kidney hospitals in bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/urology/" target="_blank"><strong>BEST KIDNEY HOSPITALS IN BANGALORE</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>RISK FACTORS</strong><br />
Some of the common risk factors of Chronic kidney disease include smoking, hypertension, obesity and diabetes mellitus.</p>
<p><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
After course of treatment is decided after determining the cause of the disease. Some kidney complications are treatable while some are not. The treatment procedure includes controlling the symptoms, reducing the complications and slowing the progression process through tested methods. In case the kidneys are severely damage then end stage treatment is provided. The medications used include those for reducing cholesterol levels, treating anemia and high blood pressure, reducing the swelling and protecting your bones. You might also be required to go on low protein diet to minimize wastage in blood.</p>
<p><strong>END STAGE TREAMENT</strong><br />
If your kidneys fail then the only treatment options available are dialysis or transplant. Dialysis is the process of removal of waste products from the body artificially with the help of a machine viz hemodialysis or a thin tube (catheter) fitted in the abdomen and dialysis solution that absorbs the waste plus excess fluids and is drained out. viz peritoneal dialysis. Kidney transplant on the other side is an expensive but better procedure because it involves replacing your kidney with a healthy kidney of a donor surgically. It could be of a deceased or living person. Though, medications after the procedure are to be taken life long for your body to accept the organ through life but no dialysis.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lower Back Pain vs Kidney Pain &#8211; The Difference</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lower-back-pain-vs-kidney-pain-the-difference/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 08:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lower back pain vs kidney pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=697</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many of us fail to figure out the difference when we experience pain particularly when its either kidney or lower back pain. So, to begin get down to the definition of lower back pain and kidney pain. It’s called lower back pain when it occurs anywhere from the buttocks upto the lower back. While kidney &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/lower-back-pain-vs-kidney-pain-the-difference/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Lower Back Pain vs Kidney Pain &#8211; The Difference"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Many of us fail to figure out the difference when we experience pain particularly when its either<em> kidney or lower back pain</em>. So, to begin get down to the definition of<em> lower back pain and kidney pain</em>.</p>
<p align="justify">It’s called <strong>lower back pain</strong> when it occurs anywhere from the buttocks upto the lower back. While <strong>kidney pain</strong> is said to occur between the hips or flanks and the ribs. At times you may experience it in the upper abdominal region as well. Well, this is the basic difference in back pain and kidney pain but otherwise also there are many other difference that can help you figure out which kind of pain you are suffering from. Here’s a sneak peek into a few other differences between kidney pain and lower back pain.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-698 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-300x147.jpg" alt="LOWER BACK PAIN VS KIDNEY PAIN" width="300" height="147" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-300x147.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1-768x377.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/LOWER-BACK-PAIN-VS-KIDNEY-PAIN-1.jpg 996w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Kidney Pain</strong><br />
Kidney pain is the result of a kidney infection or a kidney stone usually. Kidney infection can cause mild pain but kidney stone pain is very severe in nature and often compared to labor pain.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
The causes of kidney pain include kidney infection and kidney stones as mentioned before besides the pain could also be a result of renal infarction, kidney cancer and glomerulonephritis.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Lower Back Pain</strong><br />
Lower back pain is further divided as acute pain and chronic pain. While acute pain lasts for around 4 to 12 weeks, chronic back pain can easily last over 12 weeks. Also known as lumbago it affects people of all age groups.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
Lower back pain is a result of muscle sprain, spasm or tear leading to disc bulge or herniation, spinal stenosis, osteoporosis or sciatica. It could also be due to vertebral body, pedicle fracture or fracture of lamina. It can be caused due to Paravertebral muscle spasm or metastatic vertebral cancer.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Pain Management</strong><br />
<em>Kidney Pain –</em> Kidney pain treatment depends of its causes and usually involves use of antibiotics and medications if its infection but in case of kidney stones if that does not work a laser surgery or a minimally invasive surgery could be carried out.</p>
<p align="justify"><em>Back Pain</em> – For relief against lower back pain issues treatment could include suitable therapies like heat and cold, physical and massage therapies to name a few. In case with complications based on the diagnosis surgical procedures might be advised.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, its always advisable to visit your doctor if you suffer from back pain in order to figure out the root cause of the problem, be it <em>kidney or lower back</em>.</p>
<p align="justify">know about <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">best hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gallbladder Sludge &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/gallbladder-sludge-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 05:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gall bladder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gallbladder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=693</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Gall Bladder, a small organ inside our body but none the less is equally important as it has a unique function to perform just like every other organ. Gall bladder is responsible for acting as a reservoir for the bile, collecting it, concentrating it and emptying it into the bile duct. The bile duct further &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/gallbladder-sludge-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Gallbladder Sludge &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify"><em>Gall Bladder</em>, a small organ inside our body but none the less is equally important as it has a unique function to perform just like every other organ. Gall bladder is responsible for acting as a reservoir for the bile, collecting it, concentrating it and emptying it into the bile duct. The bile duct further takes it to the small intestine for digestion.<br />
The sludge in the gallbladder is known as biliary sludge and is also considered as microscopic form of gallstones. This sludge is generally made up of cholestrol and other particles as well as calcium and sodium crystals.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/gallbladder-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-694 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/gallbladder-1-300x203.jpg" alt="Gallbladder Sludge" width="300" height="203" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">People suffering from this conditions have symptoms like bloating, diarrhea, vomiting, nausea, indigestion, sweating to name a few. Initially the symptoms are mild but with time they start getting worse. Eventually, it could lead to gall bladder stones as well.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Risk Factors / Causes</strong><br />
The triggers of gall bladder sludge include fasting, certain medications, drug abuse, diet high in cholestrol, pregnancy and alcohol addictions. Even attempting a crash diet to go slim can result into gall bladder sludge as with little or no food intake the bile excretion decreases thus retaining the minimal bile in the bladder leading to sludge.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Diagnosis</strong><br />
Symptoms as mentioned before include severe abdominal pain in the upper right side of the body.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
If gall bladder sludge is diagnosed, doctors do suggest ursodoil, to help break down the protiens if any in the bile. Drinking a lot of water helps in removal of sludge naturally. But, if that does not work then the gall bladder stone needs to be removed from the body.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Prevention</strong><br />
Drinking plenty of water, intake flax seed oil, vitamin C and avoid food with high cholestrol contents.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, gall bladder stones can be removed easily with minimally invasive surgeries but its important to <a title="Book Doctor Appointment Online" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/online-appointment/" target="_blank">seek doctors </a>advice if your symptoms match the above.</p>
<p align="justify">Know More about <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">best hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Supplements Women Need After 30</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-supplements-women-need-after-30/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 09:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5 supplements for women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[after 30 years women required supplements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best psychiatrist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kidney hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=681</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many a times, lost in responsibilities around office or home, family or kids women forget about personal health or keep ignoring them. Till women are in the twenties, body is younger and fitter and hence copes in a better way. But, post 30 as you are nearly knocking door of your middle age, is when &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-supplements-women-need-after-30/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "5 Supplements Women Need After 30"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Many a times, lost in responsibilities around office or home, family or kids women forget about personal health or keep ignoring them. Till women are in the twenties, body is younger and fitter and hence copes in a better way. But, post 30 as you are nearly knocking door of your middle age, is when you really need to look into your bodily needs.<br />
After 30 there are a lot of changes that occur in a women’s body and are more visible after 35 years of age. These include changes in menstrual cycles, urinary incontinence, fibroids, pregnancy difficulties, prominent signs of aging, slow metabolism, but to name a few.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/5-Supplements-Women-Need-After-30-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-682 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/5-Supplements-Women-Need-After-30-1-300x199.jpg" alt="5 Supplements Women Need After 30" width="300" height="199" /></a>As per experts and specialists supplements can work well in maintaining the balance of nutrients required by the body.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Vitamin D</strong><br />
Vitamin D as we all know helps in a lot of ways that include immunity building, genes regulation, cancer prevention, bone health and more. The best, easy and affordable source of Vitamin D is sunlight. Sitting in the sunlight with minimal clothing for an hour can work well for your body. If not than Vitamin D supplements is the alternative.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Anti- Oxidants</strong><br />
It is in the mid or late thirties that women start noticing fine lines as well as thinning of skin. But, this process of aging can be slowed down with the help for a few minerals and vitamins together known as anti-oxidants. In order to boost immunity besides slowing aging women need to take in atleast 15 mg of Vitamin E. Further taking in 75 mg of Vitman C, which facilitates in vitamin E absorption and Vitamin A for protection against sun damage and eye</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>protection.</strong><br />
Omega 3 fatty acids/ fish oil<br />
As per doctors, our body needs 3 gms of omega 3 fatty acids per day. These help in keeping our joints health, weight management, keeping our blood fats normal and optimizing brain function. As these are essential fats and our body cannot make them taking mercury free supplements are advisable.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Calcium, Magnesium &amp; Iron</strong><br />
Calcium and magnesium help in bone building as well as producing energy and for better nerve functioning. Iron is also an essential nutrient responsible for keeping you active and protecting against infections as well as maintaining body temperature. As per experts our body requires about 18 mg per day. Though a pregnant and nursing women requires 27 mg and 9 mg per day respectively. Vitamin C and A help a lot in iron absorption.</p>
<p align="justify">As a busy woman, you might be occupied with umpteen activities around house, kids and family but its your health that equally matters so do take care of your health as well.</p>
<p align="justify">Contact to <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Best Hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
