<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>top hospitals in karnataka &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/top-hospitals-in-karnataka/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 06:05:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp – A Rare Pregnancy Rash</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/plaques-of-pregnancy-or-puppp-a-rare-pregnancy-rash/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 05:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obg specialist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaques of Pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1248</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know that pregnancy can bring along a lot of side effects also like fatigue, nausea, vomiting and more. But, one rare condition that only a few or say 1 in 160 women get are pregnancy PUPPPs. Though, it is known to be a common condition experienced by pregnant women, not all are aware &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/plaques-of-pregnancy-or-puppp-a-rare-pregnancy-rash/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp – A Rare Pregnancy Rash"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know that pregnancy can bring along a lot of side effects also
like fatigue, nausea, vomiting and more. But, one rare condition that
only a few or say 1 in 160 women get are pregnancy PUPPPs. Though, it
is known to be a common condition experienced by pregnant women, not
all are aware of it. Here’s and over view of Pruritic Urticarial
Papules or PUPPPS, also known as plaques or Pregnancy. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp.jpg" alt="Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp" class="wp-image-1249" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Though
as on day scientists and medical experts aren’t really sure of the
reason behind the surfacing of such itchy rashes in women during
pregnancy but believe that it could be due to excessive stretching of
skin in the months nearing to delivery. 
</p>



<p>Also,
there is no cure. The rashes tend to appear in the third semester and
disappear within 2 weeks post birthing. The rashes start mostly from
the stomach and spread across your thighs, legs, hands and neck area.
They look like red swollen patches and are extremely itchy. 
</p>



<p>Another
reason cited by experts around rash is the circulation of immune
fetal cells through the body. These cells spark an immune response
that in turn leads to the rash surfacing. The theory finds support in
the fact that the fetal cells do stay in the body for short time
after delivery. But, it’s not proved yet. 
</p>



<p>The
itching could get worse if you tend to scratch it. Better to avoid
scratching. In hotter regions the itching and pain is much worse and
proper care needs to be taken for relief. Here are a few tips around
relief from rashes 
</p>



<ol><li>

	Ice – Cool ice compresses
	can help relieve the itching. Wrap the ice compress in a cloth and
	apply few time during the day. 
	
	</li><li>

	Oatmeal – Oatmeal baths are
	known to be effective home remedy for may skin conditions including
	this one. 
	
	</li><li>

	Peppermint – Peppermint
	comes with menthol and it is known to have cooling effects. Use
	peppermint oil on the rashes or you might consume the prescribed
	quantity after consulting your doctor. 
	
	</li><li>

	Moisturiser –
	</li><li>

	Clove oil &#8211;  Clove oil is
	also known to have  cooling effects because it contains
	antimicrobials and antioxidants, phenol eugenol to be specific. 
	
</li></ol>



<p>
A study in 2017 revealed that
around 25 participants who applied petroleum jelly followed by clove
oil on rash prone areas show a reduction in symptoms compared to the
group that used on petroleum jelly.</p>



<p> Having said that, not every pregnant woman gets these itchy rashes but those who get could use the above tips for relief purpose because these rashes could get itchy to hell and frustrate you to the core. But, be calm, this will pass off and there is not known effects to the fetus due to their occurrence as yet.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Know more about  <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/"><strong>Best Gynecologist in Bangalore </strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 10:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1231</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[No a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions. But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town, even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus. The &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>No
a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around
relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions.
But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and
global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town,
even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus.
</p>



<p>The
earlier studies primarily were carried out for a short period of time
and only have been able to identify  the links between mental health
as well as temperature but the research till date only involves short
time period and more focused on connection rather than causal
factors. Moreover, this findings have so far not yielded any
substantial conclusions. So, the researchers with this study are
hoping to get answers to their questions that are not answered as
yet. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1232" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png 860w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-300x160.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-768x411.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
researchers for their study has gathered data from various sources
including Californian emergency departments,  collecting data and
analyzing information from the data of mental health diagnosis visits
during the period of 2005 – 2016. 
</p>



<p>They
even mined for data around suicides in America during 1960 – 2016
period.  These information was based on statuses that were
individually self-reported.  After drilling the climatic temperature
in US down, the researchers managed to develop ‘’fine spatial and
temporal scales”.</p>



<p>From
the study the researchers concluded that the mental health outcomes
decrease as the temperatures cool and the increase mental health
issues with rise in temperatures. Statistically speaking they found
that there was a rise in 0.48% rise in mental health visits with a
rise in average monthly temperature of 1<sup>0</sup> F and even a
rise in suicides by 0.35%</p>



<p>In
short, the rise and drop in temperatures has a significant impact of
the mental health because the authors of the study also showed
stability in the estimates even when accounted for socio economic
status and air conditioning adoption. 
</p>



<p>As for suicide rate, it rises only if there is a rise in temperature amid the growing season because growing season is all about crop yields. If the temperature rises, the crop yield reduces and leads to financial issues that in turn increase the risk of suicides.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Horns Of The Dilemma – Dairy Good Or Bad For Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/horns-of-the-dilemma-dairy-good-or-bad-for-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 06:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1224</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Though fruits and veggies are known to be healthy options as far as food is concerned there are conflicting views over dairy products and even their consumption levels on a regular basis. Milk and milk products in plenty are a must for kids and adolescents as milk is a rich source of calcium. Though milk &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/horns-of-the-dilemma-dairy-good-or-bad-for-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Horns Of The Dilemma – Dairy Good Or Bad For Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Though
fruits and veggies are known to be healthy options as far as food is
concerned there are conflicting views over dairy products and even
their consumption levels on a regular basis.  Milk and milk products
in plenty are a must for kids and adolescents as milk is a rich
source of calcium.  Though milk is good, it comes under saturated
fats and hence for people on a diet skimmed milk is a better option. 
</p>



<p> As per global standards the average consumption is around 2 to 2.5 servings a day for children.  Organizations like USDA and <strong>National Institute of Health (NIH)</strong> dairy is a vital source of magnesium, phosphorous, Protein and Vitamin D. A deficiency in calcium could raise the risk of osteoporosis as bones become weak and brittle.  </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Horns-Of-The-Dilemma-–-Dairy-Good-Or-Bad-For-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Horns-Of-The-Dilemma-–-Dairy-Good-Or-Bad-For-Health.jpg 512w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Horns-Of-The-Dilemma-–-Dairy-Good-Or-Bad-For-Health-300x208.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px" /></figure></div>



<p>Having
said that there are conflicting views around consumption of dairy
products.  As per a systematic review as well as meta-analysis says
that increase in dairy consumption increases the risk of
osteoporosis. But, not all studies are included in the said analysis.
 
</p>



<p>Another
long term study of Sweden that included 61000 women and 45000 men
revealed a potential link between high milk consumption as well as
high rate of bone fractures.  Though a Japanese study carried out
over 94,980 people revealed that a rise in consumption of milk did
lower the mortality risk. 
</p>



<p>Even the <strong>American heart Institution (AHA)</strong> has said that saturated fats could lead to increase in cholesterol as well as heart disease. Hence, some full fat dairy products do not come in the list of heart healthy diet recommendations. Furthermore, the national lung and blood institute has advised people to limit their dairy intake and use low fat dairy in their diet.  </p>



<p>There
is an article with umpteen analyses as well as reviews that do not
believe that saturated fats cause heart disease. It also states that
the saturated fats could decrease the risk of diabetes that is linked
to obesity.</p>



<p> So, while there is conflict with studies to support, dairy could be a healthy option if taken in limit. It could be helpful for people suffering from type 2 diabetes.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a> is one of the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Best Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nipah Virus Again On The Prowl In Kerala &#8211; All You Need To Know</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/nipah-virus-again-on-the-prowl-in-kerala-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 06:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hosital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nipah virus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1142</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Nipah Virus is again on the Prowl in Kerala. It’s just a year back that this Virus created a Havoc in the state and went on a killing Spree. The Virus with a fatality rate of over 88% killed 21 people of the 23 cases that were registered in Kerala in 2018 and scared the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/nipah-virus-again-on-the-prowl-in-kerala-all-you-need-to-know/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Nipah Virus Again On The Prowl In Kerala &#8211; All You Need To Know"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="text-align:left"><p align="justify" style="text-align:left">Nipah Virus is again on the Prowl in Kerala. It’s just a year back that this Virus created a Havoc in the state and went on a killing Spree. The Virus with a fatality rate of over 88% killed 21 people of the 23 cases that were registered in Kerala in 2018 and scared the hell out of the citizens. This year already 5 people are suspected to have contracted the NIV and under isolation already. So, primarily, it is a good idea to avoid travel to and around the region where the Nipah outbreak has just started.  Also, here’s all you need to know about this deadly condition. The Nipah infection is associated with Pteropus Bats genus as natural hosts and was first discovered in Malaysia and Singapore among pig farmers. It occurred due to close contact with pigs and is also known to spread through infected fruit bats besides humans and others like dogs, cats, rodents and horses as well. Though, the most likely ones are known to be humans, bats and pigs. The mortality rates in pigs is not high inspite of the fact that the infection rate is  In India, the first NIV outbreak occurred in Siliguri West Bengal in the year 2001, taking lives of 45 people out of the 68 detected. Then it surfaced again in 2007, killing all the 5 people known to have contracted the virus.  </p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nipah-virus-kerala.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1143" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nipah-virus-kerala.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nipah-virus-kerala-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>There
is no denial that the Nipah Virus is highly fatal and humans contract
it through either the body fluids of pigs, exposure to secretion of
sick pigs or corpses.  Human to Human contraction occurs through body
fluids, saliva of the patient and corpse as well. The fruit bat to
human infection is known to spread by consuming raw date palm sap
that are contaminated through the saliva or the urine of bats. Even
livestock that feeds on wild fruits contaminated via bats with NIV. 
</p>



<p>Nipah infection can be variable as far as symptoms are concerned right from being asymptomatic to getting fata encephalitis or acute respiratory infection. As of now there is no vaccine or treatment available for humans as well as animals. Even the 2018 Annual Review of WHO R&amp;D Blueprint list has a mention that this condition needs an emergency and speedy research as well as development. The only way at present is to make people aware about the risk factors and the precautionary measures to be taken in order to avoid the outbreak.  </p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/">Top Leading Hospital in Bangalore</a></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diabetes and Yeast Infections &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diabetes-and-yeast-infections-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 01:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals for diabetes in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes and yeast infections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rajarajeswari hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=649</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[There is certainly a relation between yeasts and diabetes and most logically it is sugar that relates yeast infections to diabetes. Yeast are generally found growing near mucous membranes around the skin. When there is a build up of yeast, it is called yeast infection. As yeast feeds on sugar and diabetics tend to sweat, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diabetes-and-yeast-infections-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Diabetes and Yeast Infections &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">There is certainly a relation between yeasts and diabetes and most logically it is sugar that relates yeast infections to diabetes. Yeast are generally found growing near mucous membranes around the skin. When there is a build up of yeast, it is called yeast infection. As yeast feeds on sugar and diabetics tend to sweat, pee and secrete a lot of mucus due to high glucose levels, automatically inviting yeasts to build on and cause yeast infections. The areas where yeast grow rapidly are those with warm temperatures typically under skin folds and breasts, mouth and around genitals.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Diabetes-and-Yeast-Infections-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignright wp-image-650 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Diabetes-and-Yeast-Infections-1-300x157.jpg" alt="Diabetes and Yeast Infections" width="300" height="157" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The most common of the yeast infections with women is the vaginal infection and generally occurs in people suffering from diabetics that is not under proper control. When the diabetes is not controlled properly, it also effects the immune system adversely. Apparently, it suppresses the growth of immune proteins known as beta defensins, responsible for killing microbes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Furthermore, even after treatment, there is high possibility of re-occurrence of the infection in people with poorly controlled diabetes. This is because after colonization of the yeast in a particular area, its becomes easy for yeast to re-attack. The extra sugar levels in diabetics helps in colonization on the yeast and makes it easy for other pathogens to stick to mucous gland and skin cells as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diagnosis</strong><br />
The doctor asks for vaginal secretion sample test to confirm the vaginal yeast infection. The microscopical review of the sample is carried out for confirmation of Candida fungus in abnormal amounts. Sometimes even urine samples are tested.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
Most of the doctors prescribe anti-fungal creams that can be easily applied to the affected area. These creams are usually available over the counter. Only when creams aren’t effective is when doctors prescribe a dose of anti-fungal medication.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Home Remedies</strong><br />
Alternatively, home remedies like using oregano oil, yogurt, over the counter creams, coconut or tea tree oil for treating yeast infection are commonly tried.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Prevention</strong><br />
Prevention is always a better idea, and particularly for diabetics, wherein there is high possibility of yeast infection to reoccur. But, certain precautionary measures can help you keep the yeast infection at bay. This includes keeping body and genital dry, using clean cotton under garments and perfumed pads of good quality. As far as diet supplements are concerned, eating yogurt on a daily basis helps a lot.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Though, treating the root cause would definitely help you the most so try keeping your glucose levels under control to prevent the complications that arise due to the same.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a title="Best Hospital in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Best Hospital in Bangalore</a> when compared to all <a title="Master Health Checkups in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/health-checkups-in-india-the-good-the-bad-and-beyond/" target="_blank">private hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fungal Infections &#8211; An Over View</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/fungal-infections-an-over-view/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 10:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysore road hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=645</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Fungal infections are very common part of our day to day lives. When our immune system is unable to handle the invasions of infection causing fungus, is when we get prone to the condition called fungal infection. There are usually two kinds of fungi that reside on human body. The helpful one and the harmful &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/fungal-infections-an-over-view/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Fungal Infections &#8211; An Over View"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Fungal infections are very common part of our day to day lives. When our immune system is unable to handle the invasions of infection causing fungus, is when we get prone to the condition called fungal infection. There are usually two kinds of fungi that reside on human body. The helpful one and the harmful one. The invasion of harmful fungi causes infections as they cannot be killed easily and can rebound as well.<a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Fungal-Infections-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignright wp-image-646 size-thumbnail" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Fungal-Infections-1-150x150.jpg" alt="Fungal Infections " width="150" height="150" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Fungal-Infections-1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Fungal-Infections-1-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><em>The most common types of fungal infections in humans include &#8211;</em></strong><br />
<em>Ringworm</em> &#8211; This infection is caused by a fungus that lives on dead tissues of skin, nails and hair. It is also responsible for causing athlete’s foot and jock itch but if it occurs on other parts of the body it is known as ringworm. Generally, doctors</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Jock itch</em> &#8211; A mildly contagious infection by nature, it is caused by fungus that breed in damp and warm regions of the body like groin, inner thighs and buttocks. It causes redness of skin accompanied by itching, chafing or burning. Doctors usually prescribe some topical anti-fungal ointments and advise patients to maintain proper body hygiene.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Athlete’s foot</em> &#8211; As the name suggests this infection is very common with sports people and athletes. The reason for it being so common with athletes is breeding environments like shoes, sports equipments, locker rooms, socks. Though it can happen to anyone as well. Athletes feet is also treated with topical anti-fungal oinments but some serious infections need oral medicinal intake as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Now, that we are aware of some of the common form of fungal infections let us run down some nutrients that can help us fight fungal infections and are commonly available.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Garlic</em> – Garlic does limit the growth of fungus called candida to a large extent as it is highly sensitive to particularly the purified extract of garlic called allyl alcohol that produced oxidative stress thus supressing the growth of it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Tea Tree Oil</em> – This oil is effective on candida and various other fungal isolates. It treats candida and paronychia infections effectively as well. The tea tree oil disrupts the yeast cell wall thus inhibiting its growth.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Another way of to protect yourself from the unhealthy fungus, maintaining good population of the healthy fungus particularly to avoid vaginal infections, in women. Yogurt and pro-biotics are a good source of friendly bacteria in the vagina or rectum. Even fructooligosaccharides, a form of sugar is known to boost the levels of the good bacteria in the body, so adding one teaspoon daily to your diet should help you a lot in proliferation of friendly bacteria.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Contact to <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">best hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heartburn or Acid Reflux &#8211; Don&#8217;t Ignore This Sign</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/heartburn-or-acid-reflux-dont-ignore-this-sign/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 08:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gastroenterologists in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gastroesophageal reflux disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heartburn or Acid Reflux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=498</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Eating habits of Indians include oily and sweet food intake and now add to it the junk food habits of the urban class.. all these roads end up to one common destination – heart burn. Heart burn is often ignored by people because it is a common condition that most of us happen to suffer &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/heartburn-or-acid-reflux-dont-ignore-this-sign/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Heartburn or Acid Reflux &#8211; Don&#8217;t Ignore This Sign"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Eating habits of Indians include oily and sweet food intake and now add to it the junk food habits of the urban class.. all these roads end up to one common destination – heart burn. Heart burn is often ignored by people because it is a common condition that most of us happen to suffer from.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>HEART BURN OR ACID REFLUX</strong><br />
Heart burn is also known as acid reflux and is also a symptom for gastro esophadeal reflux. Our body consists of a specialized muscle called esophageal sphincter (LES) placed at the lowerside of the esophagus or food pipe. When we eat food, it opens up to allow food to pass through and instantly closes down to avoid reflux or backward movement of food, acids or enzymes present in the stomach into the food pipe. In order to avoid inflammation, the stomach is provided with a lining of special protective cells. But, esophagus has no such lining for protection hence is vulnerable to damage if there is a reflux of acids and digestive juices into it. Heart burn, also a general symptom of GERD (gastroesophageal reflux disease) occurs when the digestive juices and acids reflux back into the esophagus.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Heartburn-or-Acid-Reflux-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignright wp-image-499 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Heartburn-or-Acid-Reflux-1-1.jpg" alt="Heartburn or Acid Reflux" width="275" height="183" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>CAUSES</strong><br />
Irregular and improper dietary habits usually pave the way to heartburn. Again, there are certain foods that instigate the secretion of acids in stomach again leading to the same. Some of these foods include intake of fruits containing acidic juices like pineapple, orange and veggies like tomatoes. Drugs like ibuprofen ans aspirin ,chocolates and caffeine, aerated drinks, alchohol and smoking and obesity, pregnancy and hiatal hernia, to name a few.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>EFFECTS</strong><br />
Ignoring a prolonged condition of heartburn could lead to ulcer formation, scarring and stricture and other related GERD complications. Heartburn could also lead to change in the type of cells lining the esophagus further causing Barett’s esophagus – a condition known to increase the risk of esophageal cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DIAGNOSIS</strong><br />
Recurring heartburn needs a diagnosis, definitely. It includes physical examination and medical history.<br />
<em>X- Ray Test &#8211;</em> A X-ray test that needs the patient to consume to contrasting drugs while watching the complete process through a x-ray. This is done to check whether the <a class="spell" href="https://www.google.co.in/search?rlz=1C1CHBD_enIN713IN713&amp;biw=1280&amp;bih=869&amp;q=esophagus+muscles&amp;spell=1&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=0ahUKEwjViMrg17zTAhUDQo8KHX9mBx0QvwUIICgA">esophagus <i>muscles</i></a> are in good shape, working properly as well as for inflammations or issues withing the food pipe.<br />
<strong>Endoscopy</strong><br />
Endoscopy involves the use of a flexible scope fitted with a fibre optic camera for checking out the lining of esophagus and stomach.<br />
<em>Biopsy –</em> This is only done if the gastroenterologists suspects possibilities of cancer.<br />
<em>Manometry –</em> This is not a commonly used test in India and is carried out only if the traditional diagnosis does not give any outcome. Herein, pressure monitors are used measurement of acids inside the esophagus.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
The primary treatment for heart burn involves change in lifestyle. This includes eating smaller potions of meals at frequent intervals, avoiding addictions like alcohol, smoking and more. Using a high pillow for head support while sleeping, avoiding or reducing fruits and veggies with excessive acids, weight loss if obese or overweight and using antacids but in limited proportions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For patients suffering from Barrett’s esophagus, severe reflux issues leading to wheezing and pneumonia and intensive medical therapy failure, surgery is opted. With the advancement of technology laparoscopy is also used for non invasive treatment of more serious esophagus conditions like carcinoma.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">So next time, take heart burn issues seriously and if it is recurring and prolonged then do consult a doctor because little do we know that heart burn might just be a sign of life threatening kidney disease like kidney cancer or even failure. Furthermore, do consult a doctor if you need to take heartburn drugs for a prolonged time period because regular intake could lead to serious renal issues as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">know about <a title="Best Hospital in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Rajarajeswari Hospital in Banglaore</a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
