<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>medical students life &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/medical-students-life/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 10:53:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Life of Medical Student &#8211; Awesome or Not?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/life-of-medical-student-awesome-or-not/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 10:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs student life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college student life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical students life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student life in medical]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=714</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Though medical students have a routine they follow when in college and it is mostly fixed by the college, life can differ from one individual from other. There are myths and beliefs around medicine as a course and the labor and toiling that it involves around the 5 years duration of the course. Yes, off &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/life-of-medical-student-awesome-or-not/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Life of Medical Student &#8211; Awesome or Not?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Though <strong>medical students</strong> have a routine they follow when in college and it is mostly fixed by the college, life can differ from one individual from other. There are myths and beliefs around medicine as a course and the labor and toiling that it involves around the 5 years duration of the course. Yes, off course the course involves hard work for continuous five years and a lot of study as well. But, it does come with a lot of benefits and sweet afters as well. So, here is a run down how a medical students life can be awesome even if he or she has to lose their mind for cracking the course.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Life-of-Medical-Student-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-715" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Life-of-Medical-Student-1-1.jpg" alt="Life of Medical Student" width="620" height="340" /></a></p>
<p><strong>The Busy Bee Boon</strong> – Yes, a medical students routine is all packed through the day right from the morning till the evening and includes early theory lectures, dissection, hospital visits, case presentation and more through out the day. Apparently, medical students many a times run out of time to study for their theory exams at the end of the year. But, still its a boon because it rarely gives to time to think about anything else. Remember, the saying an idle mind is a devils workshop and doctors are too busy to be idle.</p>
<p><strong>You’ll Definitely make Cool Friends</strong> – At the medical campus, you are going to find many smart heads and many of your wavelength. Over a period of time you’ll not only love discussing out the subject matter with them but develop many friendships that might as well last for a lifetime time. This is not just awesome but the most invaluable part or rather gift of your medical education.</p>
<p><strong>No Job Worries</strong> &#8211; Like any other routine degree course graduate, you don’t need to hunt for a job. Most of the jobs will slip in like butter without much ado. What more an internship is also going to pay you big bucks, and a job definitely a fortune in years to come. So, that’s a pretty good reason to feel awesome about doing a medical course ain’t it.</p>
<p><strong>Learn stuff that not many get too</strong> – Your body is beautiful and what better than exploring every part of your body and gaining knowledge about your body which you rarely did. At the end of the course you will be an enriched person with knowledge about functioning of all the organs of the body and much more.</p>
<p><strong>Serve the Society</strong> – By the time you enter your college and your hospital sessions begin you come to know that at the end of the day your are going to serve the society and be responsible for the smiles and frowns on the faces of people, while to try and work to turn frowns into smiles all the while. The feeling of doing something good for the society in itself makes one feel at the top of the world and you as a doctor are going to do it day in and day out and that above all is the best part of being a doctor or taking up medicine as career however hard or toiling or laborious it is going to be.</p>
<p>know more about <a title="Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org" target="_blank">Medical Colleges</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
