<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Medical Tourism Destination &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/medical-tourism-destination/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 04:41:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Top 5 Medical Tourism Destinations in the World</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-medical-tourism-destination-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 12:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medical Tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medical Tourism Destination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medical Tourism Destination in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top 5 Medical Tourism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=925</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know about the recent spurt in medical Tourism, but what you might not know and perhaps, would want to know is,  names of the countries that top this list. Before we look into that, here’s some information on medical tourism. As per international statistics, 11 million people from the USA opted for medical tourism &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-medical-tourism-destination-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Top 5 Medical Tourism Destinations in the World"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">We all know about the recent spurt in medical Tourism, but what you might not know and perhaps, would want to know is,  names of the countries that top this list. Before we look into that, here’s some information on medical tourism. As per international statistics, 11 million people from the USA opted for medical tourism in 2016. Now, that is a huge number. Furthermore, the medical tourism industry is slated to grow by 25% in the coming years. People are choosing medical tourism alternative for reasons like quality healthcare at impressive costs, convenience and more. Lets run-down 5 of the most sought-after medical tourism destinations in the world.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>BRAZIL</strong> &#8211; As per World Health Organization, Brazil tops the list of medical tourism destinations in the world. With over 40 JCI accredited hospitals and world’s best experts under their belts, Brazil is a one-stop solution for healthcare needs around cosmetic and plastic surgery. The reason it is third on the list of most visited countries for cosmetic and plastic surgery is due to its quality services at affordable rates.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>MEXICO</strong> &#8211; Mexico is one of the most preferred destinations for medical healthcare as it is known to reduce the medical costs by a staggering 40% to 65%. It boasts of over 98 JCI accredited hospitals and offers advanced treatment procedures in areas of cosmetic surgery and dentistry. Most of the people residing in the USA are known to travel to Mexico for their healthcare needs.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-938 alignright" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Medical-Tourism-1-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Medical-Tourism-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Medical-Tourism-1.jpg 638w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>INDIA</strong> &#8211; India is brimming with medical tourists as on day and the reason it stands in this list is its ability reduce healthcare costs by a mammoth 65% to 90% as compared to the USA, making it one of the most visited countries for healthcare services. India is a preferred location not only due to its affordability or quality healthcare services but because there is zero waiting time for scheduling surgeries and living here is a relaxing experience as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>THAILAND</strong> – The land of the white elephants as it is known, Thailand is also famous for its pristine beaches. But many of us aren’t aware of the fact that it is also a popular destination for medical tourism. You can not only reduce your medical expenditure by 50% to 75% but also avail facilities like private recovery gardens, Thai massage and other relaxation therapies at affordable prices.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TURKEY</strong> – The reason Turkey is on the list of most favored destinations for medical tourism is that it offers zero waiting times for services of healthcare particularly like transplant, neurosurgery, genomic medicine, radiation therapy for cancer. The Turkish airlines also offers discounts for medical tourists and the best part is the bottom line &#8211;  you end up saving around 50% to 65% of your money as compared to the USA.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, <a title="health care services in india" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/emergency-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">healthcare</a> has broadened its horizons and is available across borders at affordable prices. Hence, umpteen people across countries are opting for medical tourism.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
