<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>health care services in india &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/health-care-services-in-india/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 09:47:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 09:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Role Of Legumes In Heart Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1245</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes. Though it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual basis. But, recently &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer
by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find
out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes.  Though
it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual
basis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1246" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>Five color legumes for healthy , Soy bean, Navy bean or white bean, Black beam, Red bean and Green bean,</figcaption></figure>



<p>But,
recently researchers of the review called Advances in Nutrition took
up the task of understanding the significance of legumes like
lentils, peas and beans etc. around heart health. 
</p>



<p>Primarily, they focused on cardiovascular diseases like <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">coronary heart</a> disease, stroke, myocardial infarction besides looking into hypertension, obesity and diabetes. They chose cardiovascular diseases because it is one of the most common causes of mortality and even one of the most expensive ones. It is known to cause US 1 billion dollars a day. </p>



<p>They
used the data analysis of Eurpoean Association which recently carried
out a series of systematic reviews as well as meta-analysis for
Diabetics study. The researchers hope that these results could be
quite a help in updating the recommendations already made around the
role of legumes in preventing as well as treating cardio-metabolic
diseases. 
</p>



<p>The
data review and comparison with people with lowest and highest intake
of legumes revealed that dietary pulses that had legumes which either
did or did not include other legumes did decrease coronary heart
disease, obesity incidence and hypertension. 
</p>



<p>
Though the researchers were able to find a positive relationship
between intake of legumes in higher amounts and reduction in certain
parameters related to cardiovascular risks, the conclusion they came
to are muted relatively. 
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers “The overall certainty of the evidence was
graded as low for CVD incidence and ‘very low for all the other
outcomes.” 
</p>



<p>Therefore, the co author of the study Dr Hana Kahleova said “ Americans eat less than one serving of legumes per day, on average. Simply adding more beans to our plates could be a powerful tool in fighting heart disease and bringing down blood pressure.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><strong>Best Cardiologist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 09:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1213</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market of heart conditions. As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers
in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports
in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus
reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market
of heart conditions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1214" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png 620w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits-300x179.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></figure>



<p> As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">cardiovascular</a> conditions increases significantly in women and lipid profile is a reliable marker to measure heart health.  He and his colleagues investigated around 193 menopausal women participants of the age group 47-55 from Finland, registered for the Estrogenic Regulation of Muscle Apoptosis (ERMA) study.  The study is co-authored by Dr Mathew Jergenson of Minnesota Medical School and University in Minneapolis. The reason behind conducting the study as per him was to explore if physical activity did have a role in cardiovascular risk factors.  </p>



<p>
He says “It is well known that physical activity has health
benefits, yet it is less clear to what extent physical activity
prevents negative changes in lipid profile while women are in their
menopausal transition.  The participants were monitored for physical
activity levels in leisure time, generally and specifically also,
using accelerometers and had to answer questions as well.</p>



<p>
Leisure is the time that is not related to routine daily work be it
housework or commuting and includes sport or recreation activities in
free time. 
</p>



<p>The
researchers found out that there was indeed a connection between more
activities during leisure time and lowering of cholesterol levels
particularly (LDL) as well as with high levels of cholesterol (HDL). 
Karvin reports that indeed the leisure time physical activities were
related to healthy lipid profiles. But, that does not mean that the
negative changes in lipid profile during menopause can be fully done
away with due to leisure time sports activities. 
</p>



<p>The author also said that leisure time physical activities will underscore the adverse atherogenic changes in the cardiovascular risk factors in middle aged women who are healthy. Hence, sport related activities in leisure are good.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is having <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/"><strong>Top most Physiotherapist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celiac Disease Detection Now Made Faster With Blood Test –AN Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/celiac-disease-detection-now-made-faster-with-blood-test-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 05:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1183</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As per All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Celiac disease is known to affect around 6 – 8 million people across India. Also known as gluten sensitive enteropathy or celiac sprue, Celiac disease is known to be an emerging health condition. Celiac disease is a disease where in there is sensitivity against gluten, a &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/celiac-disease-detection-now-made-faster-with-blood-test-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Celiac Disease Detection Now Made Faster With Blood Test –AN Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As per All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Celiac disease is known to affect around 6 – 8 million people across India. Also known as gluten sensitive enteropathy or celiac sprue, Celiac disease is known to be an emerging health condition. Celiac disease is a disease where in there is sensitivity against gluten, a protein that is found in wheat, rye and barley. It does not mean allergy to gluten or intolerance to it at all. It is an auto immune disorder that occurs in 1 in 1000 genetically disposed people. This disorder is not very common in Southern India but is prevalent in North and North eastern parts of India.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1184" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg 754w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test-300x212.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></figure>



<p>Now
coming to the detection of this condition. The present method used to
diagnose it consumes weeks or months. As the time taken to detect the
condition is prolonged, people with the condition have to bear with
the side effects of it.  With the blood test, this time could be
reduced to just a few hours.  Scientists who are working on the same
have been able to pick some of the biomarkers forming the blood test
basis. They have found that when people are exposed to gluten, there
is an increase inflammatory molecules in the blood stream that can
associate with the symptoms that are in common. 
</p>



<p>Known
to affect 1 percent of the population across the western world,
Celiac disease is a condition one has to live with. In India there is
limited awareness about celiac disease and there is a dire need for
awareness around the condition and its prevention as well. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Now-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1185" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Now-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg 480w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Now-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test-300x218.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /></figure>



<p>As per Dr Robert P Anderson, who is the Chief Scientific Officer at ImmusanT, it was the first time that their team has been able to describe the inflammatory reaction that the patients experience when they are exposed to gluten. He also stated that the findings could also help differentiate people who have similar symptoms but do not suffer from the condition and ensure that proper treatment pertaining to their condition is given to them.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p></p>



<p>Just know about the <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Changes In Diet That Help You Reduce The Risk Of Cancer</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/changes-in-diet-that-help-you-reduce-the-risk-of-cancer/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1179</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As per statistics cancer is the causes the second highest number of deaths in India every year. Out of the 9.6 mn, over 8% are from India. Well, that’s not a small number. One of the most common cancers in India today is breast cancer. We all know that with all the innovations and advances &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/changes-in-diet-that-help-you-reduce-the-risk-of-cancer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Changes In Diet That Help You Reduce The Risk Of Cancer"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As
per statistics cancer is the causes the second highest number of
deaths in India every year.  Out of the 9.6 mn, over 8% are from
India. Well, that’s not a small number. One of the most common
cancers in India today is breast cancer. We all know that with all
the innovations and advances in Science, even today cancer does
affect the life expectancy negatively and also quality of life. So,
trying to prevent it seems a better idea. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1180" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer-300x160.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer-768x409.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>A
new study has revealed that the foods that are rich in flavonoids are
helpful in decreasing the risk of cancer and extending longevity. The
study was carried out over 50,000 participants across a span of 20
years. Finding out the impact of single compounds on health
conditions as well as mortality is not an easy study, even though
food does form the most important part of our lives.  
</p>



<p>Researchers
have already brought to light that eating vegetables and fruits
factually reduce the risk of cardiovascular conditions and increase
life span too. Though, the details on how they do it is under
research phase yet. Many researchers believe that it is rich in
flavonoids play a vital role in the same. 
</p>



<p>Flavonoids
are found in different natural food likes vegetables, dark
chocolates, fruits and tea are form a chemical class known as
polyphenols. These compounds are further divided into six sub classes
namely Flavonols, flavanones, flavan-3-ols, anthocyanins, flavones
and isoflavones.</p>



<p>A group of scientists from Edith Cowan University of Australia did begin a research in order to find out how the compounds could help increasing life span and help protect against health conditions. They also wanted to look into the effects of alcohol and smoking around the benefits of flavonoids. For investigation of the same, the scientists used the Danish Diet data of over 56048 adults across 23 years. During the process over 14083 participants passed away too. The researchers concluded that it was true that flavonoid rich diets with individual flavonoid subclasses do actually reduce the risk of cancer and cardiovascular diseases also increasing longevity.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/"><strong>Best Cancer Hospital Treatment in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monsoon And Child Health Issues</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 05:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monsoon And Child Health Issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1173</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera, Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Monsoon And Child Health Issues"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Well,
everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you
hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on
your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along
health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera,
Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. Here’s
a run-down five of the most common illness viral/bacteria borne, that
you need to protect your child from – 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1174" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg 975w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-768x451.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Dengue</strong>
– Caused by the Aedes aegypti mosquito, Dengue mosquitos breed in
stagnant water be it flower pots, buckets, tree holes or drums etc.
The incubation period is four to seven days after being bitten. The
symptoms include high grade fever with decreasing platelet count as
well as rashes. To prevent dengue try to keep your body covered as
much as possible and use mosquito repellents. Citronella is a good
mosquito repellent plant. 
</p>



<p><strong>Diarrhoea</strong>
– This is one
condition that can be prevented with proper precautions as it is
caused because of unhygienic food and water consumption. The best way
to prevent it is to drink boiled water and eat home cooked food. Both
the types of diarrhea, chronic as well as acute can be managed
through appropriate and timely treatment. 
</p>



<p><strong>Typhoid
</strong><strong>– </strong>This is
another waterborne condition that is caused by S typhi bacteria. The
main reason is poor sanitation. The symptoms include weakness, pain,
fever as well as sore throat to name a few. This condition can also
be prevented by avoiding street food, keeping your hands clean and
keeping yourself hydrated with healthy fluids. 
</p>



<p><strong>Malaria
– </strong>This is also a
water borne condition that is caused due to the female anopheles
mosquito. This mosquito breeds in water logged areas and hence is a
common condition in monsoon. The symptoms include fever with chills
or shivering, body ache and weakness, etc. The best way to prevent
the cause of malaria is to keep surroundings clean especially water
tanks. 
</p>



<p style="text-align:left">Jaundice – Jaundice is also a water borne disease that could go serious if not treated properly.  This is again a result of consuming contaminated food and water. The symptoms of jaundice include yellow eyes and urine, weakness and liver dysfunction.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Second Hand Smoke Is Also Dangerous To Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/second-hand-smoke-is-also-dangerous-to-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 09:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second hand smoke]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1169</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We are aware how dangerous smoking is for health, but second hand smoke viz. the smoke that we inhale when someone else is smoking could be life threatening too. As per statistics second hand smoke is known to cause over 3000 deaths due to heart disease to non-smokers. Second hand smoke can be particularly harmful &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/second-hand-smoke-is-also-dangerous-to-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Second Hand Smoke Is Also Dangerous To Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
are aware how dangerous smoking is for health, but second hand smoke
viz. the smoke that we inhale when someone else is smoking could be
life threatening too. As per statistics second hand smoke is known to
cause over 3000 deaths due to heart disease to non-smokers. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1170" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health.jpg 948w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health-768x575.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>Second
hand smoke can be particularly harmful to children because their
lungs are still under development.   Many children inhale this
dangerous smoke at home if their parents or family members smoke,
primarily. Even parents who smoke outside risk their children to
harmful chemicals because of second hand smoke. 
</p>



<p>Also,
known as environmental tobacco smoke, the smoke that is breathed out
as well as the smoke that is released from pipes, cigars, burning
cigarettes, cigars or pipes contains around 4000 chemicals. Almost 50
of these chemicals are carcinogenic and are known to increase the
risk of cancer. 
</p>



<p>The
American Academy of pediatrics (AAP) did a research on third hand
smoke also. Third hand smoke is the smoke that is left behind in
areas where people smoke. Though people leave the place after
smoking, the harmful toxins remain for a while for example in bars,
upholstery, even child’s hair if the care taker smokes. 
</p>



<p>Well,
second hand smoke and third hand smoke both are harmful to adults,
children and even the unborn developing ones. Unborn and children are
at a higher risk. Children whose parents smoke cough more than
children generally do. They are at the risk of getting coughs and
colds, tooth decay, ear infections and respiratory problems. Children
suffering from asthma are particularly prone to second hand smoke as
it can lead to asthma attacks that to frequent and severe leading to
a rise in hospital visits. 
</p>



<p>Well, so if you think that only smoking is injuries to health, you are certainly not right, its also the people around the smokers that are at the risk inspite of being not guilty of smoking. Take care. Quit now.</p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Private Medical Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Encephalitis (CHAMKI Fever) The Deadly Fever That Has Killed Over 150 Children In Bihar And Jharkhand Already</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/encephalitis-chamki-fever-the-deadly-fever-that-has-killed-over-150-children-in-bihar-and-jharkhand-already/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 11:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood banks in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1145</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The news of around 150 children dead due to the chamki fever is already a topic of concern present day. The Supreme Court also has taken notice of this serious or grave situation and directed Center to immediately form a medical expert team for the treatment of children having AES. An inflammation of brain, encephalitis &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/encephalitis-chamki-fever-the-deadly-fever-that-has-killed-over-150-children-in-bihar-and-jharkhand-already/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Encephalitis (CHAMKI Fever) The Deadly Fever That Has Killed Over 150 Children In Bihar And Jharkhand Already"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The
news of around 150 children dead due to the chamki fever is already a
topic of concern present day. The Supreme Court also has taken notice
of this serious or grave situation and directed Center to immediately
form a medical expert team for the treatment of children having AES. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1146" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar.jpg 700w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar-300x172.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /></figure>



<p>An
inflammation of brain, encephalitis commonly known as chamki fever is
the inflammation of brain. It is caused by viral infection and
affects the nervous system. There are two main types of Encephalitis
namely Primary and Secondary. This fever usually occurs in kids and
youngsters below 15 years of age.   
</p>



<p>The
primary is caused due to direct viral infection to the brain while
secondary is a result of a weak immune system and can be a result of
infection in any part of the body.  Presently, there’s an outbreak
of this fever in Bihar and Jharkhand. Recently, even Bengal has
reported three cases of AES or Chamki of which one is critical.  
</p>



<p><strong>Causes
</strong>
</p>



<p>AES
is known to be a viral infection but can occur due to mosquito borne
viruses, Zika or Nipah Virus, Rabis virus, childhood infections,
enteroviruses and herpes virus as well. In India the most commonly
known AES causing virus is the Japanese Encephalitis (JE) as almost 5
-35% cases are that of JE Virus AES. Though, this year only two cases
are due to the JE Virus and exact cause of so many deaths is not
known. What is known is that the deaths were caused by hypoglycemia
(low blood sugar levels) 
</p>



<p>
<strong>Symptoms </strong>
</p>



<p>At
the initial stage the symptoms are similar to mild flu and include
fever, headache, fatigue, muscle or joint pain. Though in the later
or severe stage it leads to hallucinations, agitation, confusion,
muscle weakness, hearing difficulties paralysis, sensation loss,
vomiting, poor eating, body stiffness, skull bulging and more.    
</p>



<p><strong>Treatment
</strong>
</p>



<p>There
is not medicine yet for this fever and the mild one can be brought
down through adequate rest and continuous fluid intake. Drugs like
Tylenol, Aleve and Advil also can be used. Medications like Foscavir,
Cytoven and Zovirax can be used for the viral Encephalitis only on
prescription basis. Do not consume any medications with Doctors
consult. At times supportive care like breathing assistance,
intravenous fluids to keep the person hydrated, anti-convulsant and
anti-inflammatory drugs against seizures and swelling could be
required. 
</p>



<p><strong>Prevention
</strong>
</p>



<p>Prevention is always better and hence to avoid getting this condition try to maintain hygiene at home, clean your hands properly after you visit the toilet and before eating food. Also, drink clean water and use mosquito nets and repellants when sleeping.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about The  <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Egg Freezing &#8211; More Power to Women</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/egg-freezing-is-all-about-empowering-women/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 05:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=928</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Egg freezing is not an entirely unknown term. Awareness about it is fast spreading across cities in India. Even Gynaecologists have observed a spurt in the inquiries around egg freezing. Scientifically known as oocyte cryopreservation, this process involves the extraction of a woman&#8217;s egg from the ovary, freezing and storing it. Afterwards at the time &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/egg-freezing-is-all-about-empowering-women/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Egg Freezing &#8211; More Power to Women"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Egg freezing is not an entirely unknown term. Awareness about it is fast spreading across cities in India. Even Gynaecologists have observed a spurt in the inquiries around egg freezing. Scientifically known as <strong>oocyte cryopreservation</strong>, this process involves the extraction of a woman&#8217;s egg from the ovary, freezing and storing it. Afterwards at the time of conceiving, this egg is thawed and placed in the uterus as embryos.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This is a boon for women in India today who want to make life choices on their own at their time. Many women delay marriages as they do not want to get married under pressure and want to prioritize education and career. Such women can freeze their eggs and use them later to conceive. There are numerous case studies to help you understand how egg freezing helped women in India conceive and deliver a healthy baby at a time when they were ready for it.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-937 alignright" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cryopreservation-1-300x176.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="176" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cryopreservation-1-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cryopreservation-1.jpg 638w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Case 1</strong> &#8211; A 31-year-old female from Matunga wanted to conceive through IVF and her husband was in too much pressure while donating his sperm, so much so that he was not able to produce a semen sample required for the IVF on the day of collection. So, they extracted her egg and froze it. The IVF process was later completed once the semen was received and she had a hassle free pregnancy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Case 2</strong> &#8211; A 14-year-old female was diagnosed with cancer in one of her ovaries. The doctor extracted and froze her egg from the other ovary before she underwent chemotherapy. He mother was glad that her daughter had a choice to conceive in the future as freezing her egg granted protection to her fertility.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Case 3</strong> – A 36-year-old who was not ready for marriage, froze her eggs at 32 so that whenever she is ready for it and for maternity, there are no issues with conceiving.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Today, egg freezing awareness is spreading fast amongst the society and many women are opting for the alternative as it empowers them to make a choice of becoming a mother, at the time they want to. Across the world, egg freezing has already helped conceive and deliver over 2000 babies. Having said that, even though the freezing can be done at any age based on the count of antral follicles and hormone levels, the doctors generally advise doing the egg freezing before 35 years.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In today’s times when the world is embracing gender equality and women are determined to match the abilities of men in almost every walk of life, egg freezing is an amazing addition to their empowerment arsenal.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">RRMCH has got <a title="best Gynecologist in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best gynecologist in Bangalore</a> and the department provides the best treatment for women health care. RRMCH provides regular<a title="health care services in india" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/health-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> clinical services</a> as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Ongoing Trends in Healthcare Sector</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-ongoing-trends-in-healthcare-sector/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 05:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=912</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Gone are the times when healthcare sector had a reputation of almost negative customer experiences. Nowadays, healthcare companies are going all guns blazing about their approach towards their customers. The approach also includes the optimum use of advanced technology besides newer approaches in-order to create a progressive change in the healthcare industry. Let us run &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-ongoing-trends-in-healthcare-sector/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Top 5 Ongoing Trends in Healthcare Sector"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Gone are the times when healthcare sector had a reputation of almost negative customer experiences. Nowadays, healthcare companies are going all guns blazing about their approach towards their customers. The approach also includes the optimum use of advanced technology besides newer approaches in-order to create a progressive change in the healthcare industry. Let us run through some of the upcoming trends in the healthcare eco-system.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-913 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1.jpg" alt="Trends in Healthcare Sector" width="600" height="300" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Trends-in-Healthcare-Sector-1-300x150.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tailored Medicine</strong> – Medicine is all about observation based diagnosis with evidence to support the same. Today, <a title="Health care Services in India" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/patientsvisitors/health-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">healthcare centers</a> are equipped with the latest in technology that results into accurate and speedy diagnosis. For example, with the help of radiology clinicians can investigate structures deep inside the body and with techniques like histopathology, clinicians can identify virus and tumors using microscopes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Virtual Reality</strong> &#8211; Virtual reality is working well in the management and treatment of pain. As per a study of the recent times, children responded to chemotherapy better when they played games while undergoing the same. This was because their attention got concentrated from the treatment part to the play part and hence even resulted in them requiring less dosage. Side effects like nausea and hypertension were also reduced compared to children who were advised to rest.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Patient Customization</strong> &#8211; Data has grown and so has the ability of the healthcare facilities to provide their customers with an experience that is absolutely personalized. Based on the history of the patient, these clinics provide facilities like potential health issues, doctors preferred by the patient, patient preference in terms of remote treatment or walk in, to name a few. This can help avoid the complexities involved with the navigation through health care professional web and makes patients information available readily for speedy and accurate treatment solutions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Augmented Reality</strong> – Besides other fields, augmented reality is playing a crucial role in healthcare and is fast turning out to be one of the most effective applications in medical training. AR helps doctors while monitoring diagnosis with the treatment procedure options to look forward too. They don’t have to spend time in honing their medical knowledge further because treatment options can simply pop up on their screen with options and suggestions. For example, while doing a child checkup the growth chart can pop up on the monitor itself, thus helping the doctor with seamless treatment procedures.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Smart Technology in Hospitals</strong> – <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Smart Technology in Hospitals</a> has actually helped better patient experience, comfort, and care. For example, many hospitals have started using smart technology in hospitals. In a few countries, certain healthcare outfits use self-adjusting beds for pressure and support customization for patients. Many are also making use of man free facilities where robots carry out the monitoring process of the patient in the room. Smart technology is available in different forms and works in reducing risks while increasing comfort and efficiency. Affirmatively, the use of smart technology across the healthcare ecosystem is poised to grow day by day, obviously so.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Pregnancy Complications To Be Aware Of</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-pregnancy-complications-to-be-aware-of/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 08:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top 5 Pregnancy Complications]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=889</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The news of pregnancy brings in smiles on the faces of the family members. On the flip side, during the three trimesters, you need to be on your toes and all alert because pregnancy can cause complications if proper care is not taken. Though you are going to be under the scanner all through the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-pregnancy-complications-to-be-aware-of/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Top 5 Pregnancy Complications To Be Aware Of"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The news of pregnancy brings in smiles on the faces of the family members. On the flip side, during the three trimesters, you need to be on your toes and all alert because pregnancy can cause complications if proper care is not taken. Though you are going to be under the scanner all through the pregnancy cycle and your doctor is going to get you tested on various complications, you yourself need to be aware of them and take self-care to keep them at bay.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Here is a run through <em>some complications of pregnancy</em> that can be life threatening to the fetus and the mom as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Top-5-Pregnancy-Complications-To-Be-Aware-Of-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-890 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Top-5-Pregnancy-Complications-To-Be-Aware-Of-1.jpg" alt="Top 5 Pregnancy Complications To Be Aware Of" width="299" height="168" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Pre-eclampisa</strong> &#8211; It is the almost rare condition in pregnancy because it usually affects only 5 % of the pregnant women in India. This condition is caused by high level of proteins in the urine, high blood pressure or kidney conditions post 20 weeks of pregnancy.<br />
Care needs to be taken to be aware and act promptly by the doctor if there are even mild symptoms of it because it can progress fast and can be life-threatening to the baby and the mother too. The solution to it is early delivery.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Gestational Diabetes</strong> &#8211; This is one of the common conditions occurring in pregnant women in India. Around 10% women could be prey to this condition that can be diagnosed during 24-28 weeks of pregnancy. Post-diagnosis your blood sugar levels will be monitored on a regular basis. Most of them with mild conditions manage to keep it at bay through exercise and diet and are able to deliver healthy babies without complications. But, care needs to be taken to avoid it from aggravating because it can then cause serious harm to the fetus.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Placenta Previa</strong> – This condition can cause complications towards the end of pregnancy not in the early stages. Hence, the doctors check the location and placement of your placenta with a sonography test during the second     tri-semester. 1 in 200 women suffer from this condition and it can be quite dangerous if the placenta is at extremely low levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Miscarriage</strong> – One of the most dreaded conditions which can only be avoided by taking proper care, miscarriage is caused in the first 20 weeks. This is common with Indian women and 20% of them experience this condition within 12 weeks mostly. The symptoms of it include spotting and bleeding at the vagina. The doctor does a sonography to check for the condition.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Premature Delivery</strong> – Premature delivery is when the cervix opens before 37 weeks of pregnancy. If the delivery happens too early then it can be life-threatening for the baby, so care needs to be taken to avoid it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The <a title="best Gynecologist in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">department of Obstetrics and Gynecology</a> has been providing comprehensive health care for women. We provide regular clinical services in Obstetrics like antenatal care, labor management, postpartum Care. We also provide specialized care in high risk pregnancies like P.I.H, Eclampsia, GDM, Multiple gestations, BOH. With the backup of NICU, we are able to salvage preterm babies of 30 weeks on wards. Highly qualified doctors, with the help of well equipped labor ward, conduct normal and caesarian deliveries</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
