<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Worlds Breast Feeding Week &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/worlds-breast-feeding-week/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 08:55:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Worlds Breastfeeding Week &#8211; RRMCH Bangalore</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/worlds-breastfeeding-week-2017/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 08:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of pediatrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worlds Breast Feeding Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=751</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[RRMCH, Department of Pediatrics celebrated the “Worlds Breast Feeding Week” from 1st Aug 2017 to 7th Aug 2017. World breast feeding week 2017 has been observed in department, under the guidance of Dr. Adarsh, Prof and HOD, Department of pediatrics RRMCH. We also celebrated one year anniversary of our Human Milk Bank. 1st August 2017 we had &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/worlds-breastfeeding-week-2017/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Worlds Breastfeeding Week &#8211; RRMCH Bangalore"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">RRMCH, Department of Pediatrics celebrated the <b>“Worlds Breast Feeding Week”</b> from 1st Aug 2017 to 7th Aug 2017.</p>
<p>World breast feeding week 2017 has been observed in department, under the guidance of Dr. Adarsh, Prof and HOD, Department of pediatrics RRMCH. We also celebrated one year anniversary of our Human Milk Bank.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Worlds-Breast-Feeding-Week-Aug-1-to-7-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-752 size-large" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Worlds-Breast-Feeding-Week-Aug-1-to-7-1-1024x576.jpg" alt="Worlds Breast Feeding Week" width="615" height="345" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Worlds-Breast-Feeding-Week-Aug-1-to-7-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Worlds-Breast-Feeding-Week-Aug-1-to-7-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Worlds-Breast-Feeding-Week-Aug-1-to-7-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Worlds-Breast-Feeding-Week-Aug-1-to-7-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" /></a></p>
<p>1st August 2017 we had inauguration of world breastfeeding week in pediatric OPD at 11am. Started with lighting of the lamp from Dr. Govindaraju, Medical Superintendent, Dr. Adarsh, prof and HOD of pediatrics, Dr. R.Prema, Professor of Pediatrics, Dr. Shashikala, Prof and HOD of community medicine, Dr. Nagarathanna ,Prof and HOD of OBG, RRMCH.</p>
<p>02nd August 2017, we went to the community camp in rural health training centre in Chunchunkuppe. We organized programme for the breastfeeding mother in our community health centre. We shared the thoughts with mothers regarding breastfeeding and importance of it, Dr. Sahana Associate Professor and Dr. Yashitha Junior Resident, narrated about the theme “A Sustaining breastfeeding together” to the mothers.</p>
<p>03rd of august 2017 we conducted the quiz competition regarding the breast feeding for postgraduates of pediatrics, OBG,P&amp;SM and medical students of our college, there was tough competition between all 5teams, and the winners were Dr. Vidhi and Dr. Apoorva from department of pediatrics.</p>
<p>4th August 2017, we had collage competition regarding the breastfeeding for medical students and nursing students, Out of 5 teams participated in the competition nursing students were emerged as winner.</p>
<p>5th August 2017, we oriented the mothers in PNC regarding the importance of Breastfeeding. We also narrated about the theme “A Sustaining breastfeeding together” to the mothers. Our breastfeeding counselor S/n Thayimudamma demonstrated the techniques of breast feeding and had interaction session.</p>
<p>7th August 2017 the breastfeeding awareness skit was presented by 3 groups from community medicine, 7th term medical Students and Nursing Students participated.<br />
We conclude the programme, World breastfeeding week 2017 with great success.</p>
<p>We celebrated ORS day on 29 July 2017, programme was conducted in our OPD and pediatric wards to highlight the importance of Oral Rehydration Salts (ORS) and its significance in the treatment of dehydration.</p>
<p>Excessive loss of fluids and electrolytes in the body causes dehydration. Conditions like vomiting, diarrhea, and diseases which cause diarrhea such as bacterial or viral infection, cholera, food poisoning, unhygienic feeding practices can increase the chances of dehydration.</p>
<p>Dr. Adarsh, Prof and HOD had inaugurated the programme. We created the awareness programme in parents and distributed the ORS to the children.</p>
<p>This programme helped the parents to know more about dehydration difficulties and how to prevent the problem.</p>
<p>We gave a demo on How to make the ORS drink which is available in powder form?</p>
<p>1.Put the contents of the ORS packet in a clean container. Check the packet for directions and add the amount of clean water as indicated. Too little water could make the diarrhea worse.</p>
<p>2.Add water only. Do not add ORS to milk, soup, fruit juice or any soft drinks. Do not add sugar.</p>
<p>3.Stir well, and feed it to the child from a clean cup. Do not use a bottle.</p>
<h4>ORS Day</h4>
<p>ORS Day is celebrated every year on 29th July to highlight the importance of Oral Rehydration Salts (ORS) as a cost-effective method of health intervention. Acute diarrhoeal diseases are one of the leading causes of mortality in infants and young children in many developing countries. According to WHO, Diarrhoeal disease is the second leading cause of death in children under five years old. Diarrhoea, which is frequently caused by poor sanitation and hygiene, can have serious, even deadly results, typically as a result of diarrhoea-related dehydration. It particularly affects infants, children and old people. Diarrhoea generally lasts for several days, and leaves the body without water and salts that are necessary for survival. Most people who die from diarrhoea actually die from severe dehydration and fluid loss from the body.</p>
<p>Dehydration from diarrhoea can be prevented by giving extra fluids at home, or it can be treated simply and effectively by giving adequate glucose-electrolyte solution called<strong> Oral Rehydration Salts</strong> (ORS) solution. ORS Jodi (ORS and Zinc) has proven to be successful in the prevention and management of acute diarrhoea and dehydration. Oral rehydration salts contain a variety of salts (electrolytes) and sugar. The combination of electrolytes and sugar stimulates water and electrolyte absorption from the gut. It therefore prevents or reverses dehydration and replaces lost salts in conditions such as diarrhoea and vomiting.ORS is available in the market in a powder form in sachets/ readymade solutions or one can also easily make it at home as well.</p>
<p><b>All we need to know:</b><br />
How to make the ORS drink which is available in powder form?</p>
<p>4.Put the contents of the ORS packet in a clean container. Check the packet for directions and add the amount of clean water as indicated. Too little water could make the diarrhea worse.</p>
<p>5.Add water only. Do not add ORS to milk, soup, fruit juice or any soft drinks. Do not add sugar.</p>
<p>6.Stir well, and feed it to the child from a clean cup. Do not use a bottle.</p>
<p>World Breastfeeding Week is an annual celebration which is being held every year from 1to 7 August in many countries all over the world and since past three years ADK Hospital has continued the celebration of this week. World Breastfeeding week is celebrated with the goal to promote exclusive breastfeeding for the first six months of life which gives tremendous benefits to baby as well as to the mother.</p>
<p>The<strong> World Health Organization</strong> (WHO), <strong>American Academy of Pediatrics</strong> (AAP) and the <strong>World Alliance for Breastfeeding Action</strong> (WABA) recommends exclusive breastfeeding for the first six months of life and then supplemented breastfeeding up to two years or more.</p>
<p>Theme for World Breastfeeding Week 2016 is “A Key to Sustainable Development”, which is focusing on the importance of breastfeeding and promote breastfeeding as key element in getting us to think about how to value our wellbeing from the start of life, how to respect each other and care for the world we share.</p>
<p>Below are the activities initiated by nurses in ADK Hospital for celebrating world breastfeeding week 2016.</p>
<ul>
<li>Breastfeeding refresher workshop for nurses- 1st – 2nd August</li>
<li>Visit postnatal inpatients for breastfeeding counseling – 1st – 7th August</li>
<li>Display posters &amp; breastfeeding week theme at Information Counter- 1st – 7th August</li>
<li>Inauguration of breastfeeding booklet &amp; leaflet – 2nd August</li>
<li>Visit postnatal mothers who are planned to get discharged from hospital to give breastfeeding counseling – 3rd August</li>
<li>Breastfeeding quiz between inter-nursing units – 4th August</li>
<li>Session on breastfeeding for antenatal, postnatal mothers &amp; for ADK staff – 6th August</li>
<li>Breastfeeding committee launching – 7th August</li>
</ul>
<p><a title="Department of Paediatrics at RRMCH" href="http://college.rrmch.org/department/paediatrics/" target="_blank">Department of Paediatrics</a> at <a title="Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> ,Well equipped department with skilled pediatrician teaching staff and state of the art ICU care</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
