<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>emergency medical services &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/emergency-medical-services/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 09:47:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 09:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Role Of Legumes In Heart Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1245</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes. Though it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual basis. But, recently &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer
by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find
out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes.  Though
it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual
basis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1246" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>Five color legumes for healthy , Soy bean, Navy bean or white bean, Black beam, Red bean and Green bean,</figcaption></figure>



<p>But,
recently researchers of the review called Advances in Nutrition took
up the task of understanding the significance of legumes like
lentils, peas and beans etc. around heart health. 
</p>



<p>Primarily, they focused on cardiovascular diseases like <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">coronary heart</a> disease, stroke, myocardial infarction besides looking into hypertension, obesity and diabetes. They chose cardiovascular diseases because it is one of the most common causes of mortality and even one of the most expensive ones. It is known to cause US 1 billion dollars a day. </p>



<p>They
used the data analysis of Eurpoean Association which recently carried
out a series of systematic reviews as well as meta-analysis for
Diabetics study. The researchers hope that these results could be
quite a help in updating the recommendations already made around the
role of legumes in preventing as well as treating cardio-metabolic
diseases. 
</p>



<p>The
data review and comparison with people with lowest and highest intake
of legumes revealed that dietary pulses that had legumes which either
did or did not include other legumes did decrease coronary heart
disease, obesity incidence and hypertension. 
</p>



<p>
Though the researchers were able to find a positive relationship
between intake of legumes in higher amounts and reduction in certain
parameters related to cardiovascular risks, the conclusion they came
to are muted relatively. 
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers “The overall certainty of the evidence was
graded as low for CVD incidence and ‘very low for all the other
outcomes.” 
</p>



<p>Therefore, the co author of the study Dr Hana Kahleova said “ Americans eat less than one serving of legumes per day, on average. Simply adding more beans to our plates could be a powerful tool in fighting heart disease and bringing down blood pressure.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><strong>Best Cardiologist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 09:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1213</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market of heart conditions. As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers
in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports
in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus
reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market
of heart conditions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1214" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png 620w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits-300x179.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></figure>



<p> As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">cardiovascular</a> conditions increases significantly in women and lipid profile is a reliable marker to measure heart health.  He and his colleagues investigated around 193 menopausal women participants of the age group 47-55 from Finland, registered for the Estrogenic Regulation of Muscle Apoptosis (ERMA) study.  The study is co-authored by Dr Mathew Jergenson of Minnesota Medical School and University in Minneapolis. The reason behind conducting the study as per him was to explore if physical activity did have a role in cardiovascular risk factors.  </p>



<p>
He says “It is well known that physical activity has health
benefits, yet it is less clear to what extent physical activity
prevents negative changes in lipid profile while women are in their
menopausal transition.  The participants were monitored for physical
activity levels in leisure time, generally and specifically also,
using accelerometers and had to answer questions as well.</p>



<p>
Leisure is the time that is not related to routine daily work be it
housework or commuting and includes sport or recreation activities in
free time. 
</p>



<p>The
researchers found out that there was indeed a connection between more
activities during leisure time and lowering of cholesterol levels
particularly (LDL) as well as with high levels of cholesterol (HDL). 
Karvin reports that indeed the leisure time physical activities were
related to healthy lipid profiles. But, that does not mean that the
negative changes in lipid profile during menopause can be fully done
away with due to leisure time sports activities. 
</p>



<p>The author also said that leisure time physical activities will underscore the adverse atherogenic changes in the cardiovascular risk factors in middle aged women who are healthy. Hence, sport related activities in leisure are good.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is having <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/"><strong>Top most Physiotherapist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1209</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them. It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them.  It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of us know that a declining oral health could be an indication of other risky health conditions that can also affect the quality of life of a human being.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1210" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>An article published in the <a href="http://www.jisponline.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology (opens in a new tab)">Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology</a> shows that there is a link between tooth loss as well as gum disease with stroke occurrence.  </p>



<p>As
per the conclusions of this article of 2010, gum disease is
responsible for increase in the risk of heart attack by 20%. Well,
there’s another team at the University of New Brunswick, NJ are
focusing on a connection between oral health and cognitive decline. 
</p>



<p>Even
a research team from Rutgers University carried out a two separate
studies around perceived stress and cognitive decline and published
the reports of two separate studies in the Journal of American
Geriatrics Society.</p>



<p>Talking
about other parts of the world like for example China, XinQi Dong,
the director of Rutgers University’s Institute for Health,
healthcare policy and aging research says that in china it was the
ethnic and racial minorities who were typically vulnerable to
consequences of poor oral health.  The reason being that already
there are barriers like socio economic status and language plus
access to preventive dental care is less. Particularly, the old
Chinese Americans are at a risk of oral health problems because of
lack of regular dental checkup and dental insurance. These studies
were carried out on Chinese elderly in Chicago of 60 years and above
age. The study involved quizzing question around oral health and then
asking them to complete five cognitive tests.  The second study asked
people if they had faced issues like dry mouth besides measuring
their social strain levels, social support and perceived stress with
the help of pre-defined scales. 
</p>



<p>The study involved 2700 Chinese Americans and results revealed that around half of them did had symptoms of tooth related issues. Also, there was not significant relationship between congnitive issues and gums but researchers believe that the participants may not have reported gum problems and ignored them as they do not cause major problems to health.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a> is one of the <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/">best neuro hospital in india</a></strong> </p>



<p>know more about <a href="https://www.rrdch.org"><strong>Top Dental Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Omega 3 Fatty Acids And Health Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/omega-3-fatty-acids-and-health-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 10:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good medical colleges in bangalore]]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1199</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Some of us are definitely aware of omega 3 fatty acids and their benefits. But, many of us are not aware that fatty acids are present not only in animals but plants also. The animal based fatty acids include doosahexaenoic acid (DHA) as well as eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA). While the animal based omega 3 fatty &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/omega-3-fatty-acids-and-health-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Omega 3 Fatty Acids And Health Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Some
of us are definitely aware of omega 3 fatty acids and their benefits.
 But, many of us are not aware that fatty acids are present not only
in animals but plants also. The animal based fatty acids include
doosahexaenoic acid (DHA) as well as eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA).
While the animal based omega 3 fatty acids comes from fish oils,
plant based come from plant sources. These sources contain
alpha-lionelic acid (ALA), that can be converted into Omega-3 fatty
acids of the body. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Omega-3-Fatty-Acids-And-Health-Benefits.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1200" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Omega-3-Fatty-Acids-And-Health-Benefits.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Omega-3-Fatty-Acids-And-Health-Benefits-300x156.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Omega-3-Fatty-Acids-And-Health-Benefits-768x399.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>But,
most of us are only aware about the health benefits of animal based
fish oils with EPA and DHA. But, many of us again aren’t aware
about the amount of omega 3, fatty acids that our body requires, even
though there is no set standard for intake of the same. 
</p>



<p>Many
experts believe and recommend omega 3 fatty acids for people
suffering from cardiovascular conditions particularly higher doses
for people having high cholesterol levels. Prescribed medications
that are FDA approved are available for people with conditions rather
than the supplements. 
</p>



<p>Omega
3 acids are recommended only for adults and children should not be
given any supplements of omega 3 acids before consulting the doctor.
Though natural sources of omega 3 fatty acids can be consumed by all
irrespective of ages, only if you have no significant allergies
around the same. 
</p>



<p>Natural
Sources of omega 3 fatty acids include Cod liver, Soybeans and tofu,
Walnuts, Salmon, trout, tuna and sardines, to name a few. The
international organization AHA recommends adults for males and
females except pregnant women to increase the intake of omega 3 fatty
acids 
</p>



<p>Even
avoiding the intake of omega 6 fatty acids that include eggs, meat as
well as oil can help in increasing the levels of omega 3 fatty acids
in blood. Balancing of omega 3 fatty acids to that of omega 6 can
help you manage many health conditions in a better way and reduce the
risk of certain conditions as well. As per reports people in USA
consume 14-25 times more omega 6 fatty acids as compared to omega 3
fatty acids and this imbalance is not good for health, certainly. 
</p>



<p> Having said that, omega 3 fatty acids  supplements should not be consumed without consulting your physician because they do have certain side effects particularly pregnant women with a diabetes risk should avoid them.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><strong>Best Cardiologist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Changes In Diet That Help You Reduce The Risk Of Cancer</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/changes-in-diet-that-help-you-reduce-the-risk-of-cancer/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1179</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As per statistics cancer is the causes the second highest number of deaths in India every year. Out of the 9.6 mn, over 8% are from India. Well, that’s not a small number. One of the most common cancers in India today is breast cancer. We all know that with all the innovations and advances &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/changes-in-diet-that-help-you-reduce-the-risk-of-cancer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Changes In Diet That Help You Reduce The Risk Of Cancer"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As
per statistics cancer is the causes the second highest number of
deaths in India every year.  Out of the 9.6 mn, over 8% are from
India. Well, that’s not a small number. One of the most common
cancers in India today is breast cancer. We all know that with all
the innovations and advances in Science, even today cancer does
affect the life expectancy negatively and also quality of life. So,
trying to prevent it seems a better idea. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1180" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer-300x160.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Diet-Plan-Risk-Of-Cancer-768x409.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>A
new study has revealed that the foods that are rich in flavonoids are
helpful in decreasing the risk of cancer and extending longevity. The
study was carried out over 50,000 participants across a span of 20
years. Finding out the impact of single compounds on health
conditions as well as mortality is not an easy study, even though
food does form the most important part of our lives.  
</p>



<p>Researchers
have already brought to light that eating vegetables and fruits
factually reduce the risk of cardiovascular conditions and increase
life span too. Though, the details on how they do it is under
research phase yet. Many researchers believe that it is rich in
flavonoids play a vital role in the same. 
</p>



<p>Flavonoids
are found in different natural food likes vegetables, dark
chocolates, fruits and tea are form a chemical class known as
polyphenols. These compounds are further divided into six sub classes
namely Flavonols, flavanones, flavan-3-ols, anthocyanins, flavones
and isoflavones.</p>



<p>A group of scientists from Edith Cowan University of Australia did begin a research in order to find out how the compounds could help increasing life span and help protect against health conditions. They also wanted to look into the effects of alcohol and smoking around the benefits of flavonoids. For investigation of the same, the scientists used the Danish Diet data of over 56048 adults across 23 years. During the process over 14083 participants passed away too. The researchers concluded that it was true that flavonoid rich diets with individual flavonoid subclasses do actually reduce the risk of cancer and cardiovascular diseases also increasing longevity.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/"><strong>Best Cancer Hospital Treatment in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Second Hand Smoke Is Also Dangerous To Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/second-hand-smoke-is-also-dangerous-to-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 09:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second hand smoke]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1169</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We are aware how dangerous smoking is for health, but second hand smoke viz. the smoke that we inhale when someone else is smoking could be life threatening too. As per statistics second hand smoke is known to cause over 3000 deaths due to heart disease to non-smokers. Second hand smoke can be particularly harmful &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/second-hand-smoke-is-also-dangerous-to-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Second Hand Smoke Is Also Dangerous To Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
are aware how dangerous smoking is for health, but second hand smoke
viz. the smoke that we inhale when someone else is smoking could be
life threatening too. As per statistics second hand smoke is known to
cause over 3000 deaths due to heart disease to non-smokers. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1170" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health.jpg 948w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Second-Hand-Smoke-Is-Also-Dangerous-To-Health-768x575.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>Second
hand smoke can be particularly harmful to children because their
lungs are still under development.   Many children inhale this
dangerous smoke at home if their parents or family members smoke,
primarily. Even parents who smoke outside risk their children to
harmful chemicals because of second hand smoke. 
</p>



<p>Also,
known as environmental tobacco smoke, the smoke that is breathed out
as well as the smoke that is released from pipes, cigars, burning
cigarettes, cigars or pipes contains around 4000 chemicals. Almost 50
of these chemicals are carcinogenic and are known to increase the
risk of cancer. 
</p>



<p>The
American Academy of pediatrics (AAP) did a research on third hand
smoke also. Third hand smoke is the smoke that is left behind in
areas where people smoke. Though people leave the place after
smoking, the harmful toxins remain for a while for example in bars,
upholstery, even child’s hair if the care taker smokes. 
</p>



<p>Well,
second hand smoke and third hand smoke both are harmful to adults,
children and even the unborn developing ones. Unborn and children are
at a higher risk. Children whose parents smoke cough more than
children generally do. They are at the risk of getting coughs and
colds, tooth decay, ear infections and respiratory problems. Children
suffering from asthma are particularly prone to second hand smoke as
it can lead to asthma attacks that to frequent and severe leading to
a rise in hospital visits. 
</p>



<p>Well, so if you think that only smoking is injuries to health, you are certainly not right, its also the people around the smokers that are at the risk inspite of being not guilty of smoking. Take care. Quit now.</p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Private Medical Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Encephalitis (CHAMKI Fever) The Deadly Fever That Has Killed Over 150 Children In Bihar And Jharkhand Already</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/encephalitis-chamki-fever-the-deadly-fever-that-has-killed-over-150-children-in-bihar-and-jharkhand-already/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 11:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood banks in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1145</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The news of around 150 children dead due to the chamki fever is already a topic of concern present day. The Supreme Court also has taken notice of this serious or grave situation and directed Center to immediately form a medical expert team for the treatment of children having AES. An inflammation of brain, encephalitis &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/encephalitis-chamki-fever-the-deadly-fever-that-has-killed-over-150-children-in-bihar-and-jharkhand-already/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Encephalitis (CHAMKI Fever) The Deadly Fever That Has Killed Over 150 Children In Bihar And Jharkhand Already"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The
news of around 150 children dead due to the chamki fever is already a
topic of concern present day. The Supreme Court also has taken notice
of this serious or grave situation and directed Center to immediately
form a medical expert team for the treatment of children having AES. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1146" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar.jpg 700w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/encephalitis-deaths-in-Bihar-300x172.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /></figure>



<p>An
inflammation of brain, encephalitis commonly known as chamki fever is
the inflammation of brain. It is caused by viral infection and
affects the nervous system. There are two main types of Encephalitis
namely Primary and Secondary. This fever usually occurs in kids and
youngsters below 15 years of age.   
</p>



<p>The
primary is caused due to direct viral infection to the brain while
secondary is a result of a weak immune system and can be a result of
infection in any part of the body.  Presently, there’s an outbreak
of this fever in Bihar and Jharkhand. Recently, even Bengal has
reported three cases of AES or Chamki of which one is critical.  
</p>



<p><strong>Causes
</strong>
</p>



<p>AES
is known to be a viral infection but can occur due to mosquito borne
viruses, Zika or Nipah Virus, Rabis virus, childhood infections,
enteroviruses and herpes virus as well. In India the most commonly
known AES causing virus is the Japanese Encephalitis (JE) as almost 5
-35% cases are that of JE Virus AES. Though, this year only two cases
are due to the JE Virus and exact cause of so many deaths is not
known. What is known is that the deaths were caused by hypoglycemia
(low blood sugar levels) 
</p>



<p>
<strong>Symptoms </strong>
</p>



<p>At
the initial stage the symptoms are similar to mild flu and include
fever, headache, fatigue, muscle or joint pain. Though in the later
or severe stage it leads to hallucinations, agitation, confusion,
muscle weakness, hearing difficulties paralysis, sensation loss,
vomiting, poor eating, body stiffness, skull bulging and more.    
</p>



<p><strong>Treatment
</strong>
</p>



<p>There
is not medicine yet for this fever and the mild one can be brought
down through adequate rest and continuous fluid intake. Drugs like
Tylenol, Aleve and Advil also can be used. Medications like Foscavir,
Cytoven and Zovirax can be used for the viral Encephalitis only on
prescription basis. Do not consume any medications with Doctors
consult. At times supportive care like breathing assistance,
intravenous fluids to keep the person hydrated, anti-convulsant and
anti-inflammatory drugs against seizures and swelling could be
required. 
</p>



<p><strong>Prevention
</strong>
</p>



<p>Prevention is always better and hence to avoid getting this condition try to maintain hygiene at home, clean your hands properly after you visit the toilet and before eating food. Also, drink clean water and use mosquito nets and repellants when sleeping.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about The  <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>On World Heart Day Decide on a Healthy Oil for Cooking</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/on-world-heart-day-decide-on-a-healthy-oil-for-cooking/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 09:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1029</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[It is not secret that India tops the list of mortalities due to cardiac arrests and diseases. The reasons obviously point out to many, and unhealthy lifestyle is one of the main ones. A healthy lifestyle is an amalgamation of a balanced diet, a fitness regime that is followed on a regular basis and addiction &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/on-world-heart-day-decide-on-a-healthy-oil-for-cooking/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "On World Heart Day Decide on a Healthy Oil for Cooking"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">It is not secret that India tops the list of mortalities due to cardiac arrests and diseases. The reasons obviously point out to many, and unhealthy lifestyle is one of the main ones. A healthy lifestyle is an amalgamation of a balanced diet, a fitness regime that is followed on a regular basis and addiction free. As per a leading nutritionist, though food forms a significant part of your lifestyle, it’s not just about the type of food that is consumed. A lot of things are associated with food, it’s the way the food is cooked, served, consumed as well as the time when you consume it.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1030" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/World-Heart-Day-Healthy-Oil-for-Cooking.jpg" alt="On World Heart Day Decide on a Healthy Oil for Cooking" width="732" height="549" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/World-Heart-Day-Healthy-Oil-for-Cooking.jpg 732w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/World-Heart-Day-Healthy-Oil-for-Cooking-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also, when anyone says oil, everyone seems to be rolling their eyes because, we feel that the real culprit of your unhealthy body is the oil. But, the fact is that oil is not bad as you would imagine it to be. It is a mix of different kinds of fats. Also, a healthy oil is a mixture of different kinds of fats. Hence, when you select your oil, it’s important that you check for a balance between the essential fats of it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Here are a few tips to help you out with selection of a healthy oil for healthy cooking – </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Loaded with Mono-saturated Fats</strong> – Mono-saturated fats are good for health and hence it’s good to choose an oil that is rich in mono-saturated fats. These fats solidify when kept in the fridge and transform into liquid when at room temperature.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>More of Polyunsaturated fats</strong> – Poly unsaturated fats contain Omega 3 and Omega 6, which happen to be vital for the body. We all know that omega 3 is responsible for protecting our body against inflammation, thus protecting us against diseases. Our body is not capable of producing them and hence we need it to be there in our diet. Though Omega 3 is what we need more than omega 6, precisely in a ratio of 1:2 or 1:4.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Less of Trans Fats</strong> – Trans-fat are highly harmful to the body. To say the least, its best to avoid this fat. Trans-fats are formed when poly-saturated fats are transformed into solid. These fats are leading causes of heart diseases, high cholesterol as well as cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Less of Saturated Fats</strong>&#8211; Saturated fats are known to be bad fat but apparently they come under the neutral category. You can have an intake of saturated fat but in limit. They are good but not as good as mono-saturated fat. Also, the bad saturated fats are the hydrogenated saturated fats that are man-made.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lastly, fat is bad only when it is consumed in a quantity that is more than required. So, controlling eating habits is the key to healthy body.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>RajaRajeswari hospital</strong></a> is having one of the <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best Cardiologist in Bangalore</a></strong>, It provides all types of cardiology services with cutting edge facilities advance cardiac</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>SriDevi &#8211; A Victim of Sudden Cardiac Arrest &#8211; Know About Sudden Onset</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sridevi-a-victim-of-sudden-cardiac-arrest/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 11:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=800</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The legendary actoress, a versatile actor, a super star, epitome of grace – Sridevi left every fan of hers across the world in shock as she made her way to the heavenly abode. Only 54 years of age, a fitness freak, one who maintained a healthy lifestyle all through her life passed away in such &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sridevi-a-victim-of-sudden-cardiac-arrest/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "SriDevi &#8211; A Victim of Sudden Cardiac Arrest &#8211; Know About Sudden Onset"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The legendary actoress, a versatile actor, a super star, epitome of grace – Sridevi left every fan of hers across the world in shock as she made her way to the heavenly abode. Only 54 years of age, a fitness freak, one who maintained a healthy lifestyle all through her life passed away in such a shocker, all of a sudden cardiac arrest of massive nature.</p>
<p>It took so much time to come to terms with this saddening or heart wrenching fact and still is unbelievable because we lost her at such a young age of 54, in a film industry where actors like Salman, Shahrukh and Amir at 50 are still playing lead roles and setting the box office on fire with hundreds of crores their films rake in when they release.<br />
Now that we know that sudden cardiac arrest can happen irrespective of aging here is a short note on what it is all about, the symptoms and treatment.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sudden-cardiac-arrest-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-801 size-large" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sudden-cardiac-arrest-1-1024x559.jpg" alt="sudden-cardiac-arrest" width="615" height="335" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sudden-cardiac-arrest-1-1024x559.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sudden-cardiac-arrest-1-300x164.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sudden-cardiac-arrest-1-768x420.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sudden-cardiac-arrest-1.jpg 1089w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Sudden Cardiac Arrest</strong> – It occurs all of a sudden without a clear sign. Symptoms might be there but not indicating clearly of a heart issue. In a sudden cardiac arrest case, the heart stops functioning suddenly due to some disturbance and disrupts blood flow. The blood supply to heart as a result is cut off. Sudden cardiac arrest requires prompt medical intervention in order to increase survival chances.</p>
<p><strong>Symptoms</strong> – The symptoms usually are not very clear and may be underlying. This symptoms include Dizziness or fatigue, shortness of breath, heart palpitations and chest pain around 4 weeks before the attack. The symptoms vary in men and women. People who suffer from chest pain may have it secondary accompanied with primary pain of head, shoulder and neck or back.</p>
<p><strong>Risk Factors</strong><br />
Though sudden cardiac arrest occurs out of the blue without clear signs, some risk factors responsible on a long run include diabetes, high cholesterol levels, smoking, obesity and high blood pressure to name a few. Sometimes genetics is also responsible for causing a sudden arrest to people who are fit and have no medical history of heart disease like Sridevi’s case.</p>
<p><strong>Treatment</strong> – Sudden Cardiac arrest is a highly life threatening condition which can lead to death in most cases if not given immediate medical aid. You need to offer CPR as primary treatment or use a defibrillator for the same. You can even give chest compressions until the help arrives. If medical aid is provided instantly and properly, survival is possible.</p>
<p>Well, it&#8217;s advisable to follow a healthy lifestyle and go for a routine checkup one every year once you cross 50 years of age.</p>
<p><a title="Best Cardiology Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/cms/pdf/e-brochure/RRHC%20Brochure.pdf" target="_blank">Rajarajeswari Heart Center</a>, part of the esteem institute, <a title="Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Rajarajeswari Medical College &amp; Hospital</a>. Was established in May 2012 as an initial non-interventional department with 2D echocardiography, Treadmill Test and cardiac consultation</p>
<p>*source from the internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dementia Risk and Blood Magnesium Levels</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dementia-risk-and-blood-magnesium-levels/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 06:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best psychiatrist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood banks in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dementia Risk and Blood Magnesium Levels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rajarajeswari hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=710</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Before we talk about risk factors associated with dementia lets just polish our information around the condition. This condition usually occurs at an older age and causes memory loss. Alzheimers is one of the most common forms of dementia known. Apparently, its not a condition by a symptoms or group of symptoms rather. You should &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dementia-risk-and-blood-magnesium-levels/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dementia Risk and Blood Magnesium Levels"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Before we talk about risk factors associated with dementia lets just polish our information around the condition. This condition usually occurs at an older age and causes memory loss. Alzheimers is one of the most common forms of dementia known. Apparently, its not a condition by a symptoms or group of symptoms rather. You should also know that it does hamper our day to day routines because we tend to forget a lot. Dementia symptoms are also caused due to vitamin deficiencies and thyroid problems. Dementia occurs due to brain cell damage and most of them are generally permanent or increase with time.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Dementia-Risk-and-Blood-Magnesium-Levels-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-711" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Dementia-Risk-and-Blood-Magnesium-Levels-1-1.jpg" alt="Dementia Risk and Blood Magnesium Levels" width="600" height="320" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Now, a study has found out that the levels of magnesium in your blood can associated to the risk of dementia later in life. The people with lower or higher levels of minerals in the body were subject to dementia more compared to the ones with middle levels. It has yet to be proved and nowhere confirm that it causes dementia but definitely magnesium levels do have a link with dementia. There are apparently two ways in which magnesium levels could be called as risk factor for dementia.</p>
<p align="justify">Coming back to the study, around 10,000 participant around 65 years of age were studied across 8 years span and their magnesium levels were checked at the beginning of the test. They were divided in 5 groups. The study findings showed that those with low and high level magnesium had 30% greater risk of dementia compared to mid level magnesium level participants. The lower and higher magnesium range is below 0.85 millimoles per liter and 1.10 mmol/L respectively. Though as the magnesium levels were not measure post eight years the results could have associated limitations.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, to prove that magnesium levels do determine the risk of dementia in later stages of life, further detailed study is required.</p>
<p align="justify">Know about <a title="Blood Banks in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/giving/donate-blood/" target="_blank">Blood Banks in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
