<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>best cancer hospitals in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/best-cancer-hospitals-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 11:35:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Depression and Anxiety can be as Harmful to Health as Smoking</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/depression-and-anxiety-can-be-as-harmful-to-health-as-smoking/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 11:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Depression and Anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1068</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A recent study has revealed that people who have high anxiety levels as well as depression are at 65% higher risk of developing a heart condition, 64% at a higher risk of developing a stroke, 50% high risk of developing high blood pressure and 87% higher risk of developing arthritis. Comparatively, even people who smoke &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/depression-and-anxiety-can-be-as-harmful-to-health-as-smoking/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Depression and Anxiety can be as Harmful to Health as Smoking"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A recent study has revealed that people who have high anxiety levels as well as depression are at 65% higher risk of developing a heart condition, 64% at a higher risk of developing a stroke, 50% high risk of developing high blood pressure and 87% higher risk of developing arthritis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Comparatively, even people who smoke and are obese are at the same level of risk thus pointing out the importance of mental health condition with respect to physical health. The lead author Andrea Niles of the University of California San Francisco said that hence smoking and obesity as well as mental health conditions like depression and anxiety pose the same risk.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1069" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking.jpg" alt="Depression and Anxiety can be as Harmful to Health as Smoking" width="936" height="624" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking.jpg 936w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Smoking-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Yet, cancer is not included in the list of conditions that are a result of depression and anxiety. The co-author Aoife O Donovan from UCSF has said that the study is similar to the other studies in terms of the psychological distress being a strong predictor of many types of cancers. She also asked people not to attribute <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/">cancer diagnosis</a> to stress, depression and anxiety history.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Niles also said that the study was the first one that compared between anxiety and depression with smoking and obesity as potential risk factors for health conditions that could be life threatening.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In a nutshell, the study is only brings to light the fact that mental health is to be cared for equally and has the ability to do equal harm as addictions or unfit habits do. And that it is time that people shun away the taboo around mental health and habits and take a step to consult mental health practitioners if they are facing issues like depression, anxiety or more so that they can be treated not only for it but also to avoid their physical health being affected.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is of the <a href="http://college.rrmch.org/">best medical colleges in Bangalore</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Genetically Modified Virus Effective in Cancer Treatment &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetically-modified-virus-effective-in-cancer-treatment-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1055</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The study published in the journal for Cancer Research states that scientists have developed a new technique in which they use a genetically modified virus for killing cancer cells and even has the ability to destroy their hiding places. Named as the enadenotucirev, this novel dual action virus targets cancer cells as well as the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetically-modified-virus-effective-in-cancer-treatment-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Genetically Modified Virus Effective in Cancer Treatment &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The study published in the journal for Cancer Research states that scientists have developed a new technique in which they use a genetically modified virus for killing cancer cells and even has the ability to destroy their hiding places. Named as the enadenotucirev, this novel dual action virus targets cancer cells as well as the healthy cells that are tricked into cancer cell protection by the immune system of the body called fibro-blasts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1056" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment.jpg" alt="Genetically Modified Virus Effective in Cancer Treatment" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The therapy used presently for killing the tricked viruses of cancer may also kill the fibroblast cells leading to toxicity. Carcinomas, the most common kind of cancer are found to start in the cells of the skin or in the tissues covering or lining internal organs like lungs, pancreas, breasts, colon, prostate and ovaries.<br />
As per Kerry Fisher of Britain’s University of Oxford there hasn’t been any way where you can kill the cancer cells and the fibroblasts that are known to protect them as well, without causing any harm to the other parts of the body. Therefore, this technique that can be used for targeting the cancer cells as well as the fibroblasts is definitely cited as a vital development in reducing the suppression inside the carcinomas as well as initiating the normal immune process.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><img class="alignnone wp-image-1057 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/rrmch.gif" alt="rrmch" width="647" height="42" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The team included some genetic instructions before publishing the study in the journal order the infected cancer cells to produce a protein called bispecific T cell engager, that has the ability to bind and stick two cells together. Here the first end is fibroblasts and the second end is T cells – a kind of immune cell that kills defective cells. The result, T cells started killing attached fibroblasts. The team also carried out the testing of the virus on a human bone marrow successfully to find that the process did not result in creating any toxicity to the rest of the body or any inappropriate activation of T cells.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The clinical trials of Enadenotucirev have already started for carcinoma treatment and in the upcoming year it will begin its clinical trials of finding out the safety and affectivity of it on people suffering from cancer.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Top Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore, Karnataka</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ductal Carcinoma in Situ (DCIS) &#038; Mastectomy</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-dcis-mastectomy/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 06:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1016</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In India Breast Cancer is the top occurring cancer amongst females with a mortality rate of 12.7 per 1,00,000. A non-invasive form of breast cancer, Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) is a common form of cancer in India. Ductal means ducts as its starts in the milk ducts and carcinoma means cancer that starts in &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-dcis-mastectomy/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Ductal Carcinoma in Situ (DCIS) &#038; Mastectomy"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">In<em> India Breast Cancer</em> is the top occurring cancer amongst females with a mortality rate of 12.7 per 1,00,000. A non-invasive form of breast cancer, <em><strong>Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS)</strong></em> is a common form of cancer in India. Ductal means ducts as its starts in the milk ducts and carcinoma means cancer that starts in the skin or any other tissues covering the internal organs and in situ means in its original place. The reason this cancer is known as non- invasive cancer is that is has not spread beyond the milk duct to the neighboring tissues.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">DCIS is a grade 0 cancer and is not a life threatening cancer but having it in first place does increase the risk of developing an invasive breast cancer later on compared to people who haven’t had it before. The possibility of recurrence is usually 5 or 10 years post the first appearance with a 30% likelihood.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1017" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-DCIS.jpg" alt="Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS)" width="500" height="287" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-DCIS.jpg 500w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Ductal-carcinoma-in-situ-DCIS-300x172.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The possibility of recurrence in women undergoing the breast conserving surgery is around 25% to 30% . To lower the risk of recurrence by 15% you need to include radiation therapy in the treatment plan. Also, if DCIS comes back after treatment it could either be non-invasive or invasive too, chances are 50% for each.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Here’s a look through the symptoms, causes, diagnosis and treatment of the condition.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DICS &#8211; Symptoms</strong><br />
Generally there are no visible symptoms of DCIS. Only a few people might have a lump in the breast or some nipple discharge. Diagnosis is only possible for most of the cases through mammography.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DICS – Diagnosis</strong><br />
<strong>Breast Examination</strong> – A physical examination of breasts is carried out if a lump is present though such lump is rarely noticeable.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Mammography</strong> – A mammography can easily detect DCIS. Even when a physical examination fails, mammography can be used to detect DCIS.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Biopsy</strong> – Biopsy is only carried out when a mammogram does not give a clear result. There are two kinds of non-invasive biopsies which involve a bit of surgery.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong> Core needle biopsy</strong> – A large needle is inserted for a big sample of tissue from the suspicious area.</li>
<li><strong> Fine needle biopsy</strong> &#8211; A sample of cells are obtained by inserting a small hollow needle in the breast and then examining it under the microscope.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Though more invasive biopsies are rarely need for DCIS, if the above are not able to give conclusive results then biopsies like incisional and excisional biopsy’s are to be done.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong> – Once the diagnosis confirms DCIS, surgery is done to remove the <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cancer</a> as well as the border of the healthy tissues surrounding the cancer, known as the clear margins. This means doing the procedure of lumpectomy or sometimes mastectomy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Be Aware of the Silent Killer Called Ovarian Cancer</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/be-aware-of-the-silent-killer-called-ovarian-cancer/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 11:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[be aware of Ovarian Cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ovarian Cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ovarian Cancer awareness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1009</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many women aren’t aware that ovarian cancer is also known as the Silent Killer because generally no visible symptoms indicate the presence of this cancer and the symptoms surface only during the final stages. This cancer has known to affect as many as over 20K women across the world every year and due to the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/be-aware-of-the-silent-killer-called-ovarian-cancer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Be Aware of the Silent Killer Called Ovarian Cancer"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Many women aren’t aware that <strong>ovarian cancer</strong> is also known as the Silent Killer because generally no visible symptoms indicate the presence of this cancer and the symptoms surface only during the final stages. This cancer has known to affect as many as over 20K women across the world every year and due to the lack of visible symptoms indicating the cancer, it makes this cancer even scarier.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>CAUSES AND RISKS</strong><br />
The causes of this cancer are not clear as yet but family history is one of the risk factors and the women having a family member or relative with ovarian cancer or breast cancer are definitely at a higher risk of the same. Age can also be termed as one of the risk factors because most women get it after 60 -63 years. Also, the women who have had one or more pregnancies before the age of 26 are at a lower risk. The risk is lower if the number of pregnancies is higher. Even using contraceptives frequently tends to lower the risk of ovarian cancer. As per doctors there is this contraceptive hormone called DMPA or Depo pro-vera CI that if injected of more than 3 years, reduces the risk of ovarian cancer even further. Women who make use of infertility treatment drugs over a period of one year are also known to have a high risk of getting ovarian cancer. Other risk factors include obesity, hormone therapy and gynecologic surgery as in surgery of reproductive organs and getting endometriosis at the age of 30 years.</p>
<p><img class="wp-image-1010 size-medium alignleft" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-300x300.jpg" alt="Ovarian Cancer" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DIAGNOSIS AND STAGES</strong><br />
The doctor on examination will ask for some tests that include blood test, a CT scan or MRI as well as Laparoscopy, biopsy, abdominal fluid aspiration test or colonoscopy for that matter.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Stages</strong><br />
As per the American Cancer society ovarian cancer has four stages<br />
<strong>Stage 1</strong> – This is the preliminary stage of ovarian cancer where only the ovary or the ovaries are affected.<br />
<strong>Stage 2</strong> – This is the secondary stage where the cancer is out of the ovaries and spread around the areas like fallopian tubes, uterus, rectum or the bladder.<br />
<strong>Stage 3</strong> – This is a later stage of cancer where the cancer affects the lymph nodes, abdominal lining or even the back of the abdomen.<br />
<strong>Stage 4</strong> – The last stage of cancer where the cancer has spread to other parts of the body outside the peritoneal cavity viz. abdomen or pelvis upto the liver, fluid around the lungs or the spleen.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><b>SYMPTOMS</b><br />
The initial symptoms of<em> ovarian cancer</em> are easy to miss because they are very much similar to premenstrual syndrome. So, you have to be alert and if you find any of the below mentioned symptoms that persist for a long time then good idea is to go for checkup.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Recurring Abdominal Pain</strong><br />
If you have been experiencing stomach ache for a long time even if you don’t have your monthly cycles then its time you get it tested.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Appetite loss and Nausea</strong><br />
When ovarian cancer starts spreading around, it affects the bowel system and causes nausea. If you feel you have been experiencing and loss in your appetite or feeling full sooner than ever, check it out.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Bloating and Constipation</strong><br />
When a tumor is growing inside you even when you do not eat much you feel fuller and bloated. It can also affect your bowel movement leading to regular constipation issues.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Irregular monthly cycles</strong><br />
A tumor in the ovary will cause your monthly period to become irregular or sorts. So, if you haven’t been experiencing any irregularity in your monthly periods earlier but only lately for a while, good idea to meet up with your doctor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Frequent urination</strong><br />
If you have been making frequent trips to the bathroom for peeing then this could be the sign. Do not ignore and visit your doctor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
The treatment is based on the diagnosis of the stage of the cancer and includes procedures like surgery, chemotherapy, radiation therapy, targeted therapy as well as hormonal therapy. One or more treatments in combination are usually used depending upon the stage of the cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Surgery types</strong><br />
The extent of surgery is also based on the stage and includes removal of ovaries, fallopian tubes, uterus as well the affected surrounding tissues. Then there is de-bulking surgery and lymph node dissections also which is done to reduce the cancerous tissues if the cancer is spread beyond the pelvic region and removal of lymph nodes near the aorta respectively.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Therapy types</strong><br />
Chemotherapy is generally done post-surgery to kill the remaining cancer cells. A medication known as cytotoxic medication poisonous drugs to the cells in-order to prevent growth and division. This is a recurring process based on the cancer growth. Targeted Chemotherapy is another treatment that involves target specific function or pathways of cancer cells. Another therapy that is used as a part to treatment is <strong>Hormone therapy</strong>. It is done to cut the supply of estrogen from the cancer cells in order to slow their growth. Radiation therapy is also used for treatment of cancer and is generally used in advanced form of cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Survival</strong><br />
As the stage increases the survival rate decreases. While for Stage I there is a 90% chance of survival, for stage IV, the chance is 17%.</p>
<p>Know more about <strong><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Cancer Hospital in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>All You Need to Know About Terminal Illness</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/terminal-illness/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 12:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terminal Illness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=919</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The term terminal illness means disease that is not curable and is expected to result in death of the patient over a course of time. It is a commonly used term for illnesses like cancer, heart disease of advanced stage, to name a few. When a person is said to be suffering from a terminal &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/terminal-illness/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All You Need to Know About Terminal Illness"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The term terminal illness means disease that is not curable and is expected to result in death of the patient over a course of time. It is a commonly used term for illnesses like cancer, heart disease of advanced stage, to name a few. When a person is said to be suffering from a terminal illness, there is near certainty that the patient is going to die in a course of time irrespective of the treatment. Once diagnosed with a terminal condition the patient knows that death is certain and the doctor informs the patient about the time left, in days, weeks, months or years.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Once a patient is diagnosed for terminal illness, the disease management process is decided. The options for it include continual of treatment, caregiving, hospice care and even physician assisted suicide. The decision making is done keeping the patient as well as the family in loop. Many a time patients with terminal illness experience anxiety around the nearing death as well as depression and hence requires psychotherapeutic treatment to help them deal with the same.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">On the flip side, knowing about the terminal illness condition gives them time to get ready for advance treatment and care procedures as well as living will, to help them deal with end of life care effectively. Let us run through the different disease management or end of life care procedures for terminal illness patients.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Terminal-Illness-11-e1533277309474-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-939 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Terminal-Illness1-e1533277309474-1.jpg" alt="Terminal Illness" width="640" height="400" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Terminal-Illness1-e1533277309474-1.jpg 640w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Terminal-Illness1-e1533277309474-1-300x188.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment Continuation</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Palliative Care</strong> &#8211; Palliative care is more about after care of the physical needs of the patients post diagnosis. This includes emotional support, management of pain, psychological and spiritual care. It is a methodology that concentrates on improvement of quality of life of the patients and satisfaction besides helping family members deal and cope with the difficult situation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Care Giving</strong> – Care giving is an integral part of terminal disease management. It involves keeping a nurse to take care of the person suffering from the condition. The care givers provide support like psychological support, food, assistance with movement and routine activities on a day to day basis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Medications</strong> – Terminal patients who suffer from cancer related pain, need medications for relief. The medication prescribed varies based on the pain severity as well as status of disease. One of the common symptoms that terminal illness patients experience is dyspnea viz. breathing issues.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Good Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Good Hospitals in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Hospice Care</strong> &#8211; There is a misconception that people choosing hospice care live less compared to others, but study has proved that patients with hospice care live for the same span than others. It includes spending more time with family, friends or other inmates undertaking hospice disease management procedures. They usually stay away from a hospital at home or at an inpatient hospice facility.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Physician assisted Suicide (PAS)</strong> &#8211; This concept is legally approved only in a few countries in the world. It is when a patient decides to die with dignity that he or she opts for physician assisted suicide. The decision could be based on various different reasons like avoiding pain, disability, healthcare costs, family impact, personal and religious beliefs, to name a few. The patient has to give request in writing as well as orally after which the physicians offer them lethal drugs to help them die.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, some terminally ill patients stop all the treatments that they are undergoing to avoid side-affects while some go for even more aggressive treatment in a hope to increase their life span to the maximum. Some also opt for alternative methods of treatment that are non-proven as well as diet changes that are required.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Neuroendocrine Tumors, Types and Symptoms</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/neuroendocrine-tumors-types-and-symptoms/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 09:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best neurologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=842</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Recently Bollywood celebrity Irfan Khan is known to be diagnosed by Neuroendocrine Tumor. In order to restrain his fans and people in general from any kind of speculation he even went on to clarify that neuro does not always mean about the brain. He had to do that post rumors of he suffering from brain &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/neuroendocrine-tumors-types-and-symptoms/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Neuroendocrine Tumors, Types and Symptoms"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently Bollywood celebrity Irfan Khan is known to be diagnosed by Neuroendocrine Tumor. In order to restrain his fans and people in general from any kind of speculation he even went on to clarify that neuro does not always mean about the brain. He had to do that post rumors of he suffering from brain tumor surfaced across the social media. Well, as he is out of the country right now and is getting treated, best wishes of all the country are with him. Well, for those who are unaware about neuroendocrine tumor here’s a rundown this condition.</p>
<p>Neuroendocrine tumor or NET is a tumor which does not generally show any major symptoms as it grows slowly. Once the tumor grows or if it releases hormones while it is functional is when symptoms surface.<br />
Types of Endocrine tumors include pancreatic endocrine tumor, gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors and lung neuroendocrine tumors.</p>
<p>Pancreatic Neuro Endocrine Tumors – This is a rare kind of tumor. The symptoms of this cancer are subject to the hormones released by it. The symptoms generally include the following</p>
<ol>
<li>Stomach Ulcers</li>
<li>Heart burn</li>
<li>Jaundice</li>
<li>Low or high blood Sugar levels</li>
<li>Blood clots</li>
<li>Patches of red itchy and painful skin</li>
<li>Unexplained weight loss</li>
</ol>
<p>When the gastrin in body increases excessively it causes Zollinger Ellison syndrome further increasing the quantity of stomach acid ultimately causing small intestine or stomach ulcers. The symptoms include</p>
<ol>
<li>Severe Diarrhea</li>
<li>Heartburn</li>
<li>Abdominal Pain</li>
<li>Pain in abdomen</li>
<li>Nausea and vomiting</li>
<li>Blood vomits</li>
<li>Weight loss</li>
</ol>
<p>When the level of cortisol increases highly inside the body it causes cushing syndrome. When too much Adrenocorticotrpic hormone is released it leads to lung NETs which leads to adrenal glands making too much cortisol. The symptoms are as follows –</p>
<ol>
<li>Muscle weakness</li>
<li>Increase in hair growth on body and face</li>
<li>High blood sugar</li>
<li>Weight gain</li>
<li>Fat build up above the collar bone below the shoulders</li>
<li>Mood swing and behavioral changes</li>
<li>Purple lines on skin</li>
</ol>
<p>Gastrointestinal neuroendocrine tumors – This tumor develops in any part of the gastrointestinal tract besides large and small intestine. The symptoms are as follows –</p>
<ol>
<li>Nausea and vomiting</li>
<li>Diarrhea</li>
<li>Anemia with fatigue</li>
<li>Weight loss</li>
<li>Constipation or intestine blockage</li>
<li>Blood in stool or rectal bleeding</li>
<li>Heartburn or indigestion</li>
<li>Abdominal/ rectal pain or discomfort</li>
</ol>
<p>Lung Neuroendocrine tumors &#8211; This tumor develops in the bronchi. Symptoms include</p>
<ol>
<li>Never ceasing cough</li>
<li>Blood in cough</li>
<li>Difficulty Breathing</li>
<li>Pneumonia</li>
<li>Fatigue</li>
<li>Skin flushing, wheezing and diarrhea (Carcinoid Syndrome)</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="RRMCH Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> is one the <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">best hospitals in Bangalore</a> and it are also the<a title="Best Neuro Hospital in India" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/" target="_blank"> best Neuro hospital in India</a>. It has got the best neurologist in Bangalore</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cancer to Curd &#8211; The Journey of Ramadevi Nimmanapalli</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cancer-to-curd-the-journey-of-ramadevi-nimmanapalli/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=821</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Ramadevi Nimmanapalli, a cancer researcher by profession had been in the US till 2015. She returned to India leaving behind this career in order to take up another challenging opportunity of setting up a faculty of Veterinary and Animal Sciences at the Benaras Hindu University in Varanasi. She herself had done her Science Graduation from &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cancer-to-curd-the-journey-of-ramadevi-nimmanapalli/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Cancer to Curd &#8211; The Journey of Ramadevi Nimmanapalli"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Ramadevi Nimmanapalli, a cancer researcher by profession had been in the US till 2015. She returned to India leaving behind this career in order to take up another challenging opportunity of setting up a faculty of Veterinary and Animal Sciences at the Benaras Hindu University in Varanasi. She herself had done her Science Graduation from Sri Venkateswara Veterinary University in Hyderabad after which she did her Masters in Sciences, topping the University. She further went to Oxford to pursue PhD there.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Cancer-to-Curd-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-822" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Cancer-to-Curd-1-1.jpg" alt="Cancer to Curd" width="600" height="381" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Describing her experience in Oxford England as a rather challenging one even though she was a topper, she mentioned that the education system in India and England was different. Catching up was quite a task because Indian education courses do not offer in-depth study as compared to Oxford. So, she had to work really hard with her research in microbiology in bluetongue virus that affects deers and cattle as well. After completing her Phd. She shifted to USA where she researched in areas of human cancer and chemical pathways for drug Gleevac. Before returning to India she was teaching at the Philadelphia college of Osteopathic Medicine and MD Anderson Cancer centre, Tuskagee University.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;" align="justify"><a title="Best Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank"><strong>BEST CANCER HOSPITAL IN BANGALORE</strong></a></p>
<p align="justify">Though shifting to India was also not an easy decision for her as she was already married and living there with her husband, it’s when her husband supported the decision to take the decision to go to Indi without him joining her right away, after she moved here.</p>
<p align="justify">Now, in India, as the Dean at the Benaras University, she is all set to revive the faculty which already has a dairy farm on its main campus besides a research ready campus that is being setup in Mirzapur for MSc and Doctoral students, which is nearby. She is working hard to set up this new faculty and her straight forward attitude which she brought along as a learning from her USA lifestyle has been of a great aid. She has already published around 40 research papers but the one that stands out is about dealing and characterization of curd or dahi. Though the founding dean of the faculty has not had any admissions, later this year, the faculty is going to welcome its first batch of undergraduate students. The team is ready, the labs are set and the preparations are on to take the plunge. Though a lot of preparations are underway as well, as per the Dean, it’s a long way to go.</p>
<p align="justify">*source from the internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drinking Hot Tea Increases The Chances Of Cancer By 5 Times</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/hot-tea-increases-cancer/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 09:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot Tea Increases the cancer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=789</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yes, you read that right. Though it does not hold true for all, it does hold true for men who drink tea while they are also regular consumers of alcohol and smoke tobacco. Particularly in under developed regions of countries like China esophageal cancer is quite common. Chinese men drink tea besides smoking and being &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/hot-tea-increases-cancer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Drinking Hot Tea Increases The Chances Of Cancer By 5 Times"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Yes, you read that right. Though it does not hold true for all, it does hold true for men who drink tea while they are also regular consumers of alcohol and smoke tobacco. Particularly in under developed regions of countries like China <strong>esophageal cancer</strong> is quite common. Chinese men drink tea besides smoking and being alcoholic. Esophageal cancer has very low survival rates and the rate at which it is spreading its wings in these countries is worrisome.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Drinking-Hot-Tea-Increases-The-Chances-Of-Cancer-By-5-Times-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-790 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Drinking-Hot-Tea-Increases-The-Chances-Of-Cancer-By-5-Times-1-300x168.jpg" alt="Drinking Hot Tea Increases The Chances Of Cancer By 5 Times" width="300" height="168" /></a></p>
<p>Researchers of the National Natural science foundation of china as well as national key research and development program went on to undertake a survey in China to test if consuming hot tea is associated with esophageal cancer risk. The study was done on 456155 participants between the age-group of 30 and 79 for around 9.2 years of median followup. The researchers found out that drinking hot tea while being an alcoholic and smoker did increase the risk of esophageal cancer. The participants who smoked, consumed alcohol and hot tea did tend to risk esophageal cancer risk by 5 times as compared to participants with none of the three habits. Though, the participants who did not consume alcohol or smoke were not subject to the risk of esophageal cancer.</p>
<p>The study is based on observations and hence its you cannot determine the cause and effect link, but the researchers do speculate that hot tea does damage the lining of the tissue inside the esophagus, thus increasing the chances of injury due to smoking and drinking as well. It can possibly form inflammatory compounds post repeated irritation to the esophagus, thereby increasing the risk of cancer as well.</p>
<p>Having said that, we have also come across contradictory statements with regards to cancer and tea. In the recent past WHO did conclude that beverages with temperatures above 149 degrees F including did increase the risk of esophageal cancer, however tea has been excluded most of the times in the past from the cancer causing beverages. Furthermore green tea is known to be lowering cancer risk as well.</p>
<p>So a better idea is to consume tea at less higher temperatures that do not risk the chance of causing esophageal <a title="Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank">cancer</a>. Obviously, it goes without saying that you need to stay away from addictions like smoking or alcohol as well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*source from internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cervical Cancer Spreading At Alarming Rates In India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cervical-cancer-spreading-at-alarming-rates-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 05:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cervical cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rrmch.org/blog/?p=392</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Cervical cancer cases in India are increasing at an alarming rate, so much so this monster is known to take 200 lives of women in India, on a daily basis. Over 60,000 deaths have been accounted during the year 2015 itself. It is thus, one of the most common cancers in women in India alongside &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cervical-cancer-spreading-at-alarming-rates-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Cervical Cancer Spreading At Alarming Rates In India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Cervical-Cancer-Hospitals-in-Bangalore-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-393" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Cervical-Cancer-Hospitals-in-Bangalore-1.jpg" alt="Cervical-Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore" width="601" height="492" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Cervical cancer cases in India</em> are increasing at an alarming rate, so much so this monster is known to take 200 lives of women in India, on a daily basis. Over 60,000 deaths have been accounted during the year 2015 itself. It is thus, one of the most <strong>common cancers in women in India</strong> alongside breast cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>FACTS ABOUT CERVICAL CANCER</strong><br />
<em>Human Papolloma virus or HPV causes Cervical cancer</em>. It usually effects women in the age group of 40-65, but 55-65 is the age group with highest associated risks. The virus is easily transmitted through skin to skin contact and not just sexually, which is a myth many of us believe in. In 90% of the cases, the immune system takes care of clearing the virus. The remaining 10% whose bodies are not able to create the antibodies needed to kill these invaders get affected by Cervical cancer. Also, no test is still available for knowing whether your body has the ability to create the antibodies required to defeat the cervical cancer virus or not. The rural areas bear the brunt more so due to failure in doing checkups and ignorance.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, it has been also found that women don’t really seem to be willing to take the vaccine available for cervical cancer. In India, its majorly because most of them don’t know about it or because of the cost factor. Well, the side effects also are a major concern for people with numerous myths surrounding the condition doing rounds, already. One such myth is infertility. Though, against the myth about the side effects of cervical cancer, lies the fact sheet of over 200 vaccinated cases that proves no serious long term side effects of the vaccine. Another fact being that over 65 countries have included this vaccine as a part of their health program already. The awareness levels are also less, even though there has been a lot of effort in the area for the past three decades.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT &amp; PREVENTION</strong><br />
As mentioned<strong> vaccines for cervical cancer</strong> are already available and as per experts one of this vaccines is 99% effective in prevention in young women. It’s the nonavalent, but it has yet to see the light of day in India. But, the bivalent and quadravalent vaccines are readily available and provide around 70% protection against the earlier mentioned nonavalent which offers 90%. The world health organization has recommended the vaccine for age groups of 9-13 years old girls due to its immunogenic ability at this age.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In a nutshell,<em> cervical cancer is a deadly condition in women and India</em> needs to have an action plan against it. Each one of us is responsible for our family and kids. So, go ahead and shield your girls against this deadly disease by vaccinating them early on. The HPV virus has the ability to stay in the body of a woman for a decade before it turns cancerous therefore it is advisable to do a pap smear test on a regular basis for detection of any symptoms, early on. For women not eligible for vaccination it is advisable to take up the Pap smear test after a certain age on a recommended basis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">RRMCH conducted <a title="Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/news/cervical-cancer/" target="_blank">Cervical Cancer</a>  awareness programs</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
