<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Occupational Therapy in India &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/occupational-therapy-in-india/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 07:02:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Rising Demand for Occupational Therapists in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-rising-demand-for-occupational-therapists-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 07:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occupational Therapists in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occupational Therapy in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=665</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Over the years Occupational therapy has garnered a lot of eye balls and youth seem to be interested in this career that not just pays but gives immense work satisfaction as well. The work of an occupational therapist involves around helping physically and mentally challenged people to manage themselves independently. This includes performing daily chores, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-rising-demand-for-occupational-therapists-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Rising Demand for Occupational Therapists in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Over the years Occupational therapy has garnered a lot of eye balls and youth seem to be interested in this career that not just pays but gives immense work satisfaction as well. The work of an occupational therapist involves around helping physically and mentally challenged people to manage themselves independently. This includes performing daily chores, play, work and more.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Occupational-Therapists-in-India-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-666" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Occupational-Therapists-in-India-1-1.jpg" alt="Occupational Therapy in India" width="623" height="283" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">For becoming an <em>Occupational therapist</em> you need to opt for Bachelors in Occupational Therapy degree course after 12th Science. It is a four year course and is offered by numerous medical colleges across India. Some of them offer direct admissions on the basis of percentage while for some you need to crack the entrance.</p>
<p align="justify">The syllabus includes a foundation course in research methodology besides an amalgamation of subjects from psychology, orthopaedics, psychiatry, pharmacology, anatomy, physiology, surgery combined with ergonomics and occupational therapy. After completion of the four years course you need to undergo a six months full time clinically oriented training internship program. After which you can start working as a professional or carry on with your PG diploma, masters and doctorate.</p>
<p align="justify">One major reason behind the rising demand also lies in the fact that in India only 20 institutions offering 9 graduate programs for occupational therapy. This number seems to be a meager one as compared to the leap frogging number of patients suffering from physical and mental disabilities. Hence, as far as the job opportunities are concerned, there is undoubtedly immense scope in both private and public sectors. You may either work with hospitals, schools, public healthcare institutions or carry out private practice in a clinic or alongside other specialists.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, occupational therapy is no child’s play but beyond a profession that offers a lucrative career, it is more about community service. Occupational therapists train families and care takers to deal with patients having disabilities in a positive way, thus helping them become independent, productive and lead a normal life.</p>
<h1 class="entry-title">Other post &#8211; <a title="physiotherapy colleges in bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/" target="_blank">Career in Physiotherapy in India</a></h1>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
