<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 10:27:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 10:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1231</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[No a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions. But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town, even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus. The &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>No
a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around
relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions.
But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and
global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town,
even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus.
</p>



<p>The
earlier studies primarily were carried out for a short period of time
and only have been able to identify  the links between mental health
as well as temperature but the research till date only involves short
time period and more focused on connection rather than causal
factors. Moreover, this findings have so far not yielded any
substantial conclusions. So, the researchers with this study are
hoping to get answers to their questions that are not answered as
yet. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1232" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png 860w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-300x160.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-768x411.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
researchers for their study has gathered data from various sources
including Californian emergency departments,  collecting data and
analyzing information from the data of mental health diagnosis visits
during the period of 2005 – 2016. 
</p>



<p>They
even mined for data around suicides in America during 1960 – 2016
period.  These information was based on statuses that were
individually self-reported.  After drilling the climatic temperature
in US down, the researchers managed to develop ‘’fine spatial and
temporal scales”.</p>



<p>From
the study the researchers concluded that the mental health outcomes
decrease as the temperatures cool and the increase mental health
issues with rise in temperatures. Statistically speaking they found
that there was a rise in 0.48% rise in mental health visits with a
rise in average monthly temperature of 1<sup>0</sup> F and even a
rise in suicides by 0.35%</p>



<p>In
short, the rise and drop in temperatures has a significant impact of
the mental health because the authors of the study also showed
stability in the estimates even when accounted for socio economic
status and air conditioning adoption. 
</p>



<p>As for suicide rate, it rises only if there is a rise in temperature amid the growing season because growing season is all about crop yields. If the temperature rises, the crop yield reduces and leads to financial issues that in turn increase the risk of suicides.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
