<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>hospitals in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/hospitals-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 06:42:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Weight Loss After 50 Years Of Age Reduces Breast Cancer Risk</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/weight-loss-after-50-years-of-age-reduces-breast-cancer-risk/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 06:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breast cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1251</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Breast cancer is one of the most common cancers amongst women in India and worldwide. A recent study about women who lost weight at 50 and maintained a healthy weight thereon showed a decreased risk of breast cancer as compared to women with more weight. This study is therefore a way to help women work &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/weight-loss-after-50-years-of-age-reduces-breast-cancer-risk/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weight Loss After 50 Years Of Age Reduces Breast Cancer Risk"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Breast cancer</strong> is one of the most common cancers amongst women in India and worldwide. A recent study about women who lost weight at 50 and maintained a healthy weight thereon showed a decreased risk of breast cancer as compared to women with more weight.  This study is therefore a way to help women work around prevention of cancer.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-1024x683.jpg" alt="Breast Cancer Risk" class="wp-image-1252" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
study is published in the Journal of the National Cancer Institute.
In USA over two third of the adult women are overweight or obese. The
study was carried out by the researchers at the American Cancer
Society, Harvard T. H. Chan School of Public Health using the Pooling
Project of Prospective Studies of Diet and Cancer (DCPP) in order to
determine the connection between sustained loss of weight after
menopause or later adulthood and the risk of breast cancer.</p>



<p>The
study involved over 180,000 women over 50 years of age across 10
studies. The sample size is huge and this analysis is the first to
assess the breast cancer risk impact over sustained weight loss. The
study did examine weight three times across 10 years period viz. at
the time of enrollment, post five years and again four years
thereafter. 
</p>



<p>The
results showed that women who were able to reduce more weight in
later adulthood and sustained it were able to lower the risk of
breast cancer. The women who were able to shed around 9 kg’s of
weight and then game some of it but not all did show a significant
reduction in breast cancer risk. 
</p>



<p> The lead author of the study Lauren Teras, PhD says ‘These findings may be a strong motivator for the two thirds of American women who are overweight to lose some of that weight. Even if you gain weight after age 50, it is not too late to lower your risk of breast cancer”.</p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>RRMCH is one of the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/"><strong>Best Cancer Treatment Hospital in Bangalore India</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 09:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Role Of Legumes In Heart Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1245</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes. Though it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual basis. But, recently &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer
by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find
out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes.  Though
it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual
basis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1246" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>Five color legumes for healthy , Soy bean, Navy bean or white bean, Black beam, Red bean and Green bean,</figcaption></figure>



<p>But,
recently researchers of the review called Advances in Nutrition took
up the task of understanding the significance of legumes like
lentils, peas and beans etc. around heart health. 
</p>



<p>Primarily, they focused on cardiovascular diseases like <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">coronary heart</a> disease, stroke, myocardial infarction besides looking into hypertension, obesity and diabetes. They chose cardiovascular diseases because it is one of the most common causes of mortality and even one of the most expensive ones. It is known to cause US 1 billion dollars a day. </p>



<p>They
used the data analysis of Eurpoean Association which recently carried
out a series of systematic reviews as well as meta-analysis for
Diabetics study. The researchers hope that these results could be
quite a help in updating the recommendations already made around the
role of legumes in preventing as well as treating cardio-metabolic
diseases. 
</p>



<p>The
data review and comparison with people with lowest and highest intake
of legumes revealed that dietary pulses that had legumes which either
did or did not include other legumes did decrease coronary heart
disease, obesity incidence and hypertension. 
</p>



<p>
Though the researchers were able to find a positive relationship
between intake of legumes in higher amounts and reduction in certain
parameters related to cardiovascular risks, the conclusion they came
to are muted relatively. 
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers “The overall certainty of the evidence was
graded as low for CVD incidence and ‘very low for all the other
outcomes.” 
</p>



<p>Therefore, the co author of the study Dr Hana Kahleova said “ Americans eat less than one serving of legumes per day, on average. Simply adding more beans to our plates could be a powerful tool in fighting heart disease and bringing down blood pressure.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><strong>Best Cardiologist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 10:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1231</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[No a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions. But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town, even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus. The &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>No
a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around
relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions.
But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and
global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town,
even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus.
</p>



<p>The
earlier studies primarily were carried out for a short period of time
and only have been able to identify  the links between mental health
as well as temperature but the research till date only involves short
time period and more focused on connection rather than causal
factors. Moreover, this findings have so far not yielded any
substantial conclusions. So, the researchers with this study are
hoping to get answers to their questions that are not answered as
yet. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1232" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png 860w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-300x160.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-768x411.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
researchers for their study has gathered data from various sources
including Californian emergency departments,  collecting data and
analyzing information from the data of mental health diagnosis visits
during the period of 2005 – 2016. 
</p>



<p>They
even mined for data around suicides in America during 1960 – 2016
period.  These information was based on statuses that were
individually self-reported.  After drilling the climatic temperature
in US down, the researchers managed to develop ‘’fine spatial and
temporal scales”.</p>



<p>From
the study the researchers concluded that the mental health outcomes
decrease as the temperatures cool and the increase mental health
issues with rise in temperatures. Statistically speaking they found
that there was a rise in 0.48% rise in mental health visits with a
rise in average monthly temperature of 1<sup>0</sup> F and even a
rise in suicides by 0.35%</p>



<p>In
short, the rise and drop in temperatures has a significant impact of
the mental health because the authors of the study also showed
stability in the estimates even when accounted for socio economic
status and air conditioning adoption. 
</p>



<p>As for suicide rate, it rises only if there is a rise in temperature amid the growing season because growing season is all about crop yields. If the temperature rises, the crop yield reduces and leads to financial issues that in turn increase the risk of suicides.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>After 50 Alcohol Consumption Ain’t That Risky?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/after-50-alcohol-consumption-aint-that-risky/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 09:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[full health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1176</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Addiction to alcohol ain’t good for your health, is what we are all aware off. The consequences of the same include cancers of certain type, liver damage, and heart as well as brain disease too. Having said that there are studies about health benefits of drinking in limit as well. One such recent study has &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/after-50-alcohol-consumption-aint-that-risky/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "After 50 Alcohol Consumption Ain’t That Risky?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Addiction
to alcohol ain’t good for your health, is what we are all aware
off.  The consequences of the same include cancers of certain type,
liver damage, and heart as well as brain disease too.  Having said
that there are studies about health benefits of drinking in limit as
well. One such recent study has found that alcohol intake in
moderation does protect against mortality due to cardiovascular
diseases. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/After-50-Alcohol-Consumption-Ain’t-That-Risky.jpg" alt="After 50 Alcohol Consumption" class="wp-image-1177" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/After-50-Alcohol-Consumption-Ain’t-That-Risky.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/After-50-Alcohol-Consumption-Ain’t-That-Risky-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/After-50-Alcohol-Consumption-Ain’t-That-Risky-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
study published in Journal of Alcohol and Drugs and lead by a team of
Boston medical center in Massachusetts presents a fresh approach
towards the long going debate on whether moderate drinking is good
for health. 
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers, the studies carried out earlier were not
accurate enough. The reason was that the study included participants
of age above 50. The researchers argue that people who have passed
away before 50 due to alcohol consumption are not included in the
study. Hence, people who aren’t alive cannot participate in a
cohort study. 
</p>



<p>As
per Dr. Timothy Naimi, alcohol addicts who are alive at 50 could have
been healthy before and also could have been drinking within limits
also. The authors were of the opinion that around 40 percent of the
deaths due to alcohol intake were before the age of 50 years, meaning
the deaths due to alcohol intake are not taken into consideration at
all leading to ignoring the dangers of it. 
</p>



<p>The
analysis showed that age played a major role in the risk levels
associated with alcohol.  The rate of alcohol related deaths in
people between the age group of 20 – 49 was 35.8 percent.  They
also studied individual of age above 65 years.  The study did show
that over 35 percent of the deaths occurred due to alcohol intake but
they also found that around 80 percent of the deaths in this age
group. 
</p>



<p>They also found a vast difference when they took into consideration the age group of 20-49 years and the lost number of years. The number of years saved by drinking were around 14.5 percent only.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dengue Is Back! – How To Deal With It?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dengue-is-back/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 06:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dengue Is Back]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rajarajeswari hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1161</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As almost 500 cases crop up in Dakshin Kannada or Mangaluru, Dengue is back this season and with a big bang for sure in Karnataka. Already four people have succumbed to the deadly fever that is a result of the Aedes mosquitos. Unike malaria mosquitos, Dengue mosquitos breed inside the house in clean water. A &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dengue-is-back/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dengue Is Back! – How To Deal With It?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As
almost 500 cases crop up in Dakshin Kannada or Mangaluru, Dengue is
back this season and with a big bang for sure in Karnataka. Already
four people have succumbed to the deadly fever that is a result of
the Aedes mosquitos. Unike malaria mosquitos, Dengue mosquitos breed
inside the house in clean water. A viral infection, Dengue is at its
peak in the monsoon season every year. The most common symptoms of
dengue include headache, swollen lymph nodes, rashes, exhaustion and
high fever. The main characteristics of dengue include high fever,
rashes and headache. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/DENGUE.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1163" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/DENGUE.jpg 700w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/DENGUE-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /></figure>



<p>The
acute phase of the fever can last upto two weeks. The more serious
and life threatening condition of Dengue is Dengue hemorrhagic fever
(DHF) occurring mostly in under 10 years children. This complication
can cause circulatory collapse, hemorrhage and abdominal pain. The
symptoms often occur after 3 days to 15 days of the mosquito bite.
The weather conditions also are responsible to an extent for breeding
the dengue mosquitos. Outbreaks are more common in tropical and
subtropical areas. Though the condition is not contagious, if a
mosquito bites a dengue infected, it does contract the dengue virus
too and spread it onward to other people. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/medical-admission-mbbs-ms-md-phd/" rel="follow"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/rrmch.gif" alt="rrmch" class="wp-image-1057"/></a></figure>



<p>Thus
the Aedes mosquito is considered the vector or transmitter and humans
as the source of infection. As mentioned Dengue Hemorrhagic fever or
DHF is a shock syndrome of dengue that mostly affects children under
10 years of age. DHF starts abruptly with consistent fever
accompanied with headache. Other symptoms include cough, nausea, sore
throat, and vomiting as well as abdominal pain. The shock occurs
around 2 to 6 days after the onset of symptoms with sudden collapse,
mouth blueness, weak pulse to name a few. Bleeding is also a common
possibility and DHF requires close monitoring. There is no particular
treatment and only intensive care with blood transfusion and oxygen
provision as well as immediate fluid replacement are some of the
treatments.  If proper treatment is provided the mortality rate could
be less but it could rise to as high as 20% if not treated properly. 
</p>



<p>The best idea is to take care around your house and avoid travelling to mosquito prone areas. Check for water storage possibilities for breeding mosquitos and treat appropriately.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>just know about <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/">Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Know About The Vital Screening Test That You Could Ignore!</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/know-about-the-vital-screening-test-that-you-could-ignore/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 06:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vital Screening Test]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1110</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In the times when pesticides and carcinogenic stuff has become a daily part of our life and is laying the path for different types of cancers, preventive screenings can help a lot in catching cancer in time and improving the quality of life. Today people are very much aware about preventive screenings at an early &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/know-about-the-vital-screening-test-that-you-could-ignore/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Know About The Vital Screening Test That You Could Ignore!"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">In the times when pesticides and carcinogenic stuff has become a daily part of our life and is laying the path for different types of cancers, preventive screenings can help a lot in catching cancer in time and improving the quality of life.</p>
<p align="justify">Today people are very much aware about preventive screenings at an early age but due to lack of time and hectic work schedules and other priorities you tend to ignore a few. Definitely, people are taking cancer screenings seriously.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1111" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test.jpg" alt="Vital Screening Test" width="600" height="600" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">One such condition is Osteoporosis. In this condition the body loses a lot of bone and makes very less or sometimes it could be both together. In Osteoporosis, bones become brittle. They could break even if there is a simple fall or at times even due to sneezing.</p>
<p align="justify">As per health experts early detection and intervention can help you curb the progression of the condition with the help of medicines as well as required life style changes. To detect osteoporosis, you need to go through the bone mineral density (BMD) test.</p>
<p align="justify">The diagnosis can help you detect the condition, the risk factors as well as the tracking over the course of your treatment. The test that is commonly taken and is painless in nature is the Central DXA test or the Dual energy X-ray absorptiometry test similar to X-ray. This test is recommended for the 65 and above women. As of now age based recommendations are not there for men. As per the NIH below 65 women who are at the risk of fracture also need to get tested.</p>
<p align="justify">Risk factors include low body weight, genes, early menopause, addictions like smoking and rheumatoid arthritis disorder. People with family history of osteoporosis are at the risk of getting it early on in their 40’s. So, thinking that osteoporosis can only occur post 65 years is not apparently true.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, get a little more aware and serious around some conditions that might not be life threatening but still vital because it could affect quality of life by getting you into painful problems.</p>
<p align="justify">
<p align="justify">Just know about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a></strong>, Contact for <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medical-college-admissions-2019-2020/">Medical College Admissions in Bangalore</a> &#8230; <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/medical-admission-mbbs-ms-md-phd/">Apply online</a></strong></p>
<p align="justify">
<p align="justify">*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pea Sized Insulin Pill For Diabetetics – Inspired By Nature</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/pea-sized-insulin-pill-for-diabetetics-inspired-by-nature/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 06:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insulin Pill For Diabetetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysore road hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pea Sized Insulin Pill For Diabetetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1100</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Insulin injections for diabetics who have to have daily shots are always a big no. One would rather prefer a pill over injections any day. It does affect the quality of life of many diabetics who need to take a shot every day for filling up their insulin scarcity. But, seems like a solution is &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/pea-sized-insulin-pill-for-diabetetics-inspired-by-nature/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Pea Sized Insulin Pill For Diabetetics – Inspired By Nature"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Insulin injections for diabetics who have to have daily shots are always a big no. One would rather prefer a pill over injections any day. It does affect the quality of life of many diabetics who need to take a shot every day for filling up their insulin scarcity. But, seems like a solution is underway or in the making. The <a href="http://www.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</em></a> research team has made an invention called the pea sized insulin pill. If this invention works, then not only insulin but it can be used as a replacement for many other injectable medicines.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_1103" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1103" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Pea-Sized-Insulin-Pill-For-Diabetetic.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1103 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Pea-Sized-Insulin-Pill-For-Diabetetic.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="486" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Pea-Sized-Insulin-Pill-For-Diabetetic.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Pea-Sized-Insulin-Pill-For-Diabetetic-300x182.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Pea-Sized-Insulin-Pill-For-Diabetetic-768x467.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1103" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;This undated photo provided by researchers in February 2019 shows the components of swallowable self-righting device which can inject drugs from inside the stomach. The new invention, reported Thursday, Feb. 7, 2019, by an MIT-led research team, has been tested only in animals so far. But if it pans out, it might offer a work-around to make not just insulin but a variety of usually injected medicines a little easier to take. (Felice Frankel via AP)&#8221;</figcaption></figure></p>
<p align="justify">
<p align="justify">The research for developing insulin that can be taken orally has been going on for decades now but without any success as in market reach till date. But insulin and many similar compounds do not have the ability to complete the tough journey through the digestive system. As per a non-researcher from the Mount Sinai’s Translational and Molecular Imaging Institute, ‘’the pill is like a miniaturized rocket launcher’’.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/"><img class="alignnone wp-image-1057 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/rrmch.gif" alt="rrmch" width="647" height="42" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">This pea sized pill has the ability to commute through the esophagus in seconds and in minutes of swallowing it’s inside the stomach. The design is inspired by that of a leopard tortoise whose shell design helps it to flip on its back and right itself. The researchers created this miniature capsule of similar shape with a weighted bottom so it can roll in the correct direction to latch automatically. It also came with a micro-injector made from dried insulin that was compressed into a sharp point. The researchers powered it with the help of a tiny spring and a sugar disk that was hardened. The pill pops after the acids in the stomach dissolve the pill has been already tested on pigs and the ingestible injection has been able to lower blood sugar levels just like standard shots do. Steven Little, the chairman of the chemical engineering department of University of Pittsburgh said that “It’s a very clever idea, that is meant to solve a very long standing problem”</p>
<p align="justify">The only hurdle in the research at present is that it cannot be taken over an empty stomach. Hence, presently it is could be uses instead of morning insulin shots and not post meal. Also, as the capsule is made of stainless steel and biodegradable material that floats and gets excreted, there is no harm as such. There are no side effects even if it pokes the stomach wall. Gastroenterologists have been long using needles for delivering medicines for patients. Though the medicine will take around three more years before it is tested on humans and to know how the stomach responds to it if used on a daily basis.</p>
<p align="justify">
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is one of the <strong><a href="https://college.rrmch.org/">top medical colleges in Bangalore</a></strong>, India</p>
<p align="justify">*sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Genetically Modified Virus Effective in Cancer Treatment &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetically-modified-virus-effective-in-cancer-treatment-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1055</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The study published in the journal for Cancer Research states that scientists have developed a new technique in which they use a genetically modified virus for killing cancer cells and even has the ability to destroy their hiding places. Named as the enadenotucirev, this novel dual action virus targets cancer cells as well as the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/genetically-modified-virus-effective-in-cancer-treatment-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Genetically Modified Virus Effective in Cancer Treatment &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The study published in the journal for Cancer Research states that scientists have developed a new technique in which they use a genetically modified virus for killing cancer cells and even has the ability to destroy their hiding places. Named as the enadenotucirev, this novel dual action virus targets cancer cells as well as the healthy cells that are tricked into cancer cell protection by the immune system of the body called fibro-blasts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1056" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment.jpg" alt="Genetically Modified Virus Effective in Cancer Treatment" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Genetically-Modified-Virus-Effective-in-Cancer-Treatment-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The therapy used presently for killing the tricked viruses of cancer may also kill the fibroblast cells leading to toxicity. Carcinomas, the most common kind of cancer are found to start in the cells of the skin or in the tissues covering or lining internal organs like lungs, pancreas, breasts, colon, prostate and ovaries.<br />
As per Kerry Fisher of Britain’s University of Oxford there hasn’t been any way where you can kill the cancer cells and the fibroblasts that are known to protect them as well, without causing any harm to the other parts of the body. Therefore, this technique that can be used for targeting the cancer cells as well as the fibroblasts is definitely cited as a vital development in reducing the suppression inside the carcinomas as well as initiating the normal immune process.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><img class="alignnone wp-image-1057 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/rrmch.gif" alt="rrmch" width="647" height="42" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The team included some genetic instructions before publishing the study in the journal order the infected cancer cells to produce a protein called bispecific T cell engager, that has the ability to bind and stick two cells together. Here the first end is fibroblasts and the second end is T cells – a kind of immune cell that kills defective cells. The result, T cells started killing attached fibroblasts. The team also carried out the testing of the virus on a human bone marrow successfully to find that the process did not result in creating any toxicity to the rest of the body or any inappropriate activation of T cells.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The clinical trials of Enadenotucirev have already started for carcinoma treatment and in the upcoming year it will begin its clinical trials of finding out the safety and affectivity of it on people suffering from cancer.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Top Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore, Karnataka</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zika Virus &#8211; Symptoms, Causes and treatment</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/zika-virus-symptoms-causes-and-treatment/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 08:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zika Virus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zika Virus - Symptoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zika Virus causes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zika Virus treatment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1040</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Recently, Zika virus has taken a toll in Jaipur with over 42 confirmed cases. A fatal virus, Zika finds its roots in Uganda, where it was discovered in the year 1947. The same mosquito responsible for tracing yellow fever, chikungunya and dengue virus is known to transmit Zika. Thought it can be transmitted through the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/zika-virus-symptoms-causes-and-treatment/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Zika Virus &#8211; Symptoms, Causes and treatment"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Recently, Zika virus has taken a toll in Jaipur with over 42 confirmed cases. A fatal virus, Zika finds its roots in Uganda, where it was discovered in the year 1947. The same mosquito responsible for tracing yellow fever, chikungunya and dengue virus is known to transmit Zika. Thought it can be transmitted through the following besides mosquito –</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>Pregnant women to her unborn child</li>
<li>Blood Transfusion</li>
<li>Sexual intercourse</li>
<li>Possibly through saliva while kissing (may or may not)</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Zika virus can cause various disorders/ Complications like Premature birth, severe dehydration, hearing impairment, eye problems in infants, Acute Disseminated Encephalomyelitis (ADEM) and the following as well &#8211;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1041" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Zika-Virus.jpg" alt="Zika Virus - Symptoms, Causes and treatment" width="755" height="382" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Zika-Virus.jpg 755w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Zika-Virus-300x152.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Congenital malformations</strong><br />
When the virus is transmitted to the unborn child through a pregnant woman, it is bound to attack the nervous system of the child and cause microcephaly or prevent brain growth. It may damage the fetus, which could not be visible immediately but many years of birth. This virus is present in the milk of an infected mother as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Guillain Barre Syndrome</strong><br />
After the Zika virus enters the nervous system, some people tend to suffer from a disorder known as Guillain Barre Syndrome. It can also get into the brain and cause other neurological symptoms. This virus has the ability to not directly attack but get the immune system to attack the nervous system.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong><br />
The symptoms of people infected by Zika include the following</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>Fever</li>
<li>Joint pain</li>
<li>Rash</li>
<li>Nausea</li>
<li>Headache</li>
<li>Conjunctivitis</li>
<li>Chills</li>
<li>Bloodshot eyes</li>
<li>Sweating</li>
<li>Cheek Swelling</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diagnosis</strong><br />
The diagnosis of Zika can be done using a blood, saliva , semen and urine test.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Zika Treatment</strong><br />
As on date there is not treatment or vaccination available for Zika. You only can treat the symptoms using fever reducers and medicines for reducing vomiting or rash.</p>
<p><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img class="size-full wp-image-995 aligncenter" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg" alt="" width="397" height="41" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg 397w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore-300x31.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 397px) 100vw, 397px" /></a></p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Be Aware of the Silent Killer Called Ovarian Cancer</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/be-aware-of-the-silent-killer-called-ovarian-cancer/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 11:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[be aware of Ovarian Cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ovarian Cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ovarian Cancer awareness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1009</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many women aren’t aware that ovarian cancer is also known as the Silent Killer because generally no visible symptoms indicate the presence of this cancer and the symptoms surface only during the final stages. This cancer has known to affect as many as over 20K women across the world every year and due to the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/be-aware-of-the-silent-killer-called-ovarian-cancer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Be Aware of the Silent Killer Called Ovarian Cancer"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Many women aren’t aware that <strong>ovarian cancer</strong> is also known as the Silent Killer because generally no visible symptoms indicate the presence of this cancer and the symptoms surface only during the final stages. This cancer has known to affect as many as over 20K women across the world every year and due to the lack of visible symptoms indicating the cancer, it makes this cancer even scarier.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>CAUSES AND RISKS</strong><br />
The causes of this cancer are not clear as yet but family history is one of the risk factors and the women having a family member or relative with ovarian cancer or breast cancer are definitely at a higher risk of the same. Age can also be termed as one of the risk factors because most women get it after 60 -63 years. Also, the women who have had one or more pregnancies before the age of 26 are at a lower risk. The risk is lower if the number of pregnancies is higher. Even using contraceptives frequently tends to lower the risk of ovarian cancer. As per doctors there is this contraceptive hormone called DMPA or Depo pro-vera CI that if injected of more than 3 years, reduces the risk of ovarian cancer even further. Women who make use of infertility treatment drugs over a period of one year are also known to have a high risk of getting ovarian cancer. Other risk factors include obesity, hormone therapy and gynecologic surgery as in surgery of reproductive organs and getting endometriosis at the age of 30 years.</p>
<p><img class="wp-image-1010 size-medium alignleft" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-300x300.jpg" alt="Ovarian Cancer" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ovarian-cancer-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DIAGNOSIS AND STAGES</strong><br />
The doctor on examination will ask for some tests that include blood test, a CT scan or MRI as well as Laparoscopy, biopsy, abdominal fluid aspiration test or colonoscopy for that matter.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Stages</strong><br />
As per the American Cancer society ovarian cancer has four stages<br />
<strong>Stage 1</strong> – This is the preliminary stage of ovarian cancer where only the ovary or the ovaries are affected.<br />
<strong>Stage 2</strong> – This is the secondary stage where the cancer is out of the ovaries and spread around the areas like fallopian tubes, uterus, rectum or the bladder.<br />
<strong>Stage 3</strong> – This is a later stage of cancer where the cancer affects the lymph nodes, abdominal lining or even the back of the abdomen.<br />
<strong>Stage 4</strong> – The last stage of cancer where the cancer has spread to other parts of the body outside the peritoneal cavity viz. abdomen or pelvis upto the liver, fluid around the lungs or the spleen.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><b>SYMPTOMS</b><br />
The initial symptoms of<em> ovarian cancer</em> are easy to miss because they are very much similar to premenstrual syndrome. So, you have to be alert and if you find any of the below mentioned symptoms that persist for a long time then good idea is to go for checkup.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Recurring Abdominal Pain</strong><br />
If you have been experiencing stomach ache for a long time even if you don’t have your monthly cycles then its time you get it tested.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Appetite loss and Nausea</strong><br />
When ovarian cancer starts spreading around, it affects the bowel system and causes nausea. If you feel you have been experiencing and loss in your appetite or feeling full sooner than ever, check it out.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Bloating and Constipation</strong><br />
When a tumor is growing inside you even when you do not eat much you feel fuller and bloated. It can also affect your bowel movement leading to regular constipation issues.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Irregular monthly cycles</strong><br />
A tumor in the ovary will cause your monthly period to become irregular or sorts. So, if you haven’t been experiencing any irregularity in your monthly periods earlier but only lately for a while, good idea to meet up with your doctor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Frequent urination</strong><br />
If you have been making frequent trips to the bathroom for peeing then this could be the sign. Do not ignore and visit your doctor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
The treatment is based on the diagnosis of the stage of the cancer and includes procedures like surgery, chemotherapy, radiation therapy, targeted therapy as well as hormonal therapy. One or more treatments in combination are usually used depending upon the stage of the cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Surgery types</strong><br />
The extent of surgery is also based on the stage and includes removal of ovaries, fallopian tubes, uterus as well the affected surrounding tissues. Then there is de-bulking surgery and lymph node dissections also which is done to reduce the cancerous tissues if the cancer is spread beyond the pelvic region and removal of lymph nodes near the aorta respectively.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Therapy types</strong><br />
Chemotherapy is generally done post-surgery to kill the remaining cancer cells. A medication known as cytotoxic medication poisonous drugs to the cells in-order to prevent growth and division. This is a recurring process based on the cancer growth. Targeted Chemotherapy is another treatment that involves target specific function or pathways of cancer cells. Another therapy that is used as a part to treatment is <strong>Hormone therapy</strong>. It is done to cut the supply of estrogen from the cancer cells in order to slow their growth. Radiation therapy is also used for treatment of cancer and is generally used in advanced form of cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Survival</strong><br />
As the stage increases the survival rate decreases. While for Stage I there is a 90% chance of survival, for stage IV, the chance is 17%.</p>
<p>Know more about <strong><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Cancer Hospital in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
