<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>free apps for health monitor &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/free-apps-for-health-monitor/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 06:39:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Top 5 Apps To Monitor Your Health the Smart Way</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-apps-to-monitor-your-health-the-smart-way/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 06:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android apps for health monitor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best apps for health monitor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free apps for health monitor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good apps for health monitor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top 5 apps for health monitor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rrmch.org/blog/?p=370</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[One of the most common diseases in India and across the globe is the cardiovascular or heart disease. Under this definition are listed umpteen health issues related to the heart like heart infections, plaque deposits in the arteries, coronary artery disease and more. The conditions are usually a result of chocked arteries. On the brighter &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-apps-to-monitor-your-health-the-smart-way/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Top 5 Apps To Monitor Your Health the Smart Way"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">One of the most common diseases in India and across the globe is the cardiovascular or heart disease. Under this definition are listed umpteen health issues related to the heart like heart infections, plaque deposits in the arteries, coronary artery disease and more. The conditions are usually a result of chocked arteries. On the brighter side though, certain changes in lifestyle like exercising, balance diet and more can help you improve your health condition and prevent further damage to the heart.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>HEART HEALTH MONITORING APPS</strong><br />
By the way there is another good news in the regard. With the onset of mobile applications, managing hearth health is now just a few taps away. There are different apps available in market for free and also chargeable basis for download. These apps come with numerous facilities for tracking your heart health and improving it as well. Here is a run down some of the apps that you can download for monitoring your heart health on a regular basis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. INSTANT HEART RATE</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><img class="alignleft wp-image-371" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/INSTANT-HEART-RATE-1.jpg" alt="INSTANT HEART RATE" width="108" height="152" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">One of the most commonly used app, instant heart rate can be used for tracking your heart rate accurately. You simply have to place your index finger on your phones camera and in not time get data on your Heart Rate. Further, you can also view a real time chart showing your heart rhythm pace. It works on the similar technique that oximeters use. Heart fitness results are simple– fitter the heart, lower heart rate.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Use – Measuring heart rate, Monitoring Cardio workout, Realtime PPG graph<br />
<strong>Price &#8211; Free</strong><br />
Note – Camera with a flash facility for best results. For flash less camera provide good lighting</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. I- CARE HEALTH MONITOR</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><img class="alignleft wp-image-372" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/I-CARE-HEALTH-MONITOR-1.png" alt="I- CARE HEALTH MONITOR" width="107" height="107" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/I-CARE-HEALTH-MONITOR-1.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/I-CARE-HEALTH-MONITOR-1-150x150.png 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/I-CARE-HEALTH-MONITOR-1-100x100.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 107px) 100vw, 107px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This app is designed for measuring blood pressure and heart rate primarily. It also comes with an added advantage of measuring respiratory rate, pulse wave, oxygen, vision, hearing, lung capacity, color blindness and more. To use it, press the screen using your finger. Then place your index finger on the rear camera and hold until the measurements flash on screen. It accuracy rate is very high as well.<br />
Use – Blood Pressure, Heart rate, Blood Oxygen, blood lipids measurement &amp; much more<br />
<strong>Price &#8211; Free</strong><br />
Note – Test multiple times for better results as deviation in BP are possible for precise value indication.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. MY PLATE CALORIE TRACKER</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/MY-PLATE-CALORIE-TRACKER-1-1.png"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-373" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/MY-PLATE-CALORIE-TRACKER-1-1.png" alt="MY PLATE CALORIE TRACKER" width="107" height="166" /></a>They say prevention is better than cure. The same holds true for hearth health too. Hearth health is associated with lifestyle as well. One of the factors within the lifestyle that affect heart health is diet. Eating healthy and balance food can help avoid heart related issues and also help in improving heart health. My plate is a user friendly application for tracking the calories you take in on a daily basis including food and water. It comes with a bar code scanner for finding and tracking food at speed. It also provides you with a customized foods, meals and calorie goals besides keeping track of your weight.<br />
Use &#8211; Monitor &amp; manage macro nutrient consumption, track food, water, calories, weight &amp; more<br />
<strong>Price – Free</strong><br />
Note – Nothing in particular</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. PULSE POINT</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/PULSE-POINT-1.png"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-374" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/PULSE-POINT-1.png" alt="PULSE POINT" width="111" height="111" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/PULSE-POINT-1.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/PULSE-POINT-1-150x150.png 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/PULSE-POINT-1-100x100.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 111px) 100vw, 111px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This app comes with the ability to provide life saving assistance to people during heart attacks. It provides notification to the application users who have specified that they are trained in CPR. The tracker apparently uses location based services and sends CPR need alerts to the selected people or people in vicinity. It uses a sofisticated location based service and directs the said people to the location of need as well. This app is not as popular in India right now but globally it is working very well. It also is a virtual window to 911 communication centres, thus providing emergency activity access in real-time. It is currently covering hundreds of communities as well as cities abroad.<br />
Use – Emergency CPR notifications to trained application users<br />
<strong>                                                 Price &#8211; Free</strong><br />
Note &#8211; Nothing Specific</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. KARDIA BY ALIVECOR</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/KARDIA-BY-ALIVECOR-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-375" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/KARDIA-BY-ALIVECOR-1.jpg" alt="KARDIA BY ALIVECOR" width="113" height="104" /></a>An FDA Cleared and most clinically validated App, it allows you to track EKG in no time and share it with your doctor. You can also track your exercise patterns, sleep, dietary habits, shortness of breath and more. Further it provide EKG analysis and consultations of cardiologist that are certified. This app is a smart way to monitor heart health and avoid strokes by sharing the results with physician.<br />
Use &#8211; Alert users against potential heart problems on the basis of analysis<br />
<strong>Price – Not free</strong><br />
Note – Requires Kardia mobile<br />
These are just a select few of the numerous heart health monitoring applications                                                            available for androids and iphones. You can just log on and select the one that best fits                                                  your needs and requirements and take a vital step in the direction of preserving and                                                       improving your heart health.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: justify;">* Disclaimer &#8211; Sourced from the internet. Verification required</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
