<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>orthopaedic doctors in Bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/orthopaedic-doctors-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:28:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>All You Need to Know About Ganglion Cyst</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-ganglion-cyst/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopaedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganglion Cyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganglion Cyst causes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganglion Cyst symptoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganglion Cyst treatment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopaedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1051</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many of you might not have heard about this condition but it does exist and is a common condition for the age group of 20 to 40 years. A ganglion cyst is a tumor or swelling caused either on the tendon viz. the tissue that connects muscle to the bone or the top of a &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-ganglion-cyst/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All You Need to Know About Ganglion Cyst"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Many of you might not have heard about this condition but it does exist and is a common condition for the age group of 20 to 40 years. A ganglion cyst is a tumor or swelling caused either on the tendon viz. the tissue that connects muscle to the bone or the top of a joint. The cyst is sticky and colourless and looks like a sac of liquid. The size of the cyst may vary and it could feel spongy as well. There could either be on single cyst or one large one and multiple number of smaller ones around it connected by a common stalk within the deeper tissue. Also known as Bible cyst, is not harmful and around 70% people experience it in their lifetime. Ganglion cysts are very rare in age-groups less than 10 years. Ganglion cysts usually develop on the back of the hand. They are found at the joint of the wrist but can also be seen on the side of the palm. The other rare but possible sites of cyst include mucous cysts occurring right below the cuticle on the fingertip, the foot top, as pea sized bumps on the palm finger base, as well as the outer part of the ankle as well as the knee.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1052" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst.png" alt="Ganglion Cyst" width="640" height="640" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst.png 640w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst-150x150.png 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst-300x300.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst-100x100.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
As on day the causes of the cyst are not known. As per doctors it could be due to breakdown of the tissue joint as a result of some trauma. Another theory mentions joint capsule fault or in that of the tendon sheath leading to joint tissue bulge.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;">If you have a bulge or bump of changing mass.</li>
<li>If the diameter is 1-3 cm and it does not move</li>
<li>There is a sudden swelling or a gradual one</li>
<li>If it is recurring after a certain period of time</li>
<li>Ganglion cysts do cause pain followed by acute trauma even if they don’t appear.</li>
<li>If it pains it could get worse due to joint motion</li>
<li>In cysts that are connected to the tendon, you feel weakness in the finger</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Medical Advice</strong><br />
Medical evaluation of the cyst is important whether or not you have all the symptoms. This will help the doctor in making it sure and offering a suitable line of treatment. The doctor could advise on an ultrasound or test using the cyst fluid. At times even a MRI could be advised by the doctor though it is an expensive procedure.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
Ganglion Cysts can be treated with hot bags at home. Sometimes if there is pain, doctor may prescribe a pain killer as well. Surgical or cosmetic removal of cysts of bigger size can be done but they could reoccur as well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rajarajeswari Hospital</a> having high specialised<strong> <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/orthopaedics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Orthopedic Doctors in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>HOW TO PREVENT BONE INJURY?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-to-prevent-bone-injury/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 05:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopaedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopaedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=862</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As we age our bones start becoming in brittle as they tend to lose their bone density. The risk of injuries increases and hence it becomes important that we pay attention to our bone health and stay away from orthopaedic injuries. Throughout the aging process of the body, there is bone loss and old bones &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-to-prevent-bone-injury/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "HOW TO PREVENT BONE INJURY?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we age our bones start becoming in brittle as they tend to lose their bone density. The risk of injuries increases and hence it becomes important that we pay attention to our bone health and stay away from orthopaedic injuries.<br />
Throughout the aging process of the body, there is bone loss and old bones are absorbed with the creation of the new bone. The bone health depends on apparently the balance between the old and the new bones. Bone loss also happens across your lifespan when the body absorbs calcium and phosphate in high quantity from the bones.<br />
Hence, you need to be aware and work on keeping your bones strong enough. Here are a few tips you can use to keep your bones healthy throughout and decrease if not stop the rapid weakening of the bones.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/bones_with_no_personal_injury-1-1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-863" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/bones_with_no_personal_injury-1-1.png" alt="bones_with_no_personal_injury" width="555" height="556" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Avoid Addictions</strong> – Smoking and alcohol can affect your bone health hence avoid smoking as far as possible and keep your alcohol habits at bay.</p>
<p><strong>Balance your Diet</strong> – as they say you are what you eat, so keep yourself fit by eating a balanced diet and avoiding junk. Add a bit of walking, jogging or exercise to your daily routine. This will certainly make you fitter and enhance your bone health too.</p>
<p><strong>Vitamin D Profile Check</strong> – Many women after pregnancy tend to lose vitamin D from the body. As Vitamin D is required for absorbing calcium also, its an essential component as calcium is bone food. So, getting Vitamin D profile checked is advisable and if low, vitamin D supplement intake is required.</p>
<p><strong>Heath Check</strong> – A routine health check is important so as to know how your body and bones are doing. So meet up your physician and if required get your tests done to check your body and bone health. Based on the findings the doctor will recommend you further action.</p>
<p>Well, small inclusions and exclusions in your daily lifestyle can go a long way in maintaining your bone health and reducing bone injuries or spine injuries and keep you independent and strong.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>RRMCH has got the best team of<strong> orthopaedic doctors in Bangalore</strong>. RRMCH has got many reviews as <a title="Best Orthopaedic Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/orthopaedics/" target="_blank">best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore</a> by treating all kinds of RTA</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
