<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>diabetes and yeast infections &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/diabetes-and-yeast-infections/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 01:26:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Diabetes and Yeast Infections &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diabetes-and-yeast-infections-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 01:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals for diabetes in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes and yeast infections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rajarajeswari hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=649</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[There is certainly a relation between yeasts and diabetes and most logically it is sugar that relates yeast infections to diabetes. Yeast are generally found growing near mucous membranes around the skin. When there is a build up of yeast, it is called yeast infection. As yeast feeds on sugar and diabetics tend to sweat, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/diabetes-and-yeast-infections-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Diabetes and Yeast Infections &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">There is certainly a relation between yeasts and diabetes and most logically it is sugar that relates yeast infections to diabetes. Yeast are generally found growing near mucous membranes around the skin. When there is a build up of yeast, it is called yeast infection. As yeast feeds on sugar and diabetics tend to sweat, pee and secrete a lot of mucus due to high glucose levels, automatically inviting yeasts to build on and cause yeast infections. The areas where yeast grow rapidly are those with warm temperatures typically under skin folds and breasts, mouth and around genitals.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Diabetes-and-Yeast-Infections-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignright wp-image-650 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Diabetes-and-Yeast-Infections-1-300x157.jpg" alt="Diabetes and Yeast Infections" width="300" height="157" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The most common of the yeast infections with women is the vaginal infection and generally occurs in people suffering from diabetics that is not under proper control. When the diabetes is not controlled properly, it also effects the immune system adversely. Apparently, it suppresses the growth of immune proteins known as beta defensins, responsible for killing microbes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Furthermore, even after treatment, there is high possibility of re-occurrence of the infection in people with poorly controlled diabetes. This is because after colonization of the yeast in a particular area, its becomes easy for yeast to re-attack. The extra sugar levels in diabetics helps in colonization on the yeast and makes it easy for other pathogens to stick to mucous gland and skin cells as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diagnosis</strong><br />
The doctor asks for vaginal secretion sample test to confirm the vaginal yeast infection. The microscopical review of the sample is carried out for confirmation of Candida fungus in abnormal amounts. Sometimes even urine samples are tested.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
Most of the doctors prescribe anti-fungal creams that can be easily applied to the affected area. These creams are usually available over the counter. Only when creams aren’t effective is when doctors prescribe a dose of anti-fungal medication.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Home Remedies</strong><br />
Alternatively, home remedies like using oregano oil, yogurt, over the counter creams, coconut or tea tree oil for treating yeast infection are commonly tried.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Prevention</strong><br />
Prevention is always a better idea, and particularly for diabetics, wherein there is high possibility of yeast infection to reoccur. But, certain precautionary measures can help you keep the yeast infection at bay. This includes keeping body and genital dry, using clean cotton under garments and perfumed pads of good quality. As far as diet supplements are concerned, eating yogurt on a daily basis helps a lot.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Though, treating the root cause would definitely help you the most so try keeping your glucose levels under control to prevent the complications that arise due to the same.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a title="Best Hospital in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Best Hospital in Bangalore</a> when compared to all <a title="Master Health Checkups in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/health-checkups-in-india-the-good-the-bad-and-beyond/" target="_blank">private hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
