<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>public health &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/public-health/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 06:26:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Finances and Aging – The Connection</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/finances-and-aging-the-connection/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 06:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best dermatologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finances and Aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1217</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A recent study has revealed that people who have to suffer from economic hardships for even as less as 4 years are prone to ageing faster as compared to their peers who are economically stable. The researchers at the Department of Public health at the Copenhagen University of Denmark carried out a study to compare &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/finances-and-aging-the-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Finances and Aging – The Connection"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
recent study has revealed that people who have to suffer from
economic hardships for even as less as 4 years are prone to ageing
faster as compared to their peers who are economically stable.  The
researchers at the Department of Public health at the Copenhagen
University of Denmark carried out a study to compare economically
well to do, late middle aged adults and adults experiencing financial
issues. 
</p>



<p>The
study involved over 5575 adults in their late middle ages with a
benchmark hardship of 60% less than that of the national average over
22 years period. Out of these 5575, 18% were having financial
hardship during the period of 1987-2008. Lead by Rikki Lund, the team
studied and analyzed cognitive as well as physical functions like
chair rise, jump, balance, grip and strength. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Finances-and-Aging-–-The-Connection.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1218" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Finances-and-Aging-–-The-Connection.jpg 520w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Finances-and-Aging-–-The-Connection-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 520px) 100vw, 520px" /></figure>



<p>The
study found that people who experienced poverty over 4 years
performed less as compared to people of the same age who were living
without any financial problems. The findings suggest that the absence
of economic problems protects from aging faster while the opposite
not only increases ageing but also the blood CRP levels. 
</p>



<p>When
people are less capable of doing physical activities earlier than
then the others of the same age it is called accelerated aging. It
could be a result of higher inflammatory markers like C-reactive
protein (CRP) and IL-6 or poor cognitive functioning. 
</p>



<p>In
the Western society, aging population means more healthcare costs and
hence healthy ageing is promoted.  The study has results that match
the earlier studies with did show an inverse connection between
economic difficulties and physical abilities besides cognitive
difficulties that have been already reported. 
</p>



<p>Having said that, there is one story that has a different story to tell. It states that a human’s perception about economic hardships is more significant indicator and not their real financial condition.  The study does come with a few limitations though, which include factors like not considering data of various societies, not considering any other potential confounding factors responsible or even diseases and conditions that are not a result of poverty but still could affect longevity and speed ageing.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
