<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/physiotherapy-colleges-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 06:47:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Board Games Can Keep Cognitive Degradation At Bay – A Study</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/board-games-can-keep-cognitive-degradation-at-bay-a-study/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 06:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best psychiatrist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1242</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know that board games are a fun way to be engaged in play in doors particularly for kids. But, here’s some news. A new study carried out by the Researchers at Edinburgh university of United Kingdom reveals that board games could actually help Older Adults avert off their cognitive decline. The paper was &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/board-games-can-keep-cognitive-degradation-at-bay-a-study/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Board Games Can Keep Cognitive Degradation At Bay – A Study"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know that board games are a fun way to be engaged in play in
doors particularly for kids. But, here’s some news. A new study
carried out by the Researchers at Edinburgh university of United
Kingdom reveals that board games could actually help Older Adults
avert off their cognitive decline. The paper was authored by Drew
Altschul of School of philosophy, Pscychology and Language sciences
in association with Professor Deary, director of Edinburgh Lothian
Birth Cohorts and published in the Journals of Gerontology. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1243" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games-300x233.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games-768x598.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>FBHDTJ Still-life selection of board games (Monopoly, Chess, Cluedo, Scrabble) with playing cards and gambling chips</figcaption></figure>



<p>The
study was carried out on 1091 subjects born in the year 1936 for
assessment of their mental and cognitive capabilities.  The
researchers did the evaluation for cognitive functioning across ages
11, 70, 73, 79 with the help of 14 different standard cognitive
tests.</p>



<p>The
study included asking questions to participants in the age group of
70 and 76 about how many times across the week they indulged in board
games like bingo, chess, crosswords, cards, bingo and more .  The
researchers also took into account confounding factors like
education, early life cognitive function, activity levels, sex and
health issues to name a few, as a part of their analysis. 
</p>



<p>The
results unleashed that the people who were more into board games in
their later year’s post 70’s were better off maintaining their
cognitive functioning. Particularly those older adults who indulged
in analog games post 70’s showed relative less decline in cognitive
abilities across 11 and 70 years and also between the age of 70 and
79. 
</p>



<p>Altschul,
one of the study leads says “ these latest findings add to evidence
that being more engaged in activities during the life course might be
associated with better thinking skills in later life”. 
</p>



<p>While coauthor thinks that there is a possibility that there is an interpretation of results as push to start playing board games and avoid cognitive decline.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/"><strong>Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 06:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Career In India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1234</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>
A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid
in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The
study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues
at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the
electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants in Partners
biobank for the study. The study was spread across 2 years wherein
the lead author Choi and his team studied through millions of data
points in order to look into people having any depression related
diagnosis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1235" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-768x511.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>
They also calculated the genetic risk score for every participant by
combining information around every participant complete genome to
come to score that determines their genetic risk for developing
depression. The data also revealed that people with high genetic risk
score could be diagnosed about it anytime in the coming 2 years. But,
those who were active physically even with higher genetic risk of
depression were less likely to experience depression. 
</p>



<p>
As per Choi an average 35 minutes of exercise on a daily basis could
help you reduce the risk of depression and even protect you against
depression bouts in future. The findings of the study Choi said that
“our findings strongly suggest that, when it comes to depression,
genes are not destiny and that being physically active has the
potential to neutralize the added risk of future episodes in
individuals who are genetically vulnerable”.</p>



<p> Well, exercise is always a good idea because it is useful and sparing out 30 to 35 minutes for yourself every day is the least you could do for your own wellness. A fit body definitely helps to keep you mind fit. So, invest in exercising atleast half and hour a day and you’ll see the difference in your overall fitness levels soon.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>&#8220;The <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/">department of physiotherapy</a> was established in 2003 at <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital</a> to cater to the preventive, creative, therapeutic and rehabilitation needs of the rural people need was felt to impart the much needed physiotherapy vocational and rehabilitation training programme. &#8220;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medicine As a Career in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forensic science colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio diagnosis course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=688</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Medicine As a Career in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices that are available around the medicine field apart from MBBS. So, students who aren’t able to crack the NEET can try to opt for some related courses that include BDS, Physiotherapy, Phsychiatry, Pharmacy and more. So, as per your area of interest you may choose a course. One major advantage of NEET being brought into effect is that intelligent students coming from lower income groups can try to get entry into medical without paying hefty donations to colleges.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-689 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg" alt="Medicine As a Career in India" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">In case you opt for <a title="MBBS Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/course/mbbs/" target="_blank">MBBS</a>, a masters is always a good idea considering future growth. You could either opt for a MD or MS. Though being a surgeon isnt a cake walk and invovles daily encounters with patients fighting for their lives. Its a great responshibility to shoulder and a time costing too.</p>
<p align="justify">As a surgeon or a masters degree holder you need to be available to your patients anytime. It could be in the wee hours of the night as well. So, its quite a stressful and hectic work schedule that you’ll have to manage. But, the perks include immense work satisfaction with successful medical procedures and blessing from families. If surgery is not your cup of tea then you might as well opt for MD in areas like radiology, anaesthesiology, paediatrics, forensic medicine and more.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, if not MBBS than the option of <a title="Physiotherapy Career in India" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/" target="_blank">Physiotherapy</a>, <a title="Dental College in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrdch.org/" target="_blank">BDS</a>, Ayurvedic medicine, Homeopathy, Veterinary and Pharmacy are definitely some of the good choices around medicine. A masters degree with these streams can offer rewarding career prospects.</p>
<p align="justify">Coming down to the bottom line, medical education does blow a hole into your pocket and for students coming from middle income and lower income groups, its not an easy way ahead. But, with the help of student loans, you may as well manage to realize your medical education dreams. Though, it is important to have indepth information on the student loan interest, payback procedure and time for repayment in detail, needs to be known particularly when you are planning to pursue higher education abroad.</p>
<p align="justify">Medical is undoubtedly a lucrative career but having said that it does come with its own cons which need to be considered before taking a plunge into it.</p>
<p align="justify">know about leading <a title="Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">medical colleges in Bangalore </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Rising Demand for Occupational Therapists in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-rising-demand-for-occupational-therapists-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 07:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occupational Therapists in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occupational Therapy in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=665</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Over the years Occupational therapy has garnered a lot of eye balls and youth seem to be interested in this career that not just pays but gives immense work satisfaction as well. The work of an occupational therapist involves around helping physically and mentally challenged people to manage themselves independently. This includes performing daily chores, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-rising-demand-for-occupational-therapists-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Rising Demand for Occupational Therapists in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Over the years Occupational therapy has garnered a lot of eye balls and youth seem to be interested in this career that not just pays but gives immense work satisfaction as well. The work of an occupational therapist involves around helping physically and mentally challenged people to manage themselves independently. This includes performing daily chores, play, work and more.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Occupational-Therapists-in-India-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-666" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Occupational-Therapists-in-India-1-1.jpg" alt="Occupational Therapy in India" width="623" height="283" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">For becoming an <em>Occupational therapist</em> you need to opt for Bachelors in Occupational Therapy degree course after 12th Science. It is a four year course and is offered by numerous medical colleges across India. Some of them offer direct admissions on the basis of percentage while for some you need to crack the entrance.</p>
<p align="justify">The syllabus includes a foundation course in research methodology besides an amalgamation of subjects from psychology, orthopaedics, psychiatry, pharmacology, anatomy, physiology, surgery combined with ergonomics and occupational therapy. After completion of the four years course you need to undergo a six months full time clinically oriented training internship program. After which you can start working as a professional or carry on with your PG diploma, masters and doctorate.</p>
<p align="justify">One major reason behind the rising demand also lies in the fact that in India only 20 institutions offering 9 graduate programs for occupational therapy. This number seems to be a meager one as compared to the leap frogging number of patients suffering from physical and mental disabilities. Hence, as far as the job opportunities are concerned, there is undoubtedly immense scope in both private and public sectors. You may either work with hospitals, schools, public healthcare institutions or carry out private practice in a clinic or alongside other specialists.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, occupational therapy is no child’s play but beyond a profession that offers a lucrative career, it is more about community service. Occupational therapists train families and care takers to deal with patients having disabilities in a positive way, thus helping them become independent, productive and lead a normal life.</p>
<h1 class="entry-title">Other post &#8211; <a title="physiotherapy colleges in bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/" target="_blank">Career in Physiotherapy in India</a></h1>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Career in Physiotherapy in India &#8211; Promising or not?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 05:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best bpt colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bpt course in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career in physiotherapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career in physiotherapy in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Career In India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rrmch.org/blog/?p=389</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[With pollution clogging up the air and chemicals degrading the quality of vegetables and greens, increased stress levels due to constant workloads, early age strokes, accidents while commuting, lifestyle diseases like obesity and more are taking a toll on people. Rehabilitation is slowly and steadily gaining importance in the healthcare sector. These days most of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Career in Physiotherapy in India &#8211; Promising or not?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">With pollution clogging up the air and chemicals degrading the quality of vegetables and greens, increased stress levels due to constant workloads, early age strokes, accidents while commuting, lifestyle diseases like obesity and more are taking a toll on people. Rehabilitation is slowly and steadily gaining importance in the healthcare sector. These days most of the multi-specialty hospitals have a rehabilitation centre with qualified Physiotherapists for treatment and therapy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Physiotherapy-Career-In-India-1-1.jpg"><img class="wp-image-390 aligncenter" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Physiotherapy-Career-In-India-1-1.jpg" alt="Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore" width="569" height="494" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Experts are already forecasting the immense possibilities for expansion and growth of Physiotherapy. The career is definitely a promising one, considering the fact that even people have realized the potential of physiotherapy in significantly improving quality of life by working on body mobilization.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">But, before you decide to take your plunge into this field which for sure offers total work satisfaction and is miles away from being monotonous in nature, you need to sit down and think about flip-side of the coin. You need to be aware that this career involves working with people of all ages and mental as well as physical disabilities or challenges. From kids to elderly, mentally challenged to accident victims, general populace to criminals, anyone for that matter could be your patient. Dealing with all kinds of people also means dealing with their tempers. So, primarily you need to have loads of patience and ability to keep calm during stressed times. It is a bit of physical work also because you need to demonstrate the exercises or body moves to the patients. This could be physically draining at times as well. So, take your decision about pursuing the career only after contemplating on these facts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">After giving it a thought, if you still feel passionate about pursuing the career, go ahead. Depending upon your interest you may either go for a Bachelors in Physiotherapy, Masters in Physiotherapy or you many are interested in doing research of taking up teaching as a profession. A doctorate is always advisable. In the US and UK, there is a high demand for Physiotherapists compared to India where the sun seems to be shining on this profession though its only into its initial growth phase. So, taking up a doctorate or a specialization in the field in an overseas university definitely would open doors to umpteen opportunities overseas for this profession. Even the payscale oversees is significantly high compared to India.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In India as a <a title="Physiotherapist in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/" target="_blank">physiotherapist</a> you may get to work in private hospitals, rehabilitation centres, defence establishments, sports and fitness centres, as private consultant to corporates, private practice at your own clinic or with the government hospitals, old age home, mental healthcare centres and more. The work timings are generally good and flexible to an extent. The good part is this profession does not require working during odd hours of the night, etc. So, you get ample time to spend with your family.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, <a title="Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/" target="_blank">Physiotherapy</a> is a challenging field but it is interesting and self satisfying as well. If it interests you a lot and you want to work for serving people and augmenting their health and fitness levels, then this profession is the right choice for you.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">* Disclaimer – Sourced from the internet. Verification required</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
