<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>best medical college in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/best-medical-college-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 09:33:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Medical College Admissions 2019 &#8211; 2020</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medical-college-admissions-2019-2020/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 09:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2019 medical colleges admissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs admissions 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college admissions 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical college admissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1106</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A career in medicine has by far topped the list of career choices if not amongst students then definitely amongst parents. In India, particularly medicine has been a very reputed career choice. Though times are slowly changing and parents and students are opening their minds up to careers that are more about what their children &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medical-college-admissions-2019-2020/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Medical College Admissions 2019 &#8211; 2020"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">A career in medicine has by far topped the list of career choices if not amongst students then definitely amongst parents. In India, particularly medicine has been a very reputed career choice. Though times are slowly changing and parents and students are opening their minds up to careers that are more about what their children are inclined to and not their own interests. Still, Medicine remains the most sought after career choices.</p>
<p align="justify">There are numerous colleges across India but before you select the most suitable one for your child or as a student for yourself, but it is advisable to make a checklist of points you need to make, shortlist a few colleges as per your priority and then narrow down to the final one or two.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1107" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020.jpg" alt="mbbs admissions 2019" width="998" height="320" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020.jpg 998w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020-300x96.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020-768x246.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Well, yes primarily to open the gateway to any medical college, you need to crack the NEET code but once you clear the NEET UG entrance exam, you can start thinking about the college you wish to get admitted to. The other exams include All India Institute of Medical Sciences for MBBS (AIIMS MBBS) and Jawaharlal Institute of Postgraduate Medical Education and Research (JIPMER MBBS) entrance exams. In India MBBS colleges offer over 66K seats across over 470 colleges in India. AIIMS with 8 campuses under its roof offers over 800 seats. There’s a counselling procedure done after NEET.</p>
<p align="justify"><b>Infrastructure</b> – A college with good infrastructure is the need of the hour. So, it’s always advisable that you primarily shortlist a few colleges and then visit the college to check out the infrastructure facilities and amenities most importantly that of the hospital because all the learning is going to come from there. It’s very important because you will be primarily living out of your comfort zone if you are taking admissions away from home. So, getting into a college that has a good setup is a good idea.</p>
<p align="justify"><b>Rankings </b>– Though rankings of medical college are usually based on the number of years the college has been in existence as well as the hospital reputation, it should not be the main criteria for evaluation. If the hospital is working well and has a good number of patient load, it will definitely help you gain practical experience.</p>
<p align="justify"><b>Bonds</b> – It’s a criteria you need to be aware off atleast. There are some colleges which want students to sign bonds for a mandatory internship. There is always a mention of the same in the brochure of the medical institutes. So, before you choose a college do go through the information pertaining to the bonds.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><img class="alignnone wp-image-1057 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/rrmch.gif" alt="rrmch" width="647" height="42" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><b>Location</b> – Yes, location is one point to consider and for many it could be one of the vital points. Primarily because you might be stepping out of your home or comfort zone for the first time and hence, considering the location criteria is advisable. Another important reason being that the MBBS course is over 5 years and considering the duration and the workload you’ll be having while doing the course, you might not want to lose your valuable time in commuting or feeling nostalgic about living away from home.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, finally, the student and their parents need to narrow down to one college and particularly it’s the student’s prerogative and choice when it comes to selection of college.</p>
<p align="justify">
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Madarosis &#8211; A Condition That Causes Hair Loss of Eyelashes and Eyebrows</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/madarosis-a-condition-that-causes-hair-loss-of-eyelashes-and-eyebrows/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 07:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best dermatologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hair Loss of Eyebrows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hair Loss of Eyelashes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hair Loss of Eyelashes and Eyebrows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Madarosis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skin specialist in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1096</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A condition that is as rare as one in 500 people suffering from it, is the condition called Madarosis, that leads to loss of hair of the eyelash and eyebrows. The term was initially coined only for loss of eye lashes but now it is used even for loss of hair of the eyebrow. Known &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/madarosis-a-condition-that-causes-hair-loss-of-eyelashes-and-eyebrows/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Madarosis &#8211; A Condition That Causes Hair Loss of Eyelashes and Eyebrows"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A condition that is as rare as one in 500 people suffering from it, is the condition called Madarosis, that leads to loss of hair of the eyelash and eyebrows. The term was initially coined only for loss of eye lashes but now it is used even for loss of hair of the eyebrow. Known to generally not cause scars this condition can lead to hair loss of one or both eyebrows, but in rare cases it could lead to scarring as well. Madarosis also known to be an alert for complex body diseases both complex body and dermatological.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also, the role of eyelashes is to protect the eyes from foreign bodies and eyebrows of to protect eye’s bony ridges and hence is critical to the health of the eye.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Madarosis.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1097" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Madarosis.jpg" alt="Madarosis" width="600" height="450" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Madarosis.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Madarosis-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>MADAROSIS SYMPTOMS</strong><br />
The preliminary symptoms is that the eyelashes turn brittle leading to eyelash fall. The symptoms include eyelid itching and burning sensation as well as swelling, thinning as well as hair loss from other parts of the body.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>MADAROSIS CAUSES</strong><br />
The condition is said to be caused due to many other underlying diseases and health conditions like Trauma, Burns, Psychiatric condition called trichotillomania, eyelid infection like syphilis, leprosy or herpes, chronic blepharitis and eyelid neoplasm. Even genetic conditions like ichthyosiform erythroderma, ehlers-danlos syndrome, cryptophthalmos as well as ectodermal dysplasia are known to cause madarosis</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>DIAGNOSIS</strong><br />
The doctor examines the patient physically and checks the scalp, eyebrows and eyelids as well as facial skin. The tests done for the same include skin skin scrapping for fungal infection diagnosis, skin swab for bacterial infections diagnosis, dermoscopy for skin examination with the help of a magnifier as well as blood tests.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
The treatment is based on diagnosis and includes the use of medications, borax for infections, biotin supplements for hair repair, cosmetic treatment like eyebrow tattoos, artificial eyebrows, to name a few.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Home-remedies like opting for a protein rich diet, care with doing and choosing makeup and use of castor oil on the eyebrows and eyelashes could help you get rid of infections.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Know about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH Bangalore</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
