<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>medical college in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/medical-college-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 09:32:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance – Check Out Their Amazing Health Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eat-indian-jujube-in-abundance-check-out-their-amazing-health-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 09:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Indian Jujube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1228</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The winter has almost arrived, and with it has arrived the season of Indian Jujube, or as we call them locally BER. Not many are aware that they are also known as the Korean date or Chinese date or even Indian Date. A bite sized fruit, it is relished by many but very few of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eat-indian-jujube-in-abundance-check-out-their-amazing-health-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance – Check Out Their Amazing Health Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The winter has
almost arrived, and with it has arrived the season of Indian Jujube,
or as we call them locally BER.  Not many are aware that they are
also known as the Korean date or Chinese date or even Indian Date. 
</p>



<p>A bite sized fruit, it is relished by many but very few of us really know about its umpteen health benefits.   Here’s a run down some of them –</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-1024x678.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1229" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-300x199.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-768x509.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Rich Source of Vitamin C</strong> – Jujube’s are known to be
	loaded with vitamin C as well as antioxidents and we all know the
	role of Vitamin C in revitalizing our skin, building immunity as
	well as fighting free radicals. Just consuming around 100 gms of
	Jujube can give you 69 mg of Vitamin C. Hence, eating jujube could
	be a great way of getting vitamin C as our body is not capable of
	producing the same. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Bone
	Strength</strong> – Want strong bones? Eat Jujubes. Yes, you read that
	right. Jujubes are also power packed with calcium, iron as well as
	phosphorous thus helping in improving. Hence, it’s a tasty
	alternative for people with oesteoprosis and bone degrading.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Anxiety
	soother</strong> – This fruit is known to have a calming effect on the
	brain as well as the nervous system. Jujube as well as its oil
	extract is known have sedative effects and relax your body down by
	working on the hormonal levels. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Constipation
	Relief</strong> – Jujube is known to provide great relief to people
	suffering from chronic constipation. As per statistics over 20%
	Indians suffer from chronic constipation and still its not been on
	the list of concerns. As jujube’s are a rich source of fibre, they
	help in digestion and regulation of bowel movements. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Sleep
	Well</strong> – Jujubes are rich in antioxidant pythochemicals,
	sapnins, flavonoids and polysaccharides known to have sedative
	properties. Hence, it helps in sleeping well by calming the nerves.
	So, people if you are suffering from insomnia, try jujubes.
</li></ol>



<p>Well, as this fruit is rich in fibre as well, its also considered to aid people looking at weight loss.  Perhaps, its high time you make it an integral part of your fruit consumption or diet may be.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Top Medical College in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Know About The Vital Screening Test That You Could Ignore!</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/know-about-the-vital-screening-test-that-you-could-ignore/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 06:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vital Screening Test]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1110</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In the times when pesticides and carcinogenic stuff has become a daily part of our life and is laying the path for different types of cancers, preventive screenings can help a lot in catching cancer in time and improving the quality of life. Today people are very much aware about preventive screenings at an early &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/know-about-the-vital-screening-test-that-you-could-ignore/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Know About The Vital Screening Test That You Could Ignore!"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">In the times when pesticides and carcinogenic stuff has become a daily part of our life and is laying the path for different types of cancers, preventive screenings can help a lot in catching cancer in time and improving the quality of life.</p>
<p align="justify">Today people are very much aware about preventive screenings at an early age but due to lack of time and hectic work schedules and other priorities you tend to ignore a few. Definitely, people are taking cancer screenings seriously.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1111" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test.jpg" alt="Vital Screening Test" width="600" height="600" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Vital-Screening-Test-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">One such condition is Osteoporosis. In this condition the body loses a lot of bone and makes very less or sometimes it could be both together. In Osteoporosis, bones become brittle. They could break even if there is a simple fall or at times even due to sneezing.</p>
<p align="justify">As per health experts early detection and intervention can help you curb the progression of the condition with the help of medicines as well as required life style changes. To detect osteoporosis, you need to go through the bone mineral density (BMD) test.</p>
<p align="justify">The diagnosis can help you detect the condition, the risk factors as well as the tracking over the course of your treatment. The test that is commonly taken and is painless in nature is the Central DXA test or the Dual energy X-ray absorptiometry test similar to X-ray. This test is recommended for the 65 and above women. As of now age based recommendations are not there for men. As per the NIH below 65 women who are at the risk of fracture also need to get tested.</p>
<p align="justify">Risk factors include low body weight, genes, early menopause, addictions like smoking and rheumatoid arthritis disorder. People with family history of osteoporosis are at the risk of getting it early on in their 40’s. So, thinking that osteoporosis can only occur post 65 years is not apparently true.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, get a little more aware and serious around some conditions that might not be life threatening but still vital because it could affect quality of life by getting you into painful problems.</p>
<p align="justify">
<p align="justify">Just know about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a></strong>, Contact for <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medical-college-admissions-2019-2020/">Medical College Admissions in Bangalore</a> &#8230; <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/medical-admission-mbbs-ms-md-phd/">Apply online</a></strong></p>
<p align="justify">
<p align="justify">*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Technique of Knocking Out Genes &#8211; A Sneak Peek</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/technique-of-knocking-out-genes/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 10:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=737</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Knocking out genes is a technique which researchers and scientists use when the want to find out which gene is responsible for production of which protein. In a human body there are around 20,500 different genes that each gene is responsible for making a protein because they are known to be the building blocks for &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/technique-of-knocking-out-genes/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Technique of Knocking Out Genes &#8211; A Sneak Peek"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Knocking out genes is a technique which researchers and scientists use when the want to find out<br />
which gene is responsible for production of which protein. In a human body there are around 20,500 different genes that each gene is responsible for making a protein because they are known to be the building blocks for different components of the body be it muscles or bones or brain and more. Apparently, our body is made up proteins. Every gene is responsible for producing a different type of protein and the knocking out technique only helps scientists figure out who is responsible for what.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Technique-of-Knocking-Out-Genes-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-738" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Technique-of-Knocking-Out-Genes-1-1.jpg" alt="The Technique of Knocking Out Genes - A Sneak Peek" width="860" height="460" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Knocking out a Gene</strong><br />
The scientists first find out genes with some serious mutation or mistake or create one if needed. These genes are dud genes and do not contribute a bit in production of protein. Now, this gene is injected into the DNA of a healthy cell. The scientists attach a tag called reporter gene to it for identification purpose of whether they have been accepted by the cell. Another identification of reporter genes is that the proteins they produce often glow in blue or green. The scientists apparently fool the DNA in a way. A DNA a we know is made up of long strand of genes and these genes can get damaged but the DNA has an inbuilt mechanism to fix the issue. With the help of a cellular tool box the scientist insert the knocked out gene into the DNA. They do this very smartly by making it look like a perfect copy of the surrounding gene that is to be replaced in that DNA. This disguise of sorts fold the DNA repair system and its swaps the dud gene for the old healthy gene, thus knocking out the original gene.</p>
<p align="justify">Some times scientists do not have to swap the gene fully. They can simply insert the reporter gene into the DNA they wish to get rid of, randomly. Now, the reporter gene is wedged in the middle of the old gene. Now, there is an all new piece of DNA inside and if a cell goes to read the gene, the instructions would not make sense to the cell due to its presence there. It would not use the gene to make a protein.</p>
<p align="justify">The scientist keep a watch on the process. They observe the working in case it is yeast or bacterium but if it is an embryo, scientists observe on how the animal or plant growth differs from other normal ones.<br />
Today, scientists use different techniques to knock out the genes of any organism they want to. It could be mice or bacteria or for that matter even plants that have knocked out genes. Well, scientists today can knock out even human cells growing in the labs.</p>
<p align="justify"><a title="RRMCH - Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org" target="_blank">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</a> &#8211; MOTTO: Availability of medical facilities is of utmost importance. We aim to serve the healthcare requirements needs to the medically unreached population. Through this, we provide quality <a title="Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org" target="_blank">medical</a>, paramedical, <a title="Nursing Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrcn.org/" target="_blank">nursing</a> and allied <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank">healthcare</a> education, excellent and compassionate hospital services with state of the art facilities as well as to carry out health research for the betterment of the humankind in tune with the holistic values of the institution.</p>
<p align="justify">*source from the internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
