<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>best eye hospital in india &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/best-eye-hospital-in-india/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 06:22:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dark Spot on the sclera of eye? What is it!</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dark-spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-what-is-it/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 06:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser eye operations in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=878</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When there is any spot on the sclera, it is prominent because of the white background. Hence, it catches your notice mostly within no time of surfacing. So, if you are one of those who has recently discovered a spot on the white area of your eye or sclera as it is called, then here’s &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dark-spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-what-is-it/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dark Spot on the sclera of eye? What is it!"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">When there is any spot on the sclera, it is prominent because of the white background. Hence, it catches your notice mostly within no time of surfacing. So, if you are one of those who has recently discovered a spot on the white area of your eye or sclera as it is called, then here’s what you need to know about the same.<br />
Usually, these freckles or spots are harmless but if it has occurred suddenly out of the blue, then it’s advisable to consult an ophthalmologist because it could be a sign of something critical or cancer as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Dark-Spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-879" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Dark-Spot-on-the-sclera-of-eye-1-1.jpg" alt="Dark Spot on the sclera of eye" width="600" height="451" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>SPOTS, TYPES AND CAUSES</strong><br />
These spots unlike moles are more of a lesion or nevus, mostly flat or may be slightly raised in either black, pink or brown color. Sometimes this nevus could be pigmentation free as well. This nevus could also occur in tissue beneath the retina and needs a special lamp to view.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also known as pigmented tumors, these spots or freckles are almost harmless. The most common of the eye tumors is Congenital nevi besides others like conjunctival melanoma and melanosis. Nevi is caused due pigmentation cells or over-growth of melanocytes. Most of the people who have nevi have it since their birth or it surfaces in their early childhood itself. Usually, the spot might not be noticeable until puberty because at this age it becomes bigger and darker too.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While primary acquired melanosis usually occurs in the middle to people with fair skin and suddenly too, the rarest form is the Conjunctival melanosis and it either occurs suddenly or as primary acquired melanosis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>TREATMENT</strong><br />
As per the eye cancer network most eye pigmented lesions are benign in nature and practically harmless. But, the eye specialists need to monitor these lesions to check for any signs of shape change and growth. Particular attention needs to be paid on whether the lesion extends to the cornea or develops an increase in blood supply. As compared to malignant lesions the benign nevi grow at a slower rate. In case there is any change in the shape or size of the lesion the doctor might advise a biopsy but congenital nevi becoming cancerous is extremely rare even if it shows a change in shape or size.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, dark spots in the sclera are usually not a matter of grave concern but it’s always advisable that you consult your<a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank"> ophthalmologist</a> to get a clear idea of the lesion or nevi and further line of action.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eye Lid Surgery in India &#8211; An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eye-lid-surgery-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 12:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=833</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As we age, it shows and one area that is show clearly is the region around the eyes. One of the prominent difference we see is in the upper eyelids, under eyes and eye brows, which tend to sag with age. Here is the good news, even if age causes the mentioned differences in eyes, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eye-lid-surgery-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Eye Lid Surgery in India &#8211; An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">As we age, it shows and one area that is show clearly is the region around the eyes. One of the prominent difference we see is in the upper eyelids, under eyes and eye brows, which tend to sag with age. Here is the good news, even if age causes the mentioned differences in eyes, they can be corrected with a surgery called blepharoplasty. It is popularly known as eye lift and is done by women specifically for enhancement of their looks or appearance by fixing their droopy and dull eyelids. The surgery procedure involves removal of fat pockets and excess skin from upper and lower lids. Though, patients who already have ophthalmic issues are excluded from taking up this surgery.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-834 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-300x144.jpg" alt="Eye Lid Surgery in India" width="300" height="144" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-300x144.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1-768x370.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Eyelid-Surgery-1.jpg 889w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">This is a sort of cosmetic surgery done for alteration of eye aesthetics in a way. Here what kind of corrections it can do for your eyes.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>1. Dull or fatigued eyes</strong> – With this eyelift surgery the work on correcting eyes that make the person look older and tired than actually she is</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>2. Excess skin on upper eye lid</strong> &#8211; If you have excess skin on upper eye lid it can also obstruct your eyesight. So, this surgery helps in removing the excess skin or the fat pockets there that can obstruct the eyesight.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>3. Puffy Upper Eyelids</strong> – Sometimes puppy eyes are result of genetics than sleeplessness. Blepharoplasty surgery can fix this issue</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>NON INVASIVE OPTION</strong><br />
For some doctors might recommend the non-invasive procedure as compared to the invasive one. This is considered to be a more appropriate course of treatment as well compared to the invasive one. The non -invasive treatment involves usage of Botox injections for enhancing looks by reducing wrinkles. Even facial fillers are used in this treatment for the purpose of reducing the dark circles and eye bags.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>RESULTS</strong><br />
The results of the surgery are never instant. Primarily, you may see inflammation and swelling around the area where it is done and it would generally take a couple of days to a week to subside. Once the healing occurs best results are seen.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong><a title="medical colleges in bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> <a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">Ophthalmology(eye) department</a></strong> is registered under District Blindness Control Society and has a successful record of offering the best possible care for our patients. We conduct eye screening camps every month at Mudaliar Sangha, Rajajinagar in Bangalore. We also provide treatment free for patients who can’t afford to pay their daily bills. We provide services to about 100 patients every day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brain Has Eyes Too &#8211; A sneak Peek Into Neurons</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-has-eyes-too-a-sneak-peek-into-neurons/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 09:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best eye hospital in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ent hospitals in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser operation for eyes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=704</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yes, that is true. Nicknamed as ‘Jennifer Aniston’ a neuron based on the participant study which showed that one of the neuron of his brain lit up on recognizing the face of particular people like Jennifer Aniston or Hillary Clinton. So, this neuron was named after Jennifer Aniston. This report further revealed that one single &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-has-eyes-too-a-sneak-peek-into-neurons/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Brain Has Eyes Too &#8211; A sneak Peek Into Neurons"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, that is true. Nicknamed as ‘Jennifer Aniston’ a neuron based on the participant study which showed that one of the neuron of his brain lit up on recognizing the face of particular people like Jennifer Aniston or Hillary Clinton. So, this neuron was named after Jennifer Aniston. This report further revealed that one single specific cell lit up whenever a person’s certain conscious experience was concerned. This throws further light on the response of brain cells the relation of the activities with consciousness. Though, understanding the scope and science of human consciousness is a mystery that is yet to be unfolded and even researchers cannot say with surety if these neurons lead to conscious thoughts.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Brain-Has-Eyes-Too-A-sneak-Peek-Into-Neurons-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-705" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Brain-Has-Eyes-Too-A-sneak-Peek-Into-Neurons-1-1.jpg" alt="Brain Has Eyes Too - A sneak Peek Into Neurons" width="665" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>There were studies around the same carried out in 2008 which used a masking technique. This technique showed an image of a popular person like Aniston for 16 milliseconds immediately followed by a pattern Image muddling the face afterimage on the retina, thus making it rather hard for the brain to register what it saw. Later on in another study that used a method for hiding images from participants awareness. The phenomenon used for the experiment is called attentional blink wherein two target images are shown in a high speed streaming along with some other similar images. This results in a person often not able to recognize the second image targeted.</p>
<p>A similar study was carried out over a list of 21 patients under epilepsy and brains were fitted with special treatment electrodes. The trial included showing 14 different images predetermined by the scientist as familiar to the person. Further each one had a particular activity of specific brain cell. Now, when the trial was conducted, the researchers asked the participants to concentrate on two target images of the 14. All the images would later be flashed on the screen for 150 milliseconds. The medial temporal lobe was under constant monitoring during and after the trail and the researchers queried the participants if they had seen two images of familiar faces.</p>
<p>Every cell with unique signature was studied as it lit up and helped researchers link a brain cell pattern to particular images and had the ability to tell about the image represented even though<br />
the participants are not aware of it.</p>
<p>Furthermore, research work is on as the researchers believe that they are at the intersection of perception and memory and investigation was needed to find out the results of direct stimulation of neurons.</p>
<p><a title="Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/ophthalmology/" target="_blank">Best Eye Hospitals in Bangalore</a>   <a title="Best Neuro Hospital in India" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/" target="_blank">Best Neuro Hospital in India</a>  <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">Best Hospitals in Bangalore</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
