<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>College Blog &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/category/college_blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 06:30:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Corona Virus – Facts Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/corona-virus-facts-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 06:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona Virus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1260</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As the corona virus or Wuhan virus scare is catching like wild fire and as the number of infected people across the world. The cases in china are about to reach 15000 and over 300 people are said to be already affected. The virus is on the spread across the world as it is highly &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/corona-virus-facts-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Corona Virus – Facts Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>
As the corona virus or Wuhan
virus scare is catching like wild fire and as the number of infected
people across the world. The cases in china are about to reach 15000
and over 300 people are  said to be already affected. The virus is on
the spread across the world as it is highly contagious and the UN has
already declared it as a medical emergency.  While the world is on
high alert and is also flown out their nationals from the country,
the clouds of this virus causing a havoc are already mounting. Here
are a few tips to keep the corona virus infection at bay. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Corona-Virus.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1261" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Corona-Virus.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Corona-Virus-300x167.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Corona-Virus-768x427.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<ol><li>

	Wash your hands with soap and
	water on regular basis or with alcohol based disinfectant
	</li><li>

	While sneezing or coughing
	cover your mouth with a tissue or hand
	</li><li>

	Avoid close contact with
	people suffering from cold or flu like symptoms 
	
	</li><li>

	Do not eat under cooked meat
	or eggs
	</li><li>

	Avoid contact with farm
	animals or the wild
	</li><li>

	Stay indoors at home when
	sick
	</li><li>

	Clean all objects and
	surfaces that are dirty or touched
	</li><li>

	Avoid touching your mouth,
	eyes or hands with dirty hands
	</li><li>

	Use a mask whenever outdoor 
	
	</li><li>

	Always carry a disinfectant
	along when outdoor
</li></ol>



<p>
There’s also a debate around
the transfer of the virus without showing symptoms. While the Germans
are firm that asymptomatic transmission is possible, nothing is yet
officially conveyed.</p>



<p> Well, as the cases in China keep exploding as the days pass by, the risk of it spreading across continents is always there. As of now the process of developing a vaccine for controlling the virus is on but it might take almost a year before it comes to the pharmacy. Until then, prevention is the only way out. So, stay safe and clean to keep the condition out of harm’s way.  </p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Top Leading Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>



<p>Sourced from Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>BRAT Diet For Stomach Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brat-diet-for-stomach-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 06:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brat Diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brat Diet For Stomach Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1257</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[If You are suffering from stomach related issues then, one of the most recommended diets is the BRAT diet. For the uninitiated, BRAT is an acronym standing for Banana, rice, Applesauce and toast. The reason behind recommending these foods when having stomach problems is that they are light on the stomach and bland as well. &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brat-diet-for-stomach-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BRAT Diet For Stomach Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>
If You are suffering from
stomach related issues then, one of the most recommended diets is the
BRAT diet. For the uninitiated, BRAT is an acronym standing for
Banana, rice, Applesauce and toast. The reason behind recommending
these foods when having stomach problems is that they are light on
the stomach and bland as well. Stomach problems can lead to nausea,
vomiting, diarrhea and fatigue and the BRAT diet definitely plays a
role in keeping you energized without side effects. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/BRAT-Diet.jpg" alt="Brat Diet For Stomach Health" class="wp-image-1258" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/BRAT-Diet.jpg 770w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/BRAT-Diet-300x195.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/BRAT-Diet-768x499.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>
The BRAT diet is about eating
bananas, applesauce, rice and toast in abundance as these foods are
bland I taste and easy on your digestive systems. Well, if you cannot
eat the same food over and over until you get well, you may choose
from other bland foods like weak tea, apple juice or soda, broth,
boiled potatoes as well as cooked cereals.</p>



<p>
Though you need to avoid dairy
products like milk and more as well as oily, fried and spicy food.
You also need to avoid raw or uncooked food as well as food that is
very hot or very cold. Stay away from alcohol as well as coffee or
other foods containing caffeine. 
</p>



<p>
Once 24 hours of illness have
passed you may consume clear liquids again, sipping on at an interval
of 10 minutes. Try drinking water, chicken broth, apple juice and
similar liquids. 
</p>



<p>
Although the BRAT diet is a
common recommendation by Doctors in USA, children and infants are
excluded form the recommendation. 
</p>



<p>
The reason being that these
food cannot fulfil the body requirements in terms of micro nutrients
and proteins. 
</p>



<p> But, if you are suffering from severe bout of diarrhea then you need to seek medical assistance immediately. Also in case of severe abdominal or rectal pain, black or bloody stools or a high fever or above 102 F.  </p>



<p>Just know about the <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</strong></a>, Bangalore</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weight Loss After 50 Years Of Age Reduces Breast Cancer Risk</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/weight-loss-after-50-years-of-age-reduces-breast-cancer-risk/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 06:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breast cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer treatment hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1251</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Breast cancer is one of the most common cancers amongst women in India and worldwide. A recent study about women who lost weight at 50 and maintained a healthy weight thereon showed a decreased risk of breast cancer as compared to women with more weight. This study is therefore a way to help women work &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/weight-loss-after-50-years-of-age-reduces-breast-cancer-risk/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weight Loss After 50 Years Of Age Reduces Breast Cancer Risk"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Breast cancer</strong> is one of the most common cancers amongst women in India and worldwide. A recent study about women who lost weight at 50 and maintained a healthy weight thereon showed a decreased risk of breast cancer as compared to women with more weight.  This study is therefore a way to help women work around prevention of cancer.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-1024x683.jpg" alt="Breast Cancer Risk" class="wp-image-1252" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Weightloss-After-50-Years-Of-Age-Reduces-Breast-Cancer-Risk-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
study is published in the Journal of the National Cancer Institute.
In USA over two third of the adult women are overweight or obese. The
study was carried out by the researchers at the American Cancer
Society, Harvard T. H. Chan School of Public Health using the Pooling
Project of Prospective Studies of Diet and Cancer (DCPP) in order to
determine the connection between sustained loss of weight after
menopause or later adulthood and the risk of breast cancer.</p>



<p>The
study involved over 180,000 women over 50 years of age across 10
studies. The sample size is huge and this analysis is the first to
assess the breast cancer risk impact over sustained weight loss. The
study did examine weight three times across 10 years period viz. at
the time of enrollment, post five years and again four years
thereafter. 
</p>



<p>The
results showed that women who were able to reduce more weight in
later adulthood and sustained it were able to lower the risk of
breast cancer. The women who were able to shed around 9 kg’s of
weight and then game some of it but not all did show a significant
reduction in breast cancer risk. 
</p>



<p> The lead author of the study Lauren Teras, PhD says ‘These findings may be a strong motivator for the two thirds of American women who are overweight to lose some of that weight. Even if you gain weight after age 50, it is not too late to lower your risk of breast cancer”.</p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>RRMCH is one of the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/"><strong>Best Cancer Treatment Hospital in Bangalore India</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp – A Rare Pregnancy Rash</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/plaques-of-pregnancy-or-puppp-a-rare-pregnancy-rash/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 05:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obg specialist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaques of Pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1248</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know that pregnancy can bring along a lot of side effects also like fatigue, nausea, vomiting and more. But, one rare condition that only a few or say 1 in 160 women get are pregnancy PUPPPs. Though, it is known to be a common condition experienced by pregnant women, not all are aware &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/plaques-of-pregnancy-or-puppp-a-rare-pregnancy-rash/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp – A Rare Pregnancy Rash"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know that pregnancy can bring along a lot of side effects also
like fatigue, nausea, vomiting and more. But, one rare condition that
only a few or say 1 in 160 women get are pregnancy PUPPPs. Though, it
is known to be a common condition experienced by pregnant women, not
all are aware of it. Here’s and over view of Pruritic Urticarial
Papules or PUPPPS, also known as plaques or Pregnancy. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp.jpg" alt="Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp" class="wp-image-1249" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Though
as on day scientists and medical experts aren’t really sure of the
reason behind the surfacing of such itchy rashes in women during
pregnancy but believe that it could be due to excessive stretching of
skin in the months nearing to delivery. 
</p>



<p>Also,
there is no cure. The rashes tend to appear in the third semester and
disappear within 2 weeks post birthing. The rashes start mostly from
the stomach and spread across your thighs, legs, hands and neck area.
They look like red swollen patches and are extremely itchy. 
</p>



<p>Another
reason cited by experts around rash is the circulation of immune
fetal cells through the body. These cells spark an immune response
that in turn leads to the rash surfacing. The theory finds support in
the fact that the fetal cells do stay in the body for short time
after delivery. But, it’s not proved yet. 
</p>



<p>The
itching could get worse if you tend to scratch it. Better to avoid
scratching. In hotter regions the itching and pain is much worse and
proper care needs to be taken for relief. Here are a few tips around
relief from rashes 
</p>



<ol><li>

	Ice – Cool ice compresses
	can help relieve the itching. Wrap the ice compress in a cloth and
	apply few time during the day. 
	
	</li><li>

	Oatmeal – Oatmeal baths are
	known to be effective home remedy for may skin conditions including
	this one. 
	
	</li><li>

	Peppermint – Peppermint
	comes with menthol and it is known to have cooling effects. Use
	peppermint oil on the rashes or you might consume the prescribed
	quantity after consulting your doctor. 
	
	</li><li>

	Moisturiser –
	</li><li>

	Clove oil &#8211;  Clove oil is
	also known to have  cooling effects because it contains
	antimicrobials and antioxidants, phenol eugenol to be specific. 
	
</li></ol>



<p>
A study in 2017 revealed that
around 25 participants who applied petroleum jelly followed by clove
oil on rash prone areas show a reduction in symptoms compared to the
group that used on petroleum jelly.</p>



<p> Having said that, not every pregnant woman gets these itchy rashes but those who get could use the above tips for relief purpose because these rashes could get itchy to hell and frustrate you to the core. But, be calm, this will pass off and there is not known effects to the fetus due to their occurrence as yet.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Know more about  <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/"><strong>Best Gynecologist in Bangalore </strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 09:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Role Of Legumes In Heart Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1245</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes. Though it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual basis. But, recently &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/the-role-of-legumes-in-heart-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Role Of Legumes In Heart Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know how a nutritious and balanced diet can help us live longer
by keeping heart ailments at bay. A recent study carried out to find
out the role of legumes in heart health reveals that legumes.  Though
it’s never been easy to know the benefits of food on an individual
basis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1246" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Role-Of-Legumes-In-Heart-Health-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>Five color legumes for healthy , Soy bean, Navy bean or white bean, Black beam, Red bean and Green bean,</figcaption></figure>



<p>But,
recently researchers of the review called Advances in Nutrition took
up the task of understanding the significance of legumes like
lentils, peas and beans etc. around heart health. 
</p>



<p>Primarily, they focused on cardiovascular diseases like <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">coronary heart</a> disease, stroke, myocardial infarction besides looking into hypertension, obesity and diabetes. They chose cardiovascular diseases because it is one of the most common causes of mortality and even one of the most expensive ones. It is known to cause US 1 billion dollars a day. </p>



<p>They
used the data analysis of Eurpoean Association which recently carried
out a series of systematic reviews as well as meta-analysis for
Diabetics study. The researchers hope that these results could be
quite a help in updating the recommendations already made around the
role of legumes in preventing as well as treating cardio-metabolic
diseases. 
</p>



<p>The
data review and comparison with people with lowest and highest intake
of legumes revealed that dietary pulses that had legumes which either
did or did not include other legumes did decrease coronary heart
disease, obesity incidence and hypertension. 
</p>



<p>
Though the researchers were able to find a positive relationship
between intake of legumes in higher amounts and reduction in certain
parameters related to cardiovascular risks, the conclusion they came
to are muted relatively. 
</p>



<p>As
per the researchers “The overall certainty of the evidence was
graded as low for CVD incidence and ‘very low for all the other
outcomes.” 
</p>



<p>Therefore, the co author of the study Dr Hana Kahleova said “ Americans eat less than one serving of legumes per day, on average. Simply adding more beans to our plates could be a powerful tool in fighting heart disease and bringing down blood pressure.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><strong>Best Cardiologist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Board Games Can Keep Cognitive Degradation At Bay – A Study</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/board-games-can-keep-cognitive-degradation-at-bay-a-study/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 06:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best psychiatrist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1242</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know that board games are a fun way to be engaged in play in doors particularly for kids. But, here’s some news. A new study carried out by the Researchers at Edinburgh university of United Kingdom reveals that board games could actually help Older Adults avert off their cognitive decline. The paper was &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/board-games-can-keep-cognitive-degradation-at-bay-a-study/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Board Games Can Keep Cognitive Degradation At Bay – A Study"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know that board games are a fun way to be engaged in play in
doors particularly for kids. But, here’s some news. A new study
carried out by the Researchers at Edinburgh university of United
Kingdom reveals that board games could actually help Older Adults
avert off their cognitive decline. The paper was authored by Drew
Altschul of School of philosophy, Pscychology and Language sciences
in association with Professor Deary, director of Edinburgh Lothian
Birth Cohorts and published in the Journals of Gerontology. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1243" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games-300x233.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Board-Games-768x598.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /><figcaption>FBHDTJ Still-life selection of board games (Monopoly, Chess, Cluedo, Scrabble) with playing cards and gambling chips</figcaption></figure>



<p>The
study was carried out on 1091 subjects born in the year 1936 for
assessment of their mental and cognitive capabilities.  The
researchers did the evaluation for cognitive functioning across ages
11, 70, 73, 79 with the help of 14 different standard cognitive
tests.</p>



<p>The
study included asking questions to participants in the age group of
70 and 76 about how many times across the week they indulged in board
games like bingo, chess, crosswords, cards, bingo and more .  The
researchers also took into account confounding factors like
education, early life cognitive function, activity levels, sex and
health issues to name a few, as a part of their analysis. 
</p>



<p>The
results unleashed that the people who were more into board games in
their later year’s post 70’s were better off maintaining their
cognitive functioning. Particularly those older adults who indulged
in analog games post 70’s showed relative less decline in cognitive
abilities across 11 and 70 years and also between the age of 70 and
79. 
</p>



<p>Altschul,
one of the study leads says “ these latest findings add to evidence
that being more engaged in activities during the life course might be
associated with better thinking skills in later life”. 
</p>



<p>While coauthor thinks that there is a possibility that there is an interpretation of results as push to start playing board games and avoid cognitive decline.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/"><strong>Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best dermatologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1238</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Also known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and obesity. Many a times your skin shows you the symptoms and &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Also
known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do
not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a
very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and
obesity. 
</p>



<p>Many
a times your skin shows you the symptoms and it is preventable if you
exercise and maintain normal weight. As per reports around 90% of
cases of diabetes are apparently preventable if measures are taken on
time. Furthermore, if diabetes type 2 is left untreated then it could
also lead to life threatening health complications like heart attack,
kidney failure and strokes. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1239" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg 825w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>So,
why are the warning signs not taken seriously, is one question that
haunts many. The reason could be as simple as not taking them as
signs but simple health issues that could fade away with time or just
taking notice and delaying checkup till it’s forgotten. 
</p>



<p>Well,
let us run down some of the signs that could help you alert around
type 2 diabetes. 
</p>



<ol><li>

	 <strong>Frequent Washroom trips</strong>
	– high blood sugar means kidneys work hard to remove the excess
	sugar form the blood and hence it is considered to be an alarm for
	diabetes if one has to frequently wake up to go to pee. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Frequent urge to drink
	water</strong> – Due to frequent urination, even the urge to drink
	water increases due to dehydration
	</li><li>

	Fatigue – The energy levels
	of type 2 diabetes people are low due to deficiency of sugar through
	the blood stream to the body cells. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Hunger pangs</strong> – Due
	to lack of energy people suffering from type 2 diabetes tend to feel
	hungry on a constant basis even if they’d have eaten recently
	enough
	</li><li>

	<strong>Blurry Vision </strong>– At
	times high sugar could damage vision and result into blurred vision
	in one or both the eyes
	</li><li>

	<strong>Yeast Infections </strong>–
	Excess sugar in body could lead to yeast infection. The affected
	areas could get red, sore or itchy. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Tingling and Numbness</strong>
	– Due to rise in sugar levels people with this condition could
	experience tingling and numbess in their hands and feet. Known as
	neuropathy this condition has chances of worsening with time and
	hence early intervention is required.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Skin Darkening</strong> – For
	people suffering from diabetes, dark, velvety and soft patches
	appear on skin anywhere around the armpits, groin or neck. 
	
</li></ol>



<p> Perhaps, its not that difficult to be alarmed if we only pay attention at the signs. Early intervention could help deal with diabetes in a better way and also keep other life threatening conditions at bay.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 06:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Career In India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1234</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>
A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid
in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The
study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues
at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the
electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants in Partners
biobank for the study. The study was spread across 2 years wherein
the lead author Choi and his team studied through millions of data
points in order to look into people having any depression related
diagnosis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1235" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-768x511.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>
They also calculated the genetic risk score for every participant by
combining information around every participant complete genome to
come to score that determines their genetic risk for developing
depression. The data also revealed that people with high genetic risk
score could be diagnosed about it anytime in the coming 2 years. But,
those who were active physically even with higher genetic risk of
depression were less likely to experience depression. 
</p>



<p>
As per Choi an average 35 minutes of exercise on a daily basis could
help you reduce the risk of depression and even protect you against
depression bouts in future. The findings of the study Choi said that
“our findings strongly suggest that, when it comes to depression,
genes are not destiny and that being physically active has the
potential to neutralize the added risk of future episodes in
individuals who are genetically vulnerable”.</p>



<p> Well, exercise is always a good idea because it is useful and sparing out 30 to 35 minutes for yourself every day is the least you could do for your own wellness. A fit body definitely helps to keep you mind fit. So, invest in exercising atleast half and hour a day and you’ll see the difference in your overall fitness levels soon.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>&#8220;The <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/">department of physiotherapy</a> was established in 2003 at <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital</a> to cater to the preventive, creative, therapeutic and rehabilitation needs of the rural people need was felt to impart the much needed physiotherapy vocational and rehabilitation training programme. &#8220;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 10:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1231</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[No a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions. But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town, even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus. The &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>No
a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around
relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions.
But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and
global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town,
even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus.
</p>



<p>The
earlier studies primarily were carried out for a short period of time
and only have been able to identify  the links between mental health
as well as temperature but the research till date only involves short
time period and more focused on connection rather than causal
factors. Moreover, this findings have so far not yielded any
substantial conclusions. So, the researchers with this study are
hoping to get answers to their questions that are not answered as
yet. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1232" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png 860w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-300x160.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-768x411.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
researchers for their study has gathered data from various sources
including Californian emergency departments,  collecting data and
analyzing information from the data of mental health diagnosis visits
during the period of 2005 – 2016. 
</p>



<p>They
even mined for data around suicides in America during 1960 – 2016
period.  These information was based on statuses that were
individually self-reported.  After drilling the climatic temperature
in US down, the researchers managed to develop ‘’fine spatial and
temporal scales”.</p>



<p>From
the study the researchers concluded that the mental health outcomes
decrease as the temperatures cool and the increase mental health
issues with rise in temperatures. Statistically speaking they found
that there was a rise in 0.48% rise in mental health visits with a
rise in average monthly temperature of 1<sup>0</sup> F and even a
rise in suicides by 0.35%</p>



<p>In
short, the rise and drop in temperatures has a significant impact of
the mental health because the authors of the study also showed
stability in the estimates even when accounted for socio economic
status and air conditioning adoption. 
</p>



<p>As for suicide rate, it rises only if there is a rise in temperature amid the growing season because growing season is all about crop yields. If the temperature rises, the crop yield reduces and leads to financial issues that in turn increase the risk of suicides.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance – Check Out Their Amazing Health Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eat-indian-jujube-in-abundance-check-out-their-amazing-health-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 09:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Indian Jujube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1228</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The winter has almost arrived, and with it has arrived the season of Indian Jujube, or as we call them locally BER. Not many are aware that they are also known as the Korean date or Chinese date or even Indian Date. A bite sized fruit, it is relished by many but very few of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/eat-indian-jujube-in-abundance-check-out-their-amazing-health-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Eat Indian Jujube In Abundance – Check Out Their Amazing Health Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The winter has
almost arrived, and with it has arrived the season of Indian Jujube,
or as we call them locally BER.  Not many are aware that they are
also known as the Korean date or Chinese date or even Indian Date. 
</p>



<p>A bite sized fruit, it is relished by many but very few of us really know about its umpteen health benefits.   Here’s a run down some of them –</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-1024x678.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1229" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-300x199.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance-768x509.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Eat-Indian-Jujube-In-Abundance.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Rich Source of Vitamin C</strong> – Jujube’s are known to be
	loaded with vitamin C as well as antioxidents and we all know the
	role of Vitamin C in revitalizing our skin, building immunity as
	well as fighting free radicals. Just consuming around 100 gms of
	Jujube can give you 69 mg of Vitamin C. Hence, eating jujube could
	be a great way of getting vitamin C as our body is not capable of
	producing the same. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Bone
	Strength</strong> – Want strong bones? Eat Jujubes. Yes, you read that
	right. Jujubes are also power packed with calcium, iron as well as
	phosphorous thus helping in improving. Hence, it’s a tasty
	alternative for people with oesteoprosis and bone degrading.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Anxiety
	soother</strong> – This fruit is known to have a calming effect on the
	brain as well as the nervous system. Jujube as well as its oil
	extract is known have sedative effects and relax your body down by
	working on the hormonal levels. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Constipation
	Relief</strong> – Jujube is known to provide great relief to people
	suffering from chronic constipation. As per statistics over 20%
	Indians suffer from chronic constipation and still its not been on
	the list of concerns. As jujube’s are a rich source of fibre, they
	help in digestion and regulation of bowel movements. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>
<strong>Sleep
	Well</strong> – Jujubes are rich in antioxidant pythochemicals,
	sapnins, flavonoids and polysaccharides known to have sedative
	properties. Hence, it helps in sleeping well by calming the nerves.
	So, people if you are suffering from insomnia, try jujubes.
</li></ol>



<p>Well, as this fruit is rich in fibre as well, its also considered to aid people looking at weight loss.  Perhaps, its high time you make it an integral part of your fruit consumption or diet may be.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Top Medical College in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
