<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Dengue Is Back &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/dengue-is-back/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 06:55:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dengue Is Back! – How To Deal With It?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dengue-is-back/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 06:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dengue Is Back]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rajarajeswari hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1161</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As almost 500 cases crop up in Dakshin Kannada or Mangaluru, Dengue is back this season and with a big bang for sure in Karnataka. Already four people have succumbed to the deadly fever that is a result of the Aedes mosquitos. Unike malaria mosquitos, Dengue mosquitos breed inside the house in clean water. A &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/dengue-is-back/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dengue Is Back! – How To Deal With It?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As
almost 500 cases crop up in Dakshin Kannada or Mangaluru, Dengue is
back this season and with a big bang for sure in Karnataka. Already
four people have succumbed to the deadly fever that is a result of
the Aedes mosquitos. Unike malaria mosquitos, Dengue mosquitos breed
inside the house in clean water. A viral infection, Dengue is at its
peak in the monsoon season every year. The most common symptoms of
dengue include headache, swollen lymph nodes, rashes, exhaustion and
high fever. The main characteristics of dengue include high fever,
rashes and headache. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/DENGUE.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1163" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/DENGUE.jpg 700w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/DENGUE-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /></figure>



<p>The
acute phase of the fever can last upto two weeks. The more serious
and life threatening condition of Dengue is Dengue hemorrhagic fever
(DHF) occurring mostly in under 10 years children. This complication
can cause circulatory collapse, hemorrhage and abdominal pain. The
symptoms often occur after 3 days to 15 days of the mosquito bite.
The weather conditions also are responsible to an extent for breeding
the dengue mosquitos. Outbreaks are more common in tropical and
subtropical areas. Though the condition is not contagious, if a
mosquito bites a dengue infected, it does contract the dengue virus
too and spread it onward to other people. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/medical-admission-mbbs-ms-md-phd/" rel="follow"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/rrmch.gif" alt="rrmch" class="wp-image-1057"/></a></figure>



<p>Thus
the Aedes mosquito is considered the vector or transmitter and humans
as the source of infection. As mentioned Dengue Hemorrhagic fever or
DHF is a shock syndrome of dengue that mostly affects children under
10 years of age. DHF starts abruptly with consistent fever
accompanied with headache. Other symptoms include cough, nausea, sore
throat, and vomiting as well as abdominal pain. The shock occurs
around 2 to 6 days after the onset of symptoms with sudden collapse,
mouth blueness, weak pulse to name a few. Bleeding is also a common
possibility and DHF requires close monitoring. There is no particular
treatment and only intensive care with blood transfusion and oxygen
provision as well as immediate fluid replacement are some of the
treatments.  If proper treatment is provided the mortality rate could
be less but it could rise to as high as 20% if not treated properly. 
</p>



<p>The best idea is to take care around your house and avoid travelling to mosquito prone areas. Check for water storage possibilities for breeding mosquitos and treat appropriately.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>just know about <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/">Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
