<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>best hospital in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/best-hospital-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 06:30:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Corona Virus – Facts Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/corona-virus-facts-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 06:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona Virus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1260</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As the corona virus or Wuhan virus scare is catching like wild fire and as the number of infected people across the world. The cases in china are about to reach 15000 and over 300 people are said to be already affected. The virus is on the spread across the world as it is highly &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/corona-virus-facts-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Corona Virus – Facts Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>
As the corona virus or Wuhan
virus scare is catching like wild fire and as the number of infected
people across the world. The cases in china are about to reach 15000
and over 300 people are  said to be already affected. The virus is on
the spread across the world as it is highly contagious and the UN has
already declared it as a medical emergency.  While the world is on
high alert and is also flown out their nationals from the country,
the clouds of this virus causing a havoc are already mounting. Here
are a few tips to keep the corona virus infection at bay. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Corona-Virus.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1261" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Corona-Virus.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Corona-Virus-300x167.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Corona-Virus-768x427.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<ol><li>

	Wash your hands with soap and
	water on regular basis or with alcohol based disinfectant
	</li><li>

	While sneezing or coughing
	cover your mouth with a tissue or hand
	</li><li>

	Avoid close contact with
	people suffering from cold or flu like symptoms 
	
	</li><li>

	Do not eat under cooked meat
	or eggs
	</li><li>

	Avoid contact with farm
	animals or the wild
	</li><li>

	Stay indoors at home when
	sick
	</li><li>

	Clean all objects and
	surfaces that are dirty or touched
	</li><li>

	Avoid touching your mouth,
	eyes or hands with dirty hands
	</li><li>

	Use a mask whenever outdoor 
	
	</li><li>

	Always carry a disinfectant
	along when outdoor
</li></ol>



<p>
There’s also a debate around
the transfer of the virus without showing symptoms. While the Germans
are firm that asymptomatic transmission is possible, nothing is yet
officially conveyed.</p>



<p> Well, as the cases in China keep exploding as the days pass by, the risk of it spreading across continents is always there. As of now the process of developing a vaccine for controlling the virus is on but it might take almost a year before it comes to the pharmacy. Until then, prevention is the only way out. So, stay safe and clean to keep the condition out of harm’s way.  </p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Top Leading Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>



<p>Sourced from Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thunderclap Headache &#8211; Know More About This Sudden Intense Painful Condition</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/thunderclap-headache/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 09:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good medical colleges in bangalore]]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thunderclap Headache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1153</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[This is rare kind of headache that starts suddenly out of the blue and is an experience you won’t forget. The intensity of it is very high, something you would not have experienced ever. It lasts for a while but that few minutes could be to painful. No wonder, it is known to be worst &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/thunderclap-headache/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Thunderclap Headache &#8211; Know More About This Sudden Intense Painful Condition"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This
is rare kind of headache that starts suddenly out of the blue and is
an experience you won’t forget. The intensity of it is very high,
something you would not have experienced ever. It lasts for a while
but that few minutes could be to painful. No wonder, it is known to
be worst headache in one’s life. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Thunderclap-Headache.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1155" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Thunderclap-Headache.jpg 650w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Thunderclap-Headache-300x208.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" /><figcaption>young woman who have a headache</figcaption></figure>



<p>Though
many of us might just forget about it once it is gone, it is
advisable to get yourself checked if it happens to you because it
could be life threatening.  Even if it is not, better to visit a
doctor. The symptoms of thunderclap headache include-</p>



<ol><li>
Sudden
	high intensity headache
	</li><li>
Vomiting
	or nausea
	</li><li>
Headache
	with neck or lower back pain 
	
	</li><li>
Dizziness
	and losing consciousness
	</li><li>
Experiencing
	the worst ever headache
</li></ol>



<p>The intensity of pain of a thunderclap headache can reach its zenith is a matter of 60 seconds. Sometimes it just goes away forever while at times it could last over a period of seven days. There is a difference between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thunderclap_headache" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="thunderclap headaches  (opens in a new tab)">thunderclap headaches </a>and migraine but thunderclap headaches that are not categorized as life threatening are considered as a kind of migraine only.  </p>



<p><strong>Triggers
/ Causes</strong></p>



<p>A
thunderclap headache is known to be the result of bleeding in the
brain or a symptoms of subarachnoid hemorrhage.  The life threatening
causes for this headache include –</p>



<ol><li>
Internal
	bleeding due to rupture of blood vessel in brain
	</li><li>
Ischemic
	stroke
	</li><li>
Hemorrhagic
	stroke
	</li><li>
Inflammation
	of blood vessel
	</li><li>
Reversible
	cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome
</li></ol>



<p>The common triggers though could include bowel movement strain, injury, sexual or physical activity as well.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about the <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Measles Cases Rise Around The World</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/measles-cases-rise-around-the-world/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Measles Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1071</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Measles is creating a sort of havoc across the world with over 173,000 cases reported in 2017. The reason behind the same is the fact that many parents do not vaccinate their children for the same. The 30% increase in the number of measles cases across the globe is very much due to the same. &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/measles-cases-rise-around-the-world/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Measles Cases Rise Around The World"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Measles is creating a sort of havoc across the world with over 173,000 cases reported in 2017. The reason behind the same is the fact that many parents do not vaccinate their children for the same. The 30% increase in the number of measles cases across the globe is very much due to the same. Although this disease can be prevented with the help of a vaccine, the death toll around the world has been over 110,000, which is startling.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Measles-Cases-Rise-Around-The-World.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1072" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Measles-Cases-Rise-Around-The-World.jpg" alt="Measles Cases Rise Around The World" width="660" height="371" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Measles-Cases-Rise-Around-The-World.jpg 660w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Measles-Cases-Rise-Around-The-World-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Though this disease can be prevented, it is known to be not only highly infectious in nature for also to be causing hearing loss as well as mental disorders in children. It can also result in diphtheria issues in the children who are not vaccinated. Countries like the Russian Federation, Germany and Venezuela have already had high outbreak in measles last year which has led to withdrawal of the interrupted transmission certification as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Measles outbreak affects the poor and down trodden all the more due to ignore or carelessness and even poverty or people residing in the conflict areas. This measles issues is also there around due to negative misinformation within people and trust worthiness as well which leads to skipping or avoiding the vaccine altogether. As per experts, people are not able to understand the importance of vaccination against measles and take it lightly or ignore the same and that it can be a life threatening disease amongst children.</p>
<p><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-995 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg" alt="" width="397" height="41" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg 397w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore-300x31.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 397px) 100vw, 397px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Even in India measles has taken a toll but as per WHO, the rate has dropped by a staggering 43% around 2015-16. Furthermore, the rate is expected to fall even more in the years to come because India has already taken a staunch stance to eradicate measles by 2020. While in 2015 there were around 30,168 cases, 2016 they reduced drastically to 17, 250. India has already planned it out on taking the vaccine to 40 crore Indian children in order to achieve its target or measles eradication by 2020.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>All You Need to Know About Ganglion Cyst</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-ganglion-cyst/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopaedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganglion Cyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganglion Cyst causes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganglion Cyst symptoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganglion Cyst treatment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopaedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1051</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many of you might not have heard about this condition but it does exist and is a common condition for the age group of 20 to 40 years. A ganglion cyst is a tumor or swelling caused either on the tendon viz. the tissue that connects muscle to the bone or the top of a &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/all-you-need-to-know-about-ganglion-cyst/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All You Need to Know About Ganglion Cyst"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Many of you might not have heard about this condition but it does exist and is a common condition for the age group of 20 to 40 years. A ganglion cyst is a tumor or swelling caused either on the tendon viz. the tissue that connects muscle to the bone or the top of a joint. The cyst is sticky and colourless and looks like a sac of liquid. The size of the cyst may vary and it could feel spongy as well. There could either be on single cyst or one large one and multiple number of smaller ones around it connected by a common stalk within the deeper tissue. Also known as Bible cyst, is not harmful and around 70% people experience it in their lifetime. Ganglion cysts are very rare in age-groups less than 10 years. Ganglion cysts usually develop on the back of the hand. They are found at the joint of the wrist but can also be seen on the side of the palm. The other rare but possible sites of cyst include mucous cysts occurring right below the cuticle on the fingertip, the foot top, as pea sized bumps on the palm finger base, as well as the outer part of the ankle as well as the knee.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1052" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst.png" alt="Ganglion Cyst" width="640" height="640" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst.png 640w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst-150x150.png 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst-300x300.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Ganglion-Cyst-100x100.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
As on day the causes of the cyst are not known. As per doctors it could be due to breakdown of the tissue joint as a result of some trauma. Another theory mentions joint capsule fault or in that of the tendon sheath leading to joint tissue bulge.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;">If you have a bulge or bump of changing mass.</li>
<li>If the diameter is 1-3 cm and it does not move</li>
<li>There is a sudden swelling or a gradual one</li>
<li>If it is recurring after a certain period of time</li>
<li>Ganglion cysts do cause pain followed by acute trauma even if they don’t appear.</li>
<li>If it pains it could get worse due to joint motion</li>
<li>In cysts that are connected to the tendon, you feel weakness in the finger</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Medical Advice</strong><br />
Medical evaluation of the cyst is important whether or not you have all the symptoms. This will help the doctor in making it sure and offering a suitable line of treatment. The doctor could advise on an ultrasound or test using the cyst fluid. At times even a MRI could be advised by the doctor though it is an expensive procedure.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
Ganglion Cysts can be treated with hot bags at home. Sometimes if there is pain, doctor may prescribe a pain killer as well. Surgical or cosmetic removal of cysts of bigger size can be done but they could reoccur as well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rajarajeswari Hospital</a> having high specialised<strong> <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/orthopaedics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Orthopedic Doctors in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do You Legs Pain All Night? Know Why</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/legs-pain-all-night-know-why/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1001</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Many of us experience leg pain at night. But, ever thought about the reasons behind it. Many of us should have and many should have not. So, if you are also amongst the ones who do experience leg pain at night on a regular basis and have been ignoring it or just bearing it through, &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/legs-pain-all-night-know-why/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Do You Legs Pain All Night? Know Why"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Many of us experience leg pain at night. But, ever thought about the reasons behind it. Many of us should have and many should have not. So, if you are also amongst the ones who do experience leg pain at night on a regular basis and have been ignoring it or just bearing it through, here are a few reasons that could be the reason, perhaps.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1002" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Do-You-Legs-Pain-All-Night.jpg" alt="Do You Legs Pain All Night" width="614" height="408" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Do-You-Legs-Pain-All-Night.jpg 614w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Do-You-Legs-Pain-All-Night-300x199.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 614px) 100vw, 614px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Deficiency of vital nutrients</strong><br />
Many of us never know if our diet is a balanced one of not. With a hectic life schedule and not time for to spare towards caring for health besides a diet that is more of junk and less of nutrient rich food, deficiency of vital nutrients like calcium, potassium and magnesium as well as Vitamin D can lead to leg pain.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Dehydration</strong><br />
Nocturnal leg pain is also known to be caused due to dehydration. Due to the electrolyte imbalance in blood, it can lead to nocturnal cramps. So keep yourself hydrated throughout the day and even if you tend to wake up at night stay hydrated.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Standing long hours</strong><br />
Standing for long hours can lead to leg pain at night. The reason is that standing for along time tends to accumulate the blood and water in your lower body causing fluid imbalance and cramping.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Health Conditions</strong><br />
If you are suffering from other health conditions that you are not aware of then, you could be having leg pain due to the same.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Aging</strong><br />
As you age your bones become weak and nocturnal leg pain is pretty common then. It is after 50 years that you may start experiencing this condition because you start losing neurons and get frequent cramps due to it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, health is wealth and ignoring it can lead to an irreversible or life threatening damage to the body. So, if you are experiencing the symptoms get yourself checked and do the needful. Why compromise on quality of life.</p>
<p>Know more about <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Rural India is a Bearing the Brunt of Non Communicable Diseases</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-rural-india-is-a-bearing-the-brunt-of-non-communicable-diseases/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 04:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare issue of rural India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ncd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Non communicable diseases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=980</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A doctor practicing in the rural area was taken by surprise to find numerous cases of non communicable diseases amongst men and women in and around rural areas. While a 55 year old male suffered from from a heart attack, a 53 year old female was suffering from depression and anxiety. Other cases included that &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-rural-india-is-a-bearing-the-brunt-of-non-communicable-diseases/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Rural India is a Bearing the Brunt of Non Communicable Diseases"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A doctor practicing in the rural area was taken by surprise to find numerous cases of <em>non communicable diseases</em> amongst men and women in and around rural areas. While a 55 year old male suffered from from a heart attack, a 53 year old female was suffering from depression and anxiety. Other cases included that of chronic back pain and more, that too from a tribal village that is situated in one of the most backward districts of the state.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The question that doctors are pondering on is how are rural and tribal areas populace experiencing the health issues that are commonly associated with lifestyle of urban people. The fact is that the pattern of India&#8217;s health structure is making a paradigm shift and this has been so over the past 15 years. The fact came to light when the Government of India released its report on the death causing diseases. Further more, the figures of the report of 2010-13 showed enormous growth revealing 47% of the deaths were due to NCD’s and 30% due to Communicable Diseases. This significant rise of 7% undoubtedly indicated taking a keen interest in the <a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">healthcare</a> issues of rural population and <strong>Non communicable diseases</strong> more so.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-981 alignright" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ncd-1-300x222.png" alt="" width="300" height="222" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ncd-1-300x222.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ncd-1.png 474w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, even though as per statistics the life expectancy of people in urban as well as rural India remains the same more or less, the health issues related to aging seems to crop up in rural areas as well and not just the cities. Having said that, there are challenging dealing with rural NCDs compared to that of cities. Here’s a look through a few –</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>Unavailability for diagnosis and treatment in rural areas.</li>
<li>It can be expensive and economic issues like poverty amongst families</li>
<li>Unavailability of advanced professionals needed for treatment of NCD’s</li>
<li>Data Collection issues around Rural NCD’s hampers working on the problem further in a systematic way.</li>
<li>In India compared to developed countries NCD is common among the younger generation</li>
<li>Awareness is one of the main reasons NCD’s in rural region is not gaining the kind of attention it needs to get.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Well, NCD in rural India is no myth today as can be seen from the figures and hence the policy makers and government need to focus on devising and implementing solutions to deal with this growing healthcare issue of rural India.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Food Poisoning? An Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/what-is-food-poisoning-and-more/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Poisoning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=916</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Recently, there was news of over 100 prisoners in Delhi falling sick suddenly and being admitted to the hospital. The reason cited for the same is either food poisoning, drug poisoning or contaminated water. Food poisoning is a common term and you hear people and kids suffering from it every now and then. It is &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/what-is-food-poisoning-and-more/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "What is Food Poisoning? An Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Recently, there was news of over 100 prisoners in Delhi falling sick suddenly and being admitted to the hospital. The reason cited for the same is either food poisoning, drug poisoning or contaminated water. Food poisoning is a common term and you hear people and kids suffering from it every now and then. It is a very uncomfortable condition that leads to nausea, vomiting or diarrhea and is caused due to the intake of toxic, contaminated or spoiled food.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
Food poisoning can either be caused by bacteria, viruses or parasites. The most common though is through bacteria like Listeria, E coli and salmonella. The latter is said to be the biggest cause of serious food poisoning cases. Another rare or lethal bacteria responsible for food poisoning includes the C. botulism and Campylobacter. Norovirus is a virus type which can also lead to food poisoning but is not fatal mostly. Others include Rotavirus, Astrovirus, Sapovirus and Hepatitis A, wherein the latter can be serious. Toxoplasma is a parasite which causes food poisoning. Parasites live within your digestive tract but can go undetected for years.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-1-Main-blog-image-550x410-1-1.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-942 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410-1.png" alt="Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410" width="550" height="410" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410-1.png 550w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Food-Poisoning-Main-blog-image-550x410-1-300x224.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong><br />
Usually, food poisoning is detectable based on the symptoms. The symptoms differ as per the infection source. The symptoms appear anytime within 1 hour or 28 days depending on the infection source again. Most people suffering from food poisoning show atleast three of the following symptoms.</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Headache</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Weakness</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Nausea</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Mild fever</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Loss of appetite</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Diarrhea</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Abdominal cramps</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Food poisoning ain&#8217;t life-threatening. But, this does not mean that you take the condition lightly. There is always a rare possibility of it getting life-threatening as well. Look out for the following symptoms and initiate immediate medical assistance &#8211;</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Fever of 105 or higher</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Severe dehydration, dry mouth, no urine passage</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Difficulty speaking or seeing</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Diarrhea that does not go for 3 or more days</li>
<li style="text-align: justify;">Blood in urine</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
Food poisoning generally does not require any treatment and can easily be managed at home. It can take three to five days to subside but the most important part is to stay hydrated all along. Consumption of Sports drink that has electrolyte in them works really well in dealing with the condition. To help yourself out of fatigue try natural drinks like coconut water and fruit juice.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Know about <a title="Best Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best Hospitals in Bangalore</a>, Karnataka.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 tips to help you sail through the pregnancy voyage safely</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-vital-tips-on-sailing-through-pregnancy-voyage-safely/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 07:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in banglaore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=907</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Pregnancy is the harbinger of a new life coming to form and the herald of a life changing journey commencing 9 months later. One of the most remarkable moments is when you come to know about it and then begins a daily routine that involves a lot of tests, doctor visits and self-care. While, it &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-vital-tips-on-sailing-through-pregnancy-voyage-safely/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "5 tips to help you sail through the pregnancy voyage safely"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Pregnancy is the harbinger of a new life coming to form and the herald of a life changing journey commencing 9 months later. One of the most remarkable moments is when you come to know about it and then begins a daily routine that involves a lot of tests, doctor visits and self-care. While, it is a vital part of a woman’s life, sailing through the pregnancy phase is also another extremely vital part because of the risks associated with the whole process. So, here are five important tips that could help you ensure safe drive through your pregnancy roads.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-908 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-300x225.jpg" alt="pregnancy Voyage Safely" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/5-Vital-Tips-on-Sailing-Through-pregnancy-Voyage-Safely-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Genetic Screening</strong> &#8211; Sometimes genetic illnesses can affect the health of the fetus and hence it is detrimental for you and your spouse to undergo genetic screening.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>De-stressing</strong> – Stress can affect your health as well as the health of the fetus. So, keeping yourself stress-free is a good idea. To keep stress at bay you may indulge yourself in activities like breathing exercises, relaxing showers, yoga, and meditation.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>De-Addiction</strong> &#8211; Addictions can be life-threatening for the fetus and create unnecessary complications like premature birth, low birth weight or miscarriage. Good idea to stay away from them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Exercise</strong> &#8211; Remaining active is the key to a healthy body. So, exercise on a routine basis, walk every day for some-time and feel fit all through your pregnancy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Diet Balance</strong> – A balanced diet can help you and your fetus stay healthy and receive all the necessary nutrients throughout the prenatal period. So, get a dietician for a customized diet plan and follow it all through.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Prenatal Care</strong> – Do your research to get yourself a certified and experienced prenatal care center. Try finding it nearby to avoid the hassles of commuting through traffic for regular checkups and emergency times.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Besides that always take care of yourself all through the pregnancy while walking or commuting with respect to your safety and avoid any laborious activities that have a potential to harm you like lifting heavy stuff, riding two-wheelers through traffic, but to name a few.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Department of <a title="best Gynecologist in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/" target="_blank">Obstetrics and Gynecology</a> has been providing comprehensive health care for women. We provide regular clinical services in Obstetrics like antenatal care, labor management, Postpartum Care. We also provide specialized care in high-risk pregnancies like P.I.H, Eclampsia, GDM, Multiple gestations, BOH.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Pregnancy Complications To Be Aware Of</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-pregnancy-complications-to-be-aware-of/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 08:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top 5 Pregnancy Complications]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=889</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The news of pregnancy brings in smiles on the faces of the family members. On the flip side, during the three trimesters, you need to be on your toes and all alert because pregnancy can cause complications if proper care is not taken. Though you are going to be under the scanner all through the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/top-5-pregnancy-complications-to-be-aware-of/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Top 5 Pregnancy Complications To Be Aware Of"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The news of pregnancy brings in smiles on the faces of the family members. On the flip side, during the three trimesters, you need to be on your toes and all alert because pregnancy can cause complications if proper care is not taken. Though you are going to be under the scanner all through the pregnancy cycle and your doctor is going to get you tested on various complications, you yourself need to be aware of them and take self-care to keep them at bay.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Here is a run through <em>some complications of pregnancy</em> that can be life threatening to the fetus and the mom as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Top-5-Pregnancy-Complications-To-Be-Aware-Of-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-890 size-full" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Top-5-Pregnancy-Complications-To-Be-Aware-Of-1.jpg" alt="Top 5 Pregnancy Complications To Be Aware Of" width="299" height="168" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Pre-eclampisa</strong> &#8211; It is the almost rare condition in pregnancy because it usually affects only 5 % of the pregnant women in India. This condition is caused by high level of proteins in the urine, high blood pressure or kidney conditions post 20 weeks of pregnancy.<br />
Care needs to be taken to be aware and act promptly by the doctor if there are even mild symptoms of it because it can progress fast and can be life-threatening to the baby and the mother too. The solution to it is early delivery.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Gestational Diabetes</strong> &#8211; This is one of the common conditions occurring in pregnant women in India. Around 10% women could be prey to this condition that can be diagnosed during 24-28 weeks of pregnancy. Post-diagnosis your blood sugar levels will be monitored on a regular basis. Most of them with mild conditions manage to keep it at bay through exercise and diet and are able to deliver healthy babies without complications. But, care needs to be taken to avoid it from aggravating because it can then cause serious harm to the fetus.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Placenta Previa</strong> – This condition can cause complications towards the end of pregnancy not in the early stages. Hence, the doctors check the location and placement of your placenta with a sonography test during the second     tri-semester. 1 in 200 women suffer from this condition and it can be quite dangerous if the placenta is at extremely low levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Miscarriage</strong> – One of the most dreaded conditions which can only be avoided by taking proper care, miscarriage is caused in the first 20 weeks. This is common with Indian women and 20% of them experience this condition within 12 weeks mostly. The symptoms of it include spotting and bleeding at the vagina. The doctor does a sonography to check for the condition.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Premature Delivery</strong> – Premature delivery is when the cervix opens before 37 weeks of pregnancy. If the delivery happens too early then it can be life-threatening for the baby, so care needs to be taken to avoid it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The <a title="best Gynecologist in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">department of Obstetrics and Gynecology</a> has been providing comprehensive health care for women. We provide regular clinical services in Obstetrics like antenatal care, labor management, postpartum Care. We also provide specialized care in high risk pregnancies like P.I.H, Eclampsia, GDM, Multiple gestations, BOH. With the backup of NICU, we are able to salvage preterm babies of 30 weeks on wards. Highly qualified doctors, with the help of well equipped labor ward, conduct normal and caesarian deliveries</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cancer to Curd &#8211; The Journey of Ramadevi Nimmanapalli</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cancer-to-curd-the-journey-of-ramadevi-nimmanapalli/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=821</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Ramadevi Nimmanapalli, a cancer researcher by profession had been in the US till 2015. She returned to India leaving behind this career in order to take up another challenging opportunity of setting up a faculty of Veterinary and Animal Sciences at the Benaras Hindu University in Varanasi. She herself had done her Science Graduation from &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/cancer-to-curd-the-journey-of-ramadevi-nimmanapalli/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Cancer to Curd &#8211; The Journey of Ramadevi Nimmanapalli"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Ramadevi Nimmanapalli, a cancer researcher by profession had been in the US till 2015. She returned to India leaving behind this career in order to take up another challenging opportunity of setting up a faculty of Veterinary and Animal Sciences at the Benaras Hindu University in Varanasi. She herself had done her Science Graduation from Sri Venkateswara Veterinary University in Hyderabad after which she did her Masters in Sciences, topping the University. She further went to Oxford to pursue PhD there.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Cancer-to-Curd-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-822" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Cancer-to-Curd-1-1.jpg" alt="Cancer to Curd" width="600" height="381" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Describing her experience in Oxford England as a rather challenging one even though she was a topper, she mentioned that the education system in India and England was different. Catching up was quite a task because Indian education courses do not offer in-depth study as compared to Oxford. So, she had to work really hard with her research in microbiology in bluetongue virus that affects deers and cattle as well. After completing her Phd. She shifted to USA where she researched in areas of human cancer and chemical pathways for drug Gleevac. Before returning to India she was teaching at the Philadelphia college of Osteopathic Medicine and MD Anderson Cancer centre, Tuskagee University.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;" align="justify"><a title="Best Cancer Hospitals in Bangalore" href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/surgical-oncology/" target="_blank"><strong>BEST CANCER HOSPITAL IN BANGALORE</strong></a></p>
<p align="justify">Though shifting to India was also not an easy decision for her as she was already married and living there with her husband, it’s when her husband supported the decision to take the decision to go to Indi without him joining her right away, after she moved here.</p>
<p align="justify">Now, in India, as the Dean at the Benaras University, she is all set to revive the faculty which already has a dairy farm on its main campus besides a research ready campus that is being setup in Mirzapur for MSc and Doctoral students, which is nearby. She is working hard to set up this new faculty and her straight forward attitude which she brought along as a learning from her USA lifestyle has been of a great aid. She has already published around 40 research papers but the one that stands out is about dealing and characterization of curd or dahi. Though the founding dean of the faculty has not had any admissions, later this year, the faculty is going to welcome its first batch of undergraduate students. The team is ready, the labs are set and the preparations are on to take the plunge. Though a lot of preparations are underway as well, as per the Dean, it’s a long way to go.</p>
<p align="justify">*source from the internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
