<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>radio diagnosis course &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/radio-diagnosis-course/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:42:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Medicine As a Career in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forensic science colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio diagnosis course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=688</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Medicine As a Career in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices that are available around the medicine field apart from MBBS. So, students who aren’t able to crack the NEET can try to opt for some related courses that include BDS, Physiotherapy, Phsychiatry, Pharmacy and more. So, as per your area of interest you may choose a course. One major advantage of NEET being brought into effect is that intelligent students coming from lower income groups can try to get entry into medical without paying hefty donations to colleges.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-689 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg" alt="Medicine As a Career in India" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">In case you opt for <a title="MBBS Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/course/mbbs/" target="_blank">MBBS</a>, a masters is always a good idea considering future growth. You could either opt for a MD or MS. Though being a surgeon isnt a cake walk and invovles daily encounters with patients fighting for their lives. Its a great responshibility to shoulder and a time costing too.</p>
<p align="justify">As a surgeon or a masters degree holder you need to be available to your patients anytime. It could be in the wee hours of the night as well. So, its quite a stressful and hectic work schedule that you’ll have to manage. But, the perks include immense work satisfaction with successful medical procedures and blessing from families. If surgery is not your cup of tea then you might as well opt for MD in areas like radiology, anaesthesiology, paediatrics, forensic medicine and more.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, if not MBBS than the option of <a title="Physiotherapy Career in India" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/" target="_blank">Physiotherapy</a>, <a title="Dental College in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrdch.org/" target="_blank">BDS</a>, Ayurvedic medicine, Homeopathy, Veterinary and Pharmacy are definitely some of the good choices around medicine. A masters degree with these streams can offer rewarding career prospects.</p>
<p align="justify">Coming down to the bottom line, medical education does blow a hole into your pocket and for students coming from middle income and lower income groups, its not an easy way ahead. But, with the help of student loans, you may as well manage to realize your medical education dreams. Though, it is important to have indepth information on the student loan interest, payback procedure and time for repayment in detail, needs to be known particularly when you are planning to pursue higher education abroad.</p>
<p align="justify">Medical is undoubtedly a lucrative career but having said that it does come with its own cons which need to be considered before taking a plunge into it.</p>
<p align="justify">know about leading <a title="Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">medical colleges in Bangalore </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
