<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>forensic science colleges &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/forensic-science-colleges/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:42:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Medicine As a Career in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forensic science colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio diagnosis course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=688</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Medicine As a Career in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices that are available around the medicine field apart from MBBS. So, students who aren’t able to crack the NEET can try to opt for some related courses that include BDS, Physiotherapy, Phsychiatry, Pharmacy and more. So, as per your area of interest you may choose a course. One major advantage of NEET being brought into effect is that intelligent students coming from lower income groups can try to get entry into medical without paying hefty donations to colleges.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-689 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg" alt="Medicine As a Career in India" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">In case you opt for <a title="MBBS Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/course/mbbs/" target="_blank">MBBS</a>, a masters is always a good idea considering future growth. You could either opt for a MD or MS. Though being a surgeon isnt a cake walk and invovles daily encounters with patients fighting for their lives. Its a great responshibility to shoulder and a time costing too.</p>
<p align="justify">As a surgeon or a masters degree holder you need to be available to your patients anytime. It could be in the wee hours of the night as well. So, its quite a stressful and hectic work schedule that you’ll have to manage. But, the perks include immense work satisfaction with successful medical procedures and blessing from families. If surgery is not your cup of tea then you might as well opt for MD in areas like radiology, anaesthesiology, paediatrics, forensic medicine and more.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, if not MBBS than the option of <a title="Physiotherapy Career in India" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/" target="_blank">Physiotherapy</a>, <a title="Dental College in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrdch.org/" target="_blank">BDS</a>, Ayurvedic medicine, Homeopathy, Veterinary and Pharmacy are definitely some of the good choices around medicine. A masters degree with these streams can offer rewarding career prospects.</p>
<p align="justify">Coming down to the bottom line, medical education does blow a hole into your pocket and for students coming from middle income and lower income groups, its not an easy way ahead. But, with the help of student loans, you may as well manage to realize your medical education dreams. Though, it is important to have indepth information on the student loan interest, payback procedure and time for repayment in detail, needs to be known particularly when you are planning to pursue higher education abroad.</p>
<p align="justify">Medical is undoubtedly a lucrative career but having said that it does come with its own cons which need to be considered before taking a plunge into it.</p>
<p align="justify">know about leading <a title="Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">medical colleges in Bangalore </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microscopic Robots To Replace Doctors Sooner or Later?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/microscopic-robots-to-replace-doctors-sooner-or-later/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 11:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forensic science colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microscopic Robots To Replace Doctors Sooner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=672</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Microscopic robots may seem a new phrase but we all are aware of nanotechnology, the word at least if not more. Now, nanometer is equal to one billionth of a meter and is smallest of the scales. It is apparently the size we consider for atoms and cells inside the body. We all know are &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/microscopic-robots-to-replace-doctors-sooner-or-later/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Microscopic Robots To Replace Doctors Sooner or Later?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify"><em><strong>Microscopic robots may seem a new phrase but we all are aware of nanotechnology</strong></em>, the word at least if not more. Now, nanometer is equal to one billionth of a meter and is smallest of the scales. It is apparently the size we consider for atoms and cells inside the body. We all know are body is made of millions of cells and atoms but when it comes to treatment, it happens on a greater scale. Cells or atoms are not even visible through the naked eye. So, nanotechnology works at the cellular level thus matching the levels at which our body cells or atoms work. Though, its not perfected as yet, we’ve certainly come out with a lot of solutions based on nanotechnology and are probably heading northward in the arena.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Microscopic-Robots-To-Replace-Doctors-Sooner-or-Later-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-673" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Microscopic-Robots-To-Replace-Doctors-Sooner-or-Later-1-1.jpg" alt="Microscopic Robots To Replace Doctors Sooner or Later" width="736" height="525" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">In layman’s language using nanotechnology, we can shrink the medical tools used for treating or intervention in the human body to the size of cells or atoms present inside. Using the right size tool will help intricate interventions with simplicity. Surgeries with complexities and involving heavy blood loss can be done away with using such a technology. There is a lot of scope to this technology, as per the researchers and experts in the field. Be it targeted drug treatment to treating critical illnesses like <a title="cancer hospitals in bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/cervical-cancer-spreading-at-alarming-rates-in-india/" target="_blank">cancers</a>, where nano scalpels are presently being used for damage repair of individual cells.</p>
<p align="justify">Furthermore, there is a possibility of improved biological sensors as well as disease diagnosis in the times to come. Just imagine subatomic robots just like a miniature army of soldiers getting into your body and fighting against the ailment to cure you off, that too without any major blood filled surgeries or incisions.</p>
<p align="justify">One of the examples on which researchers are presently working in some part of the world is ‘drug agnostic’. Consider a reservoir miniature in nature filled with a drug that needs to be delivered to a certain part of the body. All this needs to be done in a sustained linear way without using pumps, valves or any electrically powered tool. Its works through the nano channel delivery system (NDS). On the basis of the size of the drug molecules, the nano channel membranes are tailored and implanted below the skin. It then moves through the membranes into the patients body. As per the researchers, presently, the nano channel size is a barrier to its movement and lower the size to 2.5 nano meters would definitely help overcome the snag and also help control the drug delivery speed. Looking at the potential of this project a multi-million dollar grant has been already approved for the same.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, the use of <strong>microscopic robots</strong> for treatment is just at its infancy stage and a lot needs to be worked on yet, but positively it would take less than a decade to see it reach the operation theatres of hospitals and that’s definitely a good sign.</p>
<p align="justify">Know about <a title="Best medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">best medical college</a> and <a title="Good Hospitals in Bangalore" href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">hospitals in Banglaore</a></p>
<p align="justify">* Disclaimer – Sourced from the internet. Verification required</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
