<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Health Benefits Of Yoga &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/health-benefits-of-yoga/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 05:41:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>10 Health Benefits Of Yoga For Holistic Living</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/10-health-benefits-of-yoga-for-holistic-living/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 11:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical collegs in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Benefits Of Yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga For Holistic Living]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1138</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We are all aware of that yoga has immense benefits when it comes to health, whether it is physical or mental and overall fitness as well. Yoga, a 5000 years old practice is known to have numerous health and fitness benefits. Let’s look through 10 of the benefits that Yoga provides and that you can &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/10-health-benefits-of-yoga-for-holistic-living/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "10 Health Benefits Of Yoga For Holistic Living"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
are all aware of that yoga has immense benefits when it comes to
health, whether it is physical or mental and overall fitness as well.
Yoga, a 5000 years old practice is known to have numerous health and
fitness benefits. Let’s look through 10 of the benefits that Yoga
provides and that you can reap. – And yes, you do not have to be a
pro to do so. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/10-Health-Benefits-Of-Yoga-For-Holistic-Living-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1139" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/10-Health-Benefits-Of-Yoga-For-Holistic-Living-1.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/10-Health-Benefits-Of-Yoga-For-Holistic-Living-1-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>Present
day, not only physical health is an issue, but so is mental health.
The unhealthy lifestyles are topped with hectic and stressful work
schedules taking a toll on the mental and emotional health of humans.
While exercise, walks and activity helps work on physical health,
Yoga works well with mental health issues as well. Yoga is
responsible for stimulation of the love and bonding hormone called
oxytocin. Hence, those who practice yoga on a regular basis 
</p>



<p><strong>Stress
Buster – </strong>Yoga can
help heal issues of mental health like depression, psychiatric
conditions, schizophrenia by increasing the secretion levels of the
hormone called oxytocin, known to be the boding hormone. 
</p>



<p><strong>Back
Pain Relief – </strong>There
are studies to prove that yoga does help in providing relief with
chronic back pain. Yoga is even good for people who do not have any
back pain issues as yoga can help improve spinal flexibility. 
</p>



<p><strong>Fertility
boost – </strong>Doing
yoga on a regular basis helps de-stress and thus opens up the
energetic channels of the body. The body is relaxed and thus enhances
the fertility as the blood flow to the reproductive organs of the
body increases, leading to positive conception results. 
</p>



<p><strong>Arthritis
Healer – </strong>Yoga is
a healer when it comes to rheumatoid arthritis, particularly iyengar
yoga. Study has already proved that gentle yoga like bikram yoga does
have benefits as arthritis allows slow movements. 
</p>



<p><strong>Heart
Attack </strong>&#8211; With heart
disease yoga just works wonders, to say the least. Study has proved
that doing yoga on regular basis improves hearth health, stamina and
overall helps in reducing heart disease risk 
</p>



<p>Well, these are not the only health benefits that yoga offers, there are many more advantages of yoga that help you to lead a healthy lifestyle physically as well as mentally.  </p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
