<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>medical colleges in karnataka &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/medical-colleges-in-karnataka/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangalore hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best dermatologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye treatment in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1238</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Also known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and obesity. Many a times your skin shows you the symptoms and &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/early-signs-of-diabetes-type-2-you-must-not-ignore/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Early Signs Of Diabetes Type 2 You Must Not Ignore"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Also
known as the silent killer, diabetes can do a lot of damage if you do
not manage to understand the early signs of it. Type 2 diabetes is a
very common form of diabetes and is a result of lack of exercise and
obesity. 
</p>



<p>Many
a times your skin shows you the symptoms and it is preventable if you
exercise and maintain normal weight. As per reports around 90% of
cases of diabetes are apparently preventable if measures are taken on
time. Furthermore, if diabetes type 2 is left untreated then it could
also lead to life threatening health complications like heart attack,
kidney failure and strokes. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1239" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore.jpg 825w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Early-Signs-Of-Diabetes-Type-2-You-Must-Not-Ignore-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>So,
why are the warning signs not taken seriously, is one question that
haunts many. The reason could be as simple as not taking them as
signs but simple health issues that could fade away with time or just
taking notice and delaying checkup till it’s forgotten. 
</p>



<p>Well,
let us run down some of the signs that could help you alert around
type 2 diabetes. 
</p>



<ol><li>

	 <strong>Frequent Washroom trips</strong>
	– high blood sugar means kidneys work hard to remove the excess
	sugar form the blood and hence it is considered to be an alarm for
	diabetes if one has to frequently wake up to go to pee. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Frequent urge to drink
	water</strong> – Due to frequent urination, even the urge to drink
	water increases due to dehydration
	</li><li>

	Fatigue – The energy levels
	of type 2 diabetes people are low due to deficiency of sugar through
	the blood stream to the body cells. 
	
	</li><li>

	<strong>Hunger pangs</strong> – Due
	to lack of energy people suffering from type 2 diabetes tend to feel
	hungry on a constant basis even if they’d have eaten recently
	enough
	</li><li>

	<strong>Blurry Vision </strong>– At
	times high sugar could damage vision and result into blurred vision
	in one or both the eyes
	</li><li>

	<strong>Yeast Infections </strong>–
	Excess sugar in body could lead to yeast infection. The affected
	areas could get red, sore or itchy. 
	
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Tingling and Numbness</strong>
	– Due to rise in sugar levels people with this condition could
	experience tingling and numbess in their hands and feet. Known as
	neuropathy this condition has chances of worsening with time and
	hence early intervention is required.
</li></ol>



<ol><li>

	<strong>Skin Darkening</strong> – For
	people suffering from diabetes, dark, velvety and soft patches
	appear on skin anywhere around the armpits, groin or neck. 
	
</li></ol>



<p> Perhaps, its not that difficult to be alarmed if we only pay attention at the signs. Early intervention could help deal with diabetes in a better way and also keep other life threatening conditions at bay.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 06:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Career In India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1234</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/exercise-your-way-to-reduce-depression/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Exercise Your Way To Reduce Depression"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>
A First of its kind study has revealed that physical activity can aid
in reducing depression even if there is a higher genetic risk. The
study was carried out by author Karmel Choi, Ph.D and her colleagues
at the Massachusetts General Hospital of Boston. They used the
electronic and genomic data records of 8000 participants in Partners
biobank for the study. The study was spread across 2 years wherein
the lead author Choi and his team studied through millions of data
points in order to look into people having any depression related
diagnosis. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1235" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Exercise-Your-Way-To-Reduce-Depression-1-768x511.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>
They also calculated the genetic risk score for every participant by
combining information around every participant complete genome to
come to score that determines their genetic risk for developing
depression. The data also revealed that people with high genetic risk
score could be diagnosed about it anytime in the coming 2 years. But,
those who were active physically even with higher genetic risk of
depression were less likely to experience depression. 
</p>



<p>
As per Choi an average 35 minutes of exercise on a daily basis could
help you reduce the risk of depression and even protect you against
depression bouts in future. The findings of the study Choi said that
“our findings strongly suggest that, when it comes to depression,
genes are not destiny and that being physically active has the
potential to neutralize the added risk of future episodes in
individuals who are genetically vulnerable”.</p>



<p> Well, exercise is always a good idea because it is useful and sparing out 30 to 35 minutes for yourself every day is the least you could do for your own wellness. A fit body definitely helps to keep you mind fit. So, invest in exercising atleast half and hour a day and you’ll see the difference in your overall fitness levels soon.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>&#8220;The <a href="https://college.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/">department of physiotherapy</a> was established in 2003 at <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RajaRajeswari Medical College and Hospital</a> to cater to the preventive, creative, therapeutic and rehabilitation needs of the rural people need was felt to impart the much needed physiotherapy vocational and rehabilitation training programme. &#8220;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 10:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1231</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[No a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions. But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town, even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus. The &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-climatic-conditions-effect-mental-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Climatic Conditions Effect Mental Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>No
a new idea really, as there have been studies earlier around
relationship study between mental health and climatic conditions.
But, as the climatic conditions seen to be changing drastically and
global warming issues and more are becoming the talk of the town,
even the psychological health issues are becoming the areas of focus.
</p>



<p>The
earlier studies primarily were carried out for a short period of time
and only have been able to identify  the links between mental health
as well as temperature but the research till date only involves short
time period and more focused on connection rather than causal
factors. Moreover, this findings have so far not yielded any
substantial conclusions. So, the researchers with this study are
hoping to get answers to their questions that are not answered as
yet. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1232" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health.png 860w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-300x160.png 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/climate-change-mental-health-768x411.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>The
researchers for their study has gathered data from various sources
including Californian emergency departments,  collecting data and
analyzing information from the data of mental health diagnosis visits
during the period of 2005 – 2016. 
</p>



<p>They
even mined for data around suicides in America during 1960 – 2016
period.  These information was based on statuses that were
individually self-reported.  After drilling the climatic temperature
in US down, the researchers managed to develop ‘’fine spatial and
temporal scales”.</p>



<p>From
the study the researchers concluded that the mental health outcomes
decrease as the temperatures cool and the increase mental health
issues with rise in temperatures. Statistically speaking they found
that there was a rise in 0.48% rise in mental health visits with a
rise in average monthly temperature of 1<sup>0</sup> F and even a
rise in suicides by 0.35%</p>



<p>In
short, the rise and drop in temperatures has a significant impact of
the mental health because the authors of the study also showed
stability in the estimates even when accounted for socio economic
status and air conditioning adoption. 
</p>



<p>As for suicide rate, it rises only if there is a rise in temperature amid the growing season because growing season is all about crop yields. If the temperature rises, the crop yield reduces and leads to financial issues that in turn increase the risk of suicides.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Horns Of The Dilemma – Dairy Good Or Bad For Health</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/horns-of-the-dilemma-dairy-good-or-bad-for-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 06:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rrmch bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1224</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Though fruits and veggies are known to be healthy options as far as food is concerned there are conflicting views over dairy products and even their consumption levels on a regular basis. Milk and milk products in plenty are a must for kids and adolescents as milk is a rich source of calcium. Though milk &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/horns-of-the-dilemma-dairy-good-or-bad-for-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Horns Of The Dilemma – Dairy Good Or Bad For Health"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Though
fruits and veggies are known to be healthy options as far as food is
concerned there are conflicting views over dairy products and even
their consumption levels on a regular basis.  Milk and milk products
in plenty are a must for kids and adolescents as milk is a rich
source of calcium.  Though milk is good, it comes under saturated
fats and hence for people on a diet skimmed milk is a better option. 
</p>



<p> As per global standards the average consumption is around 2 to 2.5 servings a day for children.  Organizations like USDA and <strong>National Institute of Health (NIH)</strong> dairy is a vital source of magnesium, phosphorous, Protein and Vitamin D. A deficiency in calcium could raise the risk of osteoporosis as bones become weak and brittle.  </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Horns-Of-The-Dilemma-–-Dairy-Good-Or-Bad-For-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Horns-Of-The-Dilemma-–-Dairy-Good-Or-Bad-For-Health.jpg 512w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Horns-Of-The-Dilemma-–-Dairy-Good-Or-Bad-For-Health-300x208.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px" /></figure></div>



<p>Having
said that there are conflicting views around consumption of dairy
products.  As per a systematic review as well as meta-analysis says
that increase in dairy consumption increases the risk of
osteoporosis. But, not all studies are included in the said analysis.
 
</p>



<p>Another
long term study of Sweden that included 61000 women and 45000 men
revealed a potential link between high milk consumption as well as
high rate of bone fractures.  Though a Japanese study carried out
over 94,980 people revealed that a rise in consumption of milk did
lower the mortality risk. 
</p>



<p>Even the <strong>American heart Institution (AHA)</strong> has said that saturated fats could lead to increase in cholesterol as well as heart disease. Hence, some full fat dairy products do not come in the list of heart healthy diet recommendations. Furthermore, the national lung and blood institute has advised people to limit their dairy intake and use low fat dairy in their diet.  </p>



<p>There
is an article with umpteen analyses as well as reviews that do not
believe that saturated fats cause heart disease. It also states that
the saturated fats could decrease the risk of diabetes that is linked
to obesity.</p>



<p> So, while there is conflict with studies to support, dairy could be a healthy option if taken in limit. It could be helpful for people suffering from type 2 diabetes.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a> is one of the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Best Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Much Fiber Intake For Prevention Of Diseases</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-much-fiber-intake-for-prevention-of-diseases/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 06:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best neurologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how much fiber intake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1221</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A new study revealed exactly how much fiber is required for keeping the chronic conditions as well as premature mortality at bay. The objective of the study is to set the guideline for consumption of fiber besides bringing to light information around the carbs responsible for protection against non-communicable diseases as well as curb weight &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/how-much-fiber-intake-for-prevention-of-diseases/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How Much Fiber Intake For Prevention Of Diseases"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
new study revealed exactly how much fiber is required for keeping the
chronic conditions as well as premature mortality at bay.  The
objective of the study is to set the guideline for consumption of
fiber besides bringing to light information around the carbs
responsible for protection against non-communicable diseases as well
as curb weight gain. 
</p>



<p>The
author of the study namely Professor Jim Mann, of Otago University
New Zealand and the author of the paper Andrew Reynolds is a
postdoctoral research fellow at Otago’s Dunedin School of Medicine.

</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1222" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases.jpg 678w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/How-Much-Fiber-Intake-For-Prevention-Of-Diseases-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 678px) 100vw, 678px" /></figure>



<p>The
study was carried out by Reynolds and colleagues by examination of a
data that had 185 observational studies that included 135 million
person-years besides 58 clinical trials that involved the
participation of 4600 people.  The study analysis was carried across
40 years. 
</p>



<p>As
per prof. Mann, the motivation behind this study was analysis of
previous reviews and meta-analysis.  The scientists studied chronic
condition incidences as well as premature deaths resulting from them.
 The conditions included cardiovascular diseases, stroke, colon
cancer, type 2 diabetes, cancers such as esophageal cancer,
endometrial cancer, prostate cancer to name a few. 
</p>



<p>The
results of the study revealed that people who consume more fiber
daily are      15-30% less prone to premature deaths or any of the
aforementioned conditions. It also determined that daily consumption
of 25 -29 gms of fibre is good for health. Though consumption of more
than 29 gms of fibre could be even more beneficial. 
</p>



<p>Having
said that, the authors cleared that the study did not present any
side effects of fibre consumption but too much fibre could also be
harmful particularly for people with iron and mineral deficiencies.
Even consumption of whole grains in excess can lead to iron
deficiency as per researchers. 
</p>



<p>Lastly,
the study also found that consumption of high amount of fibre results
does relate to less weight and cholesterol levels. 
</p>



<p> Prof. Mann says “ Health benefits of fiber are supported by over 100 years of research into its chemistry, physical properties, physiology and effects on metabolism.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital, Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monsoon And Child Health Issues</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 05:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monsoon And Child Health Issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1173</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera, Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Monsoon And Child Health Issues"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Well,
everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you
hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on
your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along
health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera,
Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. Here’s
a run-down five of the most common illness viral/bacteria borne, that
you need to protect your child from – 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1174" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg 975w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-768x451.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Dengue</strong>
– Caused by the Aedes aegypti mosquito, Dengue mosquitos breed in
stagnant water be it flower pots, buckets, tree holes or drums etc.
The incubation period is four to seven days after being bitten. The
symptoms include high grade fever with decreasing platelet count as
well as rashes. To prevent dengue try to keep your body covered as
much as possible and use mosquito repellents. Citronella is a good
mosquito repellent plant. 
</p>



<p><strong>Diarrhoea</strong>
– This is one
condition that can be prevented with proper precautions as it is
caused because of unhygienic food and water consumption. The best way
to prevent it is to drink boiled water and eat home cooked food. Both
the types of diarrhea, chronic as well as acute can be managed
through appropriate and timely treatment. 
</p>



<p><strong>Typhoid
</strong><strong>– </strong>This is
another waterborne condition that is caused by S typhi bacteria. The
main reason is poor sanitation. The symptoms include weakness, pain,
fever as well as sore throat to name a few. This condition can also
be prevented by avoiding street food, keeping your hands clean and
keeping yourself hydrated with healthy fluids. 
</p>



<p><strong>Malaria
– </strong>This is also a
water borne condition that is caused due to the female anopheles
mosquito. This mosquito breeds in water logged areas and hence is a
common condition in monsoon. The symptoms include fever with chills
or shivering, body ache and weakness, etc. The best way to prevent
the cause of malaria is to keep surroundings clean especially water
tanks. 
</p>



<p style="text-align:left">Jaundice – Jaundice is also a water borne disease that could go serious if not treated properly.  This is again a result of consuming contaminated food and water. The symptoms of jaundice include yellow eyes and urine, weakness and liver dysfunction.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Burnout – A Medical Condition Or Not?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/burnout-a-medical-condition-or-not/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 06:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Burnout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs admissions in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1117</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Do not misunderstand burnout to be a medical condition says WHO, that erroneously stated that it was a medical condition. The clarification comes as stating it as a “chronic workplace stress that hasn’t been managed successfully”. So, what is burnout exactly and what are the symptoms of this condition that has been termed as permanent &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/burnout-a-medical-condition-or-not/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Burnout – A Medical Condition Or Not?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Do not misunderstand burnout to be a medical condition says WHO, that erroneously stated that it was a medical condition. The clarification comes as stating it as a “chronic workplace stress that hasn’t been managed successfully”. So, what is burnout exactly and what are the symptoms of this condition that has been termed as permanent stress of work. Let’s explore –</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1118 aligncenter" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout.jpg" alt="Burnout" width="485" height="312" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout.jpg 485w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout-300x193.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 485px) 100vw, 485px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><b>Burnout – Definition, Symptoms and Causes</b></p>
<p align="justify">A state of being in permanent stress as a result of work is what Burnout means. It is more of a psychological problem rather than a physical issue. The symptoms usually include work anxiety, aggression and anger outbursts, detachment from work, feeling unworthy, aloofness, mood swings, insomnia, fatigue, stomach ache, appetite loss, breathlessness, headaches, chest pain, drug or alcohol addiction and lack of interest in the job, to name a few . It is a gradual process and not an out of the blue sorts. With time the symptoms worsen.</p>
<p align="justify"><b>Risk Factors</b></p>
<p align="justify">People who are workaholics and too much into their work tend to suffer from it and most of them are known to be high achievers at work and perfectionists. Their passion about work is so fueled that they even ignore the symptoms of Burnout.</p>
<p><b>Behavioral Indications </b></p>
<p>Burnout is definite to bring in some symptoms like withdrawal from responsibilities, coming late to office and leaving early, slowing down when it comes to work, to name a few. There is a visible difference between Burnout and Stress like stress is about losing energy while burnout is about losing motivation, hope and ideals. It causes anxiety while burnout causes depression and detachment. Stress leads to physical damage while burnout to emotional one.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_957" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-957" style="width: 422px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/medical-admission-mbbs-ms-md-phd/"><img class="wp-image-957 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/rrmch-logo-1.png" alt="RRMCH - Medical Admissions " width="422" height="101" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/rrmch-logo-1.png 422w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/rrmch-logo-1-300x72.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 422px) 100vw, 422px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-957" class="wp-caption-text">MBBS MS MD Admissions in 2019-20</figcaption></figure></p>
<p><b>Dealing with it</b></p>
<p align="justify">One of the most effective ways to deal with it is to speak to someone who is very dear or close to you and also is a good listener. This will help you calm down. Try spending quality time with your dear ones. Socialize a bit with the people you are working with, participate in activities in workplace. Indulge yourself into some hobby or outdoor activity or take a break from work. You could be at a phase where you might just have to consider quitting your job and taking a break before you begin again. Alternatively, joining a support community with cause can help you connect with like-minded people and help you de-tress on a regular basis. If nothing else seem to find you a way out it’s never too late to find new friends. With internet at your help finding friends is not a difficult task.</p>
<p align="justify">Know more about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH </a></strong></p>
<p align="justify">*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medicine As a Career in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forensic science colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physiotherapy Colleges in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapy in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio diagnosis course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=688</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medicine-as-a-career-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Medicine As a Career in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Indian parents have been long obsessed with this career stream and yes no marks for guess that right… its medical offcourse. Though, times are changing, but the attraction for medicine hasn’t faded as yet with parents only because of the surefire career that it is. But, over the years there are a lot of choices that are available around the medicine field apart from MBBS. So, students who aren’t able to crack the NEET can try to opt for some related courses that include BDS, Physiotherapy, Phsychiatry, Pharmacy and more. So, as per your area of interest you may choose a course. One major advantage of NEET being brought into effect is that intelligent students coming from lower income groups can try to get entry into medical without paying hefty donations to colleges.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-689 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg" alt="Medicine As a Career in India" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Medicine-As-a-Career-in-India-2-1.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">In case you opt for <a title="MBBS Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/course/mbbs/" target="_blank">MBBS</a>, a masters is always a good idea considering future growth. You could either opt for a MD or MS. Though being a surgeon isnt a cake walk and invovles daily encounters with patients fighting for their lives. Its a great responshibility to shoulder and a time costing too.</p>
<p align="justify">As a surgeon or a masters degree holder you need to be available to your patients anytime. It could be in the wee hours of the night as well. So, its quite a stressful and hectic work schedule that you’ll have to manage. But, the perks include immense work satisfaction with successful medical procedures and blessing from families. If surgery is not your cup of tea then you might as well opt for MD in areas like radiology, anaesthesiology, paediatrics, forensic medicine and more.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, if not MBBS than the option of <a title="Physiotherapy Career in India" href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/physiotherapy-career-in-india-the-scope/" target="_blank">Physiotherapy</a>, <a title="Dental College in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrdch.org/" target="_blank">BDS</a>, Ayurvedic medicine, Homeopathy, Veterinary and Pharmacy are definitely some of the good choices around medicine. A masters degree with these streams can offer rewarding career prospects.</p>
<p align="justify">Coming down to the bottom line, medical education does blow a hole into your pocket and for students coming from middle income and lower income groups, its not an easy way ahead. But, with the help of student loans, you may as well manage to realize your medical education dreams. Though, it is important to have indepth information on the student loan interest, payback procedure and time for repayment in detail, needs to be known particularly when you are planning to pursue higher education abroad.</p>
<p align="justify">Medical is undoubtedly a lucrative career but having said that it does come with its own cons which need to be considered before taking a plunge into it.</p>
<p align="justify">know about leading <a title="Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://college.rrmch.org/" target="_blank">medical colleges in Bangalore </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
