<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>good medical colleges in bangalore] &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/good-medical-colleges-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 10:57:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Omega 3 Fatty Acids And Health Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/omega-3-fatty-acids-and-health-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 10:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiology hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good medical colleges in bangalore]]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1199</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Some of us are definitely aware of omega 3 fatty acids and their benefits. But, many of us are not aware that fatty acids are present not only in animals but plants also. The animal based fatty acids include doosahexaenoic acid (DHA) as well as eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA). While the animal based omega 3 fatty &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/omega-3-fatty-acids-and-health-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Omega 3 Fatty Acids And Health Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Some
of us are definitely aware of omega 3 fatty acids and their benefits.
 But, many of us are not aware that fatty acids are present not only
in animals but plants also. The animal based fatty acids include
doosahexaenoic acid (DHA) as well as eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA).
While the animal based omega 3 fatty acids comes from fish oils,
plant based come from plant sources. These sources contain
alpha-lionelic acid (ALA), that can be converted into Omega-3 fatty
acids of the body. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Omega-3-Fatty-Acids-And-Health-Benefits.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1200" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Omega-3-Fatty-Acids-And-Health-Benefits.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Omega-3-Fatty-Acids-And-Health-Benefits-300x156.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Omega-3-Fatty-Acids-And-Health-Benefits-768x399.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>But,
most of us are only aware about the health benefits of animal based
fish oils with EPA and DHA. But, many of us again aren’t aware
about the amount of omega 3, fatty acids that our body requires, even
though there is no set standard for intake of the same. 
</p>



<p>Many
experts believe and recommend omega 3 fatty acids for people
suffering from cardiovascular conditions particularly higher doses
for people having high cholesterol levels. Prescribed medications
that are FDA approved are available for people with conditions rather
than the supplements. 
</p>



<p>Omega
3 acids are recommended only for adults and children should not be
given any supplements of omega 3 acids before consulting the doctor.
Though natural sources of omega 3 fatty acids can be consumed by all
irrespective of ages, only if you have no significant allergies
around the same. 
</p>



<p>Natural
Sources of omega 3 fatty acids include Cod liver, Soybeans and tofu,
Walnuts, Salmon, trout, tuna and sardines, to name a few. The
international organization AHA recommends adults for males and
females except pregnant women to increase the intake of omega 3 fatty
acids 
</p>



<p>Even
avoiding the intake of omega 6 fatty acids that include eggs, meat as
well as oil can help in increasing the levels of omega 3 fatty acids
in blood. Balancing of omega 3 fatty acids to that of omega 6 can
help you manage many health conditions in a better way and reduce the
risk of certain conditions as well. As per reports people in USA
consume 14-25 times more omega 6 fatty acids as compared to omega 3
fatty acids and this imbalance is not good for health, certainly. 
</p>



<p> Having said that, omega 3 fatty acids  supplements should not be consumed without consulting your physician because they do have certain side effects particularly pregnant women with a diabetes risk should avoid them.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about the <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><strong>Best Cardiologist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thunderclap Headache &#8211; Know More About This Sudden Intense Painful Condition</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/thunderclap-headache/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 09:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good medical colleges in bangalore]]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thunderclap Headache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1153</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[This is rare kind of headache that starts suddenly out of the blue and is an experience you won’t forget. The intensity of it is very high, something you would not have experienced ever. It lasts for a while but that few minutes could be to painful. No wonder, it is known to be worst &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/thunderclap-headache/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Thunderclap Headache &#8211; Know More About This Sudden Intense Painful Condition"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This
is rare kind of headache that starts suddenly out of the blue and is
an experience you won’t forget. The intensity of it is very high,
something you would not have experienced ever. It lasts for a while
but that few minutes could be to painful. No wonder, it is known to
be worst headache in one’s life. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Thunderclap-Headache.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1155" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Thunderclap-Headache.jpg 650w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Thunderclap-Headache-300x208.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" /><figcaption>young woman who have a headache</figcaption></figure>



<p>Though
many of us might just forget about it once it is gone, it is
advisable to get yourself checked if it happens to you because it
could be life threatening.  Even if it is not, better to visit a
doctor. The symptoms of thunderclap headache include-</p>



<ol><li>
Sudden
	high intensity headache
	</li><li>
Vomiting
	or nausea
	</li><li>
Headache
	with neck or lower back pain 
	
	</li><li>
Dizziness
	and losing consciousness
	</li><li>
Experiencing
	the worst ever headache
</li></ol>



<p>The intensity of pain of a thunderclap headache can reach its zenith is a matter of 60 seconds. Sometimes it just goes away forever while at times it could last over a period of seven days. There is a difference between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thunderclap_headache" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="thunderclap headaches  (opens in a new tab)">thunderclap headaches </a>and migraine but thunderclap headaches that are not categorized as life threatening are considered as a kind of migraine only.  </p>



<p><strong>Triggers
/ Causes</strong></p>



<p>A
thunderclap headache is known to be the result of bleeding in the
brain or a symptoms of subarachnoid hemorrhage.  The life threatening
causes for this headache include –</p>



<ol><li>
Internal
	bleeding due to rupture of blood vessel in brain
	</li><li>
Ischemic
	stroke
	</li><li>
Hemorrhagic
	stroke
	</li><li>
Inflammation
	of blood vessel
	</li><li>
Reversible
	cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome
</li></ol>



<p>The common triggers though could include bowel movement strain, injury, sexual or physical activity as well.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about the <a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><strong>RRMCH</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Common Food Allergens in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-common-food-allergens-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 05:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Common Food Allergens in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[common food allergies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Allergens in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[full health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good medical colleges in bangalore]]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1083</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Allergies are very common amongst us. Either we know we are allergic to stuff based on our experience post consumption of these foods or we aren’t. Many people have hiccups on eating spicy stuff like a chilly, while many get a runny nose. There are people who suffer from lactose intolerance and suffer from diarrhea &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-common-food-allergens-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "5 Common Food Allergens in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Allergies are very common amongst us. Either we know we are allergic to stuff based on our experience post consumption of these foods or we aren’t. Many people have hiccups on eating spicy stuff like a chilly, while many get a runny nose. There are people who suffer from lactose intolerance and suffer from diarrhea after consuming foods like milk or cheese. But, if you think all these are allergies, then you aren’t completely right. These can be categorized under food intolerance or insensitivity. A food allergy is not the same. It occurs when your body considers harmless food to apparently harm the body. Food allergies could range from creating simple reactions like rashes on skin, or irritation to eyes or breathing problems to turn out to be life threatening if immediate steps are not taken. The best way to keep yourself safe is to be aware of such triggers and avoid them.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1084" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India.jpg" alt="5 Common Food Allergens in India" width="800" height="600" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Let’s look through 10 different food allergens and their side effects or reactions they cause. The most common allergens are as follows &#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Eggs</strong> &#8211; The trigger that causes food allergies in eggs is egg protein like conalbumin, ovumucoid and ovalbumin. This allergy is found mostly in children than in adults. Some of the allergens are destroyed when the eggs are cooked but not all. This allergy can also cause anaphylaxis. The allergy can vary from person to person. While some might be allergic to yoke, some to egg white and some to all.</p>
<p><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-995 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg" alt="" width="397" height="41" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg 397w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore-300x31.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 397px) 100vw, 397px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Fish</strong> &#8211; Fish allergy could be really harmful. It can be life threatening and lead to anaphylaxis. The allergy can show reactions like throat swelling, diarrhea and puking, skin irritations, blood pressure drop and anaphylaxis as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Milk</strong> – Many children may be allergic to cow’s milk. It can also be passed to the child indirectly through breast feeding. Many children out-grow of the allergy once adults but one fifth of them are said to have it in their adulthood too. The presence of the milk antibodies can be determined with the help of the blood test.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Soyabean</strong> &#8211; Soy bean is also one of the common allergy to have. The reactions of soya bean allergy includes vomiting, diarrhea, ashes as well as stomach cramps. Sometimes it could also cause swelling of the tongue, lips as well as hand, feet and puffed eyes too. Other reactions include bloating, flatulence. Though, it rarely gets life threatening and cause anaphylaxis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Shellfish</strong> – Shell fish includes aquatic life like shrimp, oyster, crabs, mussels, clams, scallops, to name a few. This allergy can get serious and even vapor of the cooking shell fish can be allergic. The reaction are very much similar to other allergic reactions</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As far as allergens go, prevention is always the best idea. So be aware of allergies if you have any and avoid food that can cause allergies primarily. Also, in case you get one for the first time, take immediate action and consult a doctor without wasting much of a time.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about <strong><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/">Top Private Hospitals in Bangalore, Karnataka</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Step Towards Preventing Heart Disease &#8211; A Vaccine To Lower Cholesterol Levels</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/preventing-heart-disease/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 09:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good medical colleges in bangalore]]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preventing Heart Disease]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=772</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The word cholesterol has always been able to raise eyebrows of people because the rising levels of cholesterol is a factual indicator of growing heart disease. While there has been a lot of research and development in the field of cardiac study, here is some further news around the same. Well, lowering cholesterol for a &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/preventing-heart-disease/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Another Step Towards Preventing Heart Disease &#8211; A Vaccine To Lower Cholesterol Levels"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">The word cholesterol has always been able to raise eyebrows of people because the rising levels of cholesterol is a factual indicator of growing heart disease. While there has been a lot of research and development in the field of cardiac study, here is some further news around the same. Well, lowering cholesterol for a healthy heart is a known fact. We all know how high levels of low density lipo-protein (LDL), also known as bad cholesterol can lead to a stroke due to atherosclerosis or the build up of plaque in the arteries thereby clogging them.</p>
<p align="justify">Now, we have this vaccine named Ato4A that has the ability to lower cholesterol levels in the body. It is a cholesterol lowering vaccine by nature and its role is to induce the antibodies production against an enzyme by name PCSK9 responsible for preventing the LDL cholesterol clearance from blood. It apparently attacks the PCSK9 enzyme and reduces the buildup of LDL cholesterol.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Preventing-Heart-Disease-1-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft wp-image-773 size-medium" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Preventing-Heart-Disease-1-300x199.jpg" alt="Preventing Heart Disease" width="300" height="199" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">The vaccine has already been experimented on mice. After feeding the mice with high cholesterol based western food for a while in order to increase atherosclerosis. The findings clearly showed some amazing results.<br />
While the total lowering in cholesterol was a whooping 53%, the reversal of the atherosclerotic damage to blood vessels was a startling 64% and reduction in the biological markers of blood vessel inflammation by 21-28%. The researchers also found that the antibodies were functional throughout the study with increased levels of concentrations towards the end of it.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>The PROCESS</strong><br />
Now, the PCSK9 protein is responsible for blocking the LDL cholesterol receptors. Due to this our body fails to get rid of this Cholesterol from blood. When the vaccine Ato4a is injected in the body it starts producing antibodies that in turn block the PSCK9’s function. As a result the activity of LDL cholesterol receptors increases.</p>
<p align="justify">A notable difference though between the conventional vaccines and Ato4A is that usually the antibodies in conventional vaccines are only specific to foreign bacterial and viral proteins. While Ato4A induces antibodies against body proteins.</p>
<p align="justify">Thus, as per researchers the next step was to take the study forward to human beings and see how the results fare. If it works then surely, this discovery of sorts is going to help fight heart diseases and stroke more effectively in the times to come.</p>
<p align="justify"><strong>Dr. H. P. Prabhuswamy, MBBS, MS, M. CH, FICC, FIACS, Cardiac Surgery, Professor &amp; HOD, Dept. of CTVS, <a title="Best Medical Colleges in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org" target="_blank">RRMCH</a> and team conducted a Minimally Invasive Cardiac Surgery.</strong></p>
<p align="justify">
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
