<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Plantar Fasciitis &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/plantar-fasciitis/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 05:36:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>All You Need To Know About Plantar Fasciitis</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/know-about-plantar-fasciitis/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 05:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Know About Plantar Fasciitis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plantar Fasciitis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what is Plantar Fasciitis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1089</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[One of the most common causes leading to heel pain is plantar. Plantar causes the thick band of tissue that connects the heel bone to your toes and runs through the foot bottom to swell. The pain is of stabbing nature that begins with your first step in the morning. Once you get on your &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/know-about-plantar-fasciitis/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "All You Need To Know About Plantar Fasciitis"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">One of the most common causes leading to heel pain is plantar. Plantar causes the thick band of tissue that connects the heel bone to your toes and runs through the foot bottom to swell. The pain is of stabbing nature that begins with your first step in the morning. Once you get on your feet and start walking. Though it decreases eventually but can reoccur once you sit for a long time. It is a common problem faced by runners and even obese people who don’t wear proper shoes.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Know-About-Plantar-Fasciitis.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1090" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Know-About-Plantar-Fasciitis.jpg" alt="Know About Plantar Fasciitis" width="750" height="457" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Know-About-Plantar-Fasciitis.jpg 750w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Know-About-Plantar-Fasciitis-300x183.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Causes</strong><br />
The role of Plantar fascia is to act like shock bowstring that supports your foot arch. The fascia gets small tears if the tension around the bowstring increases significantly. If this continuous on a repetitive basis than it leads to further inflammation and irritation as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Risk Factors</strong><br />
Some of the factors that could be the risks for the aforementioned condition include standing for long time at work, obesity, foot mechanics, age as well as certain exercise types.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Symptoms</strong><br />
Stabbing pain at foots base around the heel. The pain is really bad in the beginning when you take your first few steps. The trigger is stagnancy for a long time. It is also known to worsen after exercise.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Treatment</strong><br />
The diagnosis is done on the basis of physical examination and considering the medical history. The treatment includes conservative method, like use of ice pads, stretching as well as resting but require several months. Medications are also prescribed by doctors and surgery if conservative procedures are not working. The surgical and other procedures include Extracorporeal shock wave therapy, injecting steroids, Tenex procedures and surgery as well, when nothing works.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Home Remedies and Lifestyle Changes</strong><br />
To manage your pain, you need to make a few lifestyle changes like using shoes that support, maintain a healthy weight, avoid using worn out shoes, opting for a sport that is low impact and doing arch stretching workout or simple home exercise.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about the <a href="http://college.rrmch.org/"><strong>Medical Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
