<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>private medical colleges in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/private-medical-colleges-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 06:13:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 09:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best cardiologist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best orthopedic hospital in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthopedic doctors in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physiotherapist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1213</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market of heart conditions. As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/sports-hobbies-for-middle-aged-women-benefits/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Sports Hobbies For Middle Aged Women – Benefits"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A
study around post-menopausal women published in the journal Frontiers
in Endocrinology reveals that physical activity that involves sports
in leisure time helps in managing the blood lipid profile well, thus
reducing cardiovascular conditions as blood lipid profile is a market
of heart conditions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1214" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits.png 620w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sports-Hobbies-For-Middle-Aged-Women-–-Benefits-300x179.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></figure>



<p> As per Karvinen and his team, after menopause the risk of <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/">cardiovascular</a> conditions increases significantly in women and lipid profile is a reliable marker to measure heart health.  He and his colleagues investigated around 193 menopausal women participants of the age group 47-55 from Finland, registered for the Estrogenic Regulation of Muscle Apoptosis (ERMA) study.  The study is co-authored by Dr Mathew Jergenson of Minnesota Medical School and University in Minneapolis. The reason behind conducting the study as per him was to explore if physical activity did have a role in cardiovascular risk factors.  </p>



<p>
He says “It is well known that physical activity has health
benefits, yet it is less clear to what extent physical activity
prevents negative changes in lipid profile while women are in their
menopausal transition.  The participants were monitored for physical
activity levels in leisure time, generally and specifically also,
using accelerometers and had to answer questions as well.</p>



<p>
Leisure is the time that is not related to routine daily work be it
housework or commuting and includes sport or recreation activities in
free time. 
</p>



<p>The
researchers found out that there was indeed a connection between more
activities during leisure time and lowering of cholesterol levels
particularly (LDL) as well as with high levels of cholesterol (HDL). 
Karvin reports that indeed the leisure time physical activities were
related to healthy lipid profiles. But, that does not mean that the
negative changes in lipid profile during menopause can be fully done
away with due to leisure time sports activities. 
</p>



<p>The author also said that leisure time physical activities will underscore the adverse atherogenic changes in the cardiovascular risk factors in middle aged women who are healthy. Hence, sport related activities in leisure are good.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a> is having <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/physiotherapy/"><strong>Top most Physiotherapist in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Neuro hospital in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency medical services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1209</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them. It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/brain-function-and-poor-oral-health-the-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Brain Function And Poor Oral Health &#8211; The Connection"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Not one but two new studies have revealed that stress on a continuous basis can negatively impact oral health of elderly humans and also lead to a decline in the cognitive functioning in them.  It has been always said that oral health is a good indicator of a humans overall health. But, not many of us know that a declining oral health could be an indication of other risky health conditions that can also affect the quality of life of a human being.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1210" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Brain-Function-And-Poor-Oral-Health-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>An article published in the <a href="http://www.jisponline.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology (opens in a new tab)">Journal of Indian Society of Periodontology</a> shows that there is a link between tooth loss as well as gum disease with stroke occurrence.  </p>



<p>As
per the conclusions of this article of 2010, gum disease is
responsible for increase in the risk of heart attack by 20%. Well,
there’s another team at the University of New Brunswick, NJ are
focusing on a connection between oral health and cognitive decline. 
</p>



<p>Even
a research team from Rutgers University carried out a two separate
studies around perceived stress and cognitive decline and published
the reports of two separate studies in the Journal of American
Geriatrics Society.</p>



<p>Talking
about other parts of the world like for example China, XinQi Dong,
the director of Rutgers University’s Institute for Health,
healthcare policy and aging research says that in china it was the
ethnic and racial minorities who were typically vulnerable to
consequences of poor oral health.  The reason being that already
there are barriers like socio economic status and language plus
access to preventive dental care is less. Particularly, the old
Chinese Americans are at a risk of oral health problems because of
lack of regular dental checkup and dental insurance. These studies
were carried out on Chinese elderly in Chicago of 60 years and above
age. The study involved quizzing question around oral health and then
asking them to complete five cognitive tests.  The second study asked
people if they had faced issues like dry mouth besides measuring
their social strain levels, social support and perceived stress with
the help of pre-defined scales. 
</p>



<p>The study involved 2700 Chinese Americans and results revealed that around half of them did had symptoms of tooth related issues. Also, there was not significant relationship between congnitive issues and gums but researchers believe that the participants may not have reported gum problems and ignored them as they do not cause major problems to health.  </p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a> is one of the <strong><a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/neurology/">best neuro hospital in india</a></strong> </p>



<p>know more about <a href="https://www.rrdch.org"><strong>Top Dental Colleges in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celiac Disease Detection Now Made Faster With Blood Test –AN Overview</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/celiac-disease-detection-now-made-faster-with-blood-test-an-overview/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 05:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1183</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As per All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Celiac disease is known to affect around 6 – 8 million people across India. Also known as gluten sensitive enteropathy or celiac sprue, Celiac disease is known to be an emerging health condition. Celiac disease is a disease where in there is sensitivity against gluten, a &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/celiac-disease-detection-now-made-faster-with-blood-test-an-overview/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Celiac Disease Detection Now Made Faster With Blood Test –AN Overview"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As per All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Celiac disease is known to affect around 6 – 8 million people across India. Also known as gluten sensitive enteropathy or celiac sprue, Celiac disease is known to be an emerging health condition. Celiac disease is a disease where in there is sensitivity against gluten, a protein that is found in wheat, rye and barley. It does not mean allergy to gluten or intolerance to it at all. It is an auto immune disorder that occurs in 1 in 1000 genetically disposed people. This disorder is not very common in Southern India but is prevalent in North and North eastern parts of India.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1184" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg 754w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test-300x212.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></figure>



<p>Now
coming to the detection of this condition. The present method used to
diagnose it consumes weeks or months. As the time taken to detect the
condition is prolonged, people with the condition have to bear with
the side effects of it.  With the blood test, this time could be
reduced to just a few hours.  Scientists who are working on the same
have been able to pick some of the biomarkers forming the blood test
basis. They have found that when people are exposed to gluten, there
is an increase inflammatory molecules in the blood stream that can
associate with the symptoms that are in common. 
</p>



<p>Known
to affect 1 percent of the population across the western world,
Celiac disease is a condition one has to live with. In India there is
limited awareness about celiac disease and there is a dire need for
awareness around the condition and its prevention as well. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Now-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1185" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Now-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test.jpg 480w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Celiac-Disease-Detection-Now-Made-Faster-With-Blood-Test-300x218.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /></figure>



<p>As per Dr Robert P Anderson, who is the Chief Scientific Officer at ImmusanT, it was the first time that their team has been able to describe the inflammatory reaction that the patients experience when they are exposed to gluten. He also stated that the findings could also help differentiate people who have similar symptoms but do not suffer from the condition and ensure that proper treatment pertaining to their condition is given to them.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p></p>



<p>Just know about the <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">Rajarajeswari Medical College and Hospital in Bangalore</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monsoon And Child Health Issues</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 05:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[24 Hours Casualty and Emergency Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced ambulance services in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best pediatrician in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best skin specialist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book doctor appointment online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care services in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monsoon And Child Health Issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1173</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera, Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/monsoon-and-child-health-issues/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Monsoon And Child Health Issues"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Well,
everyone loves the rains, more so the foodies as the season where you
hog on hot pakoras or samosas, bhutta or chalebi while sipping on
your hot piping tea. Coming to the flip side Monsoon does bring along
health hazards in form of illness like Dengue, Jaundice, Cholera,
Malaria, thypoid, Gastro-intestinal infections, hepatitis A. Here’s
a run-down five of the most common illness viral/bacteria borne, that
you need to protect your child from – 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1174" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues.jpg 975w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Monsoon-And-Child-Health-Issues-768x451.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Dengue</strong>
– Caused by the Aedes aegypti mosquito, Dengue mosquitos breed in
stagnant water be it flower pots, buckets, tree holes or drums etc.
The incubation period is four to seven days after being bitten. The
symptoms include high grade fever with decreasing platelet count as
well as rashes. To prevent dengue try to keep your body covered as
much as possible and use mosquito repellents. Citronella is a good
mosquito repellent plant. 
</p>



<p><strong>Diarrhoea</strong>
– This is one
condition that can be prevented with proper precautions as it is
caused because of unhygienic food and water consumption. The best way
to prevent it is to drink boiled water and eat home cooked food. Both
the types of diarrhea, chronic as well as acute can be managed
through appropriate and timely treatment. 
</p>



<p><strong>Typhoid
</strong><strong>– </strong>This is
another waterborne condition that is caused by S typhi bacteria. The
main reason is poor sanitation. The symptoms include weakness, pain,
fever as well as sore throat to name a few. This condition can also
be prevented by avoiding street food, keeping your hands clean and
keeping yourself hydrated with healthy fluids. 
</p>



<p><strong>Malaria
– </strong>This is also a
water borne condition that is caused due to the female anopheles
mosquito. This mosquito breeds in water logged areas and hence is a
common condition in monsoon. The symptoms include fever with chills
or shivering, body ache and weakness, etc. The best way to prevent
the cause of malaria is to keep surroundings clean especially water
tanks. 
</p>



<p style="text-align:left">Jaundice – Jaundice is also a water borne disease that could go serious if not treated properly.  This is again a result of consuming contaminated food and water. The symptoms of jaundice include yellow eyes and urine, weakness and liver dysfunction.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nipah Virus Again On The Prowl In Kerala &#8211; All You Need To Know</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/nipah-virus-again-on-the-prowl-in-kerala-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 06:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hosital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nipah virus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1142</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Nipah Virus is again on the Prowl in Kerala. It’s just a year back that this Virus created a Havoc in the state and went on a killing Spree. The Virus with a fatality rate of over 88% killed 21 people of the 23 cases that were registered in Kerala in 2018 and scared the &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/nipah-virus-again-on-the-prowl-in-kerala-all-you-need-to-know/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Nipah Virus Again On The Prowl In Kerala &#8211; All You Need To Know"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="text-align:left"><p align="justify" style="text-align:left">Nipah Virus is again on the Prowl in Kerala. It’s just a year back that this Virus created a Havoc in the state and went on a killing Spree. The Virus with a fatality rate of over 88% killed 21 people of the 23 cases that were registered in Kerala in 2018 and scared the hell out of the citizens. This year already 5 people are suspected to have contracted the NIV and under isolation already. So, primarily, it is a good idea to avoid travel to and around the region where the Nipah outbreak has just started.  Also, here’s all you need to know about this deadly condition. The Nipah infection is associated with Pteropus Bats genus as natural hosts and was first discovered in Malaysia and Singapore among pig farmers. It occurred due to close contact with pigs and is also known to spread through infected fruit bats besides humans and others like dogs, cats, rodents and horses as well. Though, the most likely ones are known to be humans, bats and pigs. The mortality rates in pigs is not high inspite of the fact that the infection rate is  In India, the first NIV outbreak occurred in Siliguri West Bengal in the year 2001, taking lives of 45 people out of the 68 detected. Then it surfaced again in 2007, killing all the 5 people known to have contracted the virus.  </p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nipah-virus-kerala.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1143" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nipah-virus-kerala.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nipah-virus-kerala-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>There
is no denial that the Nipah Virus is highly fatal and humans contract
it through either the body fluids of pigs, exposure to secretion of
sick pigs or corpses.  Human to Human contraction occurs through body
fluids, saliva of the patient and corpse as well. The fruit bat to
human infection is known to spread by consuming raw date palm sap
that are contaminated through the saliva or the urine of bats. Even
livestock that feeds on wild fruits contaminated via bats with NIV. 
</p>



<p>Nipah infection can be variable as far as symptoms are concerned right from being asymptomatic to getting fata encephalitis or acute respiratory infection. As of now there is no vaccine or treatment available for humans as well as animals. Even the 2018 Annual Review of WHO R&amp;D Blueprint list has a mention that this condition needs an emergency and speedy research as well as development. The only way at present is to make people aware about the risk factors and the precautionary measures to be taken in order to avoid the outbreak.  </p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/">Top Leading Hospital in Bangalore</a></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Health Benefits Of Yoga For Holistic Living</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/10-health-benefits-of-yoga-for-holistic-living/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 11:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical collegs in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Benefits Of Yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga For Holistic Living]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1138</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We are all aware of that yoga has immense benefits when it comes to health, whether it is physical or mental and overall fitness as well. Yoga, a 5000 years old practice is known to have numerous health and fitness benefits. Let’s look through 10 of the benefits that Yoga provides and that you can &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/10-health-benefits-of-yoga-for-holistic-living/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "10 Health Benefits Of Yoga For Holistic Living"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
are all aware of that yoga has immense benefits when it comes to
health, whether it is physical or mental and overall fitness as well.
Yoga, a 5000 years old practice is known to have numerous health and
fitness benefits. Let’s look through 10 of the benefits that Yoga
provides and that you can reap. – And yes, you do not have to be a
pro to do so. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/10-Health-Benefits-Of-Yoga-For-Holistic-Living-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1139" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/10-Health-Benefits-Of-Yoga-For-Holistic-Living-1.jpg 768w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/10-Health-Benefits-Of-Yoga-For-Holistic-Living-1-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></figure>



<p>Present
day, not only physical health is an issue, but so is mental health.
The unhealthy lifestyles are topped with hectic and stressful work
schedules taking a toll on the mental and emotional health of humans.
While exercise, walks and activity helps work on physical health,
Yoga works well with mental health issues as well. Yoga is
responsible for stimulation of the love and bonding hormone called
oxytocin. Hence, those who practice yoga on a regular basis 
</p>



<p><strong>Stress
Buster – </strong>Yoga can
help heal issues of mental health like depression, psychiatric
conditions, schizophrenia by increasing the secretion levels of the
hormone called oxytocin, known to be the boding hormone. 
</p>



<p><strong>Back
Pain Relief – </strong>There
are studies to prove that yoga does help in providing relief with
chronic back pain. Yoga is even good for people who do not have any
back pain issues as yoga can help improve spinal flexibility. 
</p>



<p><strong>Fertility
boost – </strong>Doing
yoga on a regular basis helps de-stress and thus opens up the
energetic channels of the body. The body is relaxed and thus enhances
the fertility as the blood flow to the reproductive organs of the
body increases, leading to positive conception results. 
</p>



<p><strong>Arthritis
Healer – </strong>Yoga is
a healer when it comes to rheumatoid arthritis, particularly iyengar
yoga. Study has already proved that gentle yoga like bikram yoga does
have benefits as arthritis allows slow movements. 
</p>



<p><strong>Heart
Attack </strong>&#8211; With heart
disease yoga just works wonders, to say the least. Study has proved
that doing yoga on regular basis improves hearth health, stamina and
overall helps in reducing heart disease risk 
</p>



<p>Well, these are not the only health benefits that yoga offers, there are many more advantages of yoga that help you to lead a healthy lifestyle physically as well as mentally.  </p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH</a></p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Burnout – A Medical Condition Or Not?</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/burnout-a-medical-condition-or-not/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 06:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Burnout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs admissions in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges of india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1117</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Do not misunderstand burnout to be a medical condition says WHO, that erroneously stated that it was a medical condition. The clarification comes as stating it as a “chronic workplace stress that hasn’t been managed successfully”. So, what is burnout exactly and what are the symptoms of this condition that has been termed as permanent &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/burnout-a-medical-condition-or-not/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Burnout – A Medical Condition Or Not?"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Do not misunderstand burnout to be a medical condition says WHO, that erroneously stated that it was a medical condition. The clarification comes as stating it as a “chronic workplace stress that hasn’t been managed successfully”. So, what is burnout exactly and what are the symptoms of this condition that has been termed as permanent stress of work. Let’s explore –</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1118 aligncenter" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout.jpg" alt="Burnout" width="485" height="312" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout.jpg 485w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/burnout-300x193.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 485px) 100vw, 485px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><b>Burnout – Definition, Symptoms and Causes</b></p>
<p align="justify">A state of being in permanent stress as a result of work is what Burnout means. It is more of a psychological problem rather than a physical issue. The symptoms usually include work anxiety, aggression and anger outbursts, detachment from work, feeling unworthy, aloofness, mood swings, insomnia, fatigue, stomach ache, appetite loss, breathlessness, headaches, chest pain, drug or alcohol addiction and lack of interest in the job, to name a few . It is a gradual process and not an out of the blue sorts. With time the symptoms worsen.</p>
<p align="justify"><b>Risk Factors</b></p>
<p align="justify">People who are workaholics and too much into their work tend to suffer from it and most of them are known to be high achievers at work and perfectionists. Their passion about work is so fueled that they even ignore the symptoms of Burnout.</p>
<p><b>Behavioral Indications </b></p>
<p>Burnout is definite to bring in some symptoms like withdrawal from responsibilities, coming late to office and leaving early, slowing down when it comes to work, to name a few. There is a visible difference between Burnout and Stress like stress is about losing energy while burnout is about losing motivation, hope and ideals. It causes anxiety while burnout causes depression and detachment. Stress leads to physical damage while burnout to emotional one.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_957" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-957" style="width: 422px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/medical-admission-mbbs-ms-md-phd/"><img class="wp-image-957 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/rrmch-logo-1.png" alt="RRMCH - Medical Admissions " width="422" height="101" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/rrmch-logo-1.png 422w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/rrmch-logo-1-300x72.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 422px) 100vw, 422px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-957" class="wp-caption-text">MBBS MS MD Admissions in 2019-20</figcaption></figure></p>
<p><b>Dealing with it</b></p>
<p align="justify">One of the most effective ways to deal with it is to speak to someone who is very dear or close to you and also is a good listener. This will help you calm down. Try spending quality time with your dear ones. Socialize a bit with the people you are working with, participate in activities in workplace. Indulge yourself into some hobby or outdoor activity or take a break from work. You could be at a phase where you might just have to consider quitting your job and taking a break before you begin again. Alternatively, joining a support community with cause can help you connect with like-minded people and help you de-tress on a regular basis. If nothing else seem to find you a way out it’s never too late to find new friends. With internet at your help finding friends is not a difficult task.</p>
<p align="justify">Know more about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org">RRMCH </a></strong></p>
<p align="justify">*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medical College Admissions 2019 &#8211; 2020</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medical-college-admissions-2019-2020/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 09:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2019 medical colleges admissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical college in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mbbs admissions 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical college admissions 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical college admissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1106</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A career in medicine has by far topped the list of career choices if not amongst students then definitely amongst parents. In India, particularly medicine has been a very reputed career choice. Though times are slowly changing and parents and students are opening their minds up to careers that are more about what their children &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/medical-college-admissions-2019-2020/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Medical College Admissions 2019 &#8211; 2020"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">A career in medicine has by far topped the list of career choices if not amongst students then definitely amongst parents. In India, particularly medicine has been a very reputed career choice. Though times are slowly changing and parents and students are opening their minds up to careers that are more about what their children are inclined to and not their own interests. Still, Medicine remains the most sought after career choices.</p>
<p align="justify">There are numerous colleges across India but before you select the most suitable one for your child or as a student for yourself, but it is advisable to make a checklist of points you need to make, shortlist a few colleges as per your priority and then narrow down to the final one or two.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1107" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020.jpg" alt="mbbs admissions 2019" width="998" height="320" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020.jpg 998w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020-300x96.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/RRMCH-admissions-2019-2020-768x246.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p align="justify">Well, yes primarily to open the gateway to any medical college, you need to crack the NEET code but once you clear the NEET UG entrance exam, you can start thinking about the college you wish to get admitted to. The other exams include All India Institute of Medical Sciences for MBBS (AIIMS MBBS) and Jawaharlal Institute of Postgraduate Medical Education and Research (JIPMER MBBS) entrance exams. In India MBBS colleges offer over 66K seats across over 470 colleges in India. AIIMS with 8 campuses under its roof offers over 800 seats. There’s a counselling procedure done after NEET.</p>
<p align="justify"><b>Infrastructure</b> – A college with good infrastructure is the need of the hour. So, it’s always advisable that you primarily shortlist a few colleges and then visit the college to check out the infrastructure facilities and amenities most importantly that of the hospital because all the learning is going to come from there. It’s very important because you will be primarily living out of your comfort zone if you are taking admissions away from home. So, getting into a college that has a good setup is a good idea.</p>
<p align="justify"><b>Rankings </b>– Though rankings of medical college are usually based on the number of years the college has been in existence as well as the hospital reputation, it should not be the main criteria for evaluation. If the hospital is working well and has a good number of patient load, it will definitely help you gain practical experience.</p>
<p align="justify"><b>Bonds</b> – It’s a criteria you need to be aware off atleast. There are some colleges which want students to sign bonds for a mandatory internship. There is always a mention of the same in the brochure of the medical institutes. So, before you choose a college do go through the information pertaining to the bonds.</p>
<p align="justify"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/"><img class="alignnone wp-image-1057 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/rrmch.gif" alt="rrmch" width="647" height="42" /></a></p>
<p align="justify"><b>Location</b> – Yes, location is one point to consider and for many it could be one of the vital points. Primarily because you might be stepping out of your home or comfort zone for the first time and hence, considering the location criteria is advisable. Another important reason being that the MBBS course is over 5 years and considering the duration and the workload you’ll be having while doing the course, you might not want to lose your valuable time in commuting or feeling nostalgic about living away from home.</p>
<p align="justify">Well, finally, the student and their parents need to narrow down to one college and particularly it’s the student’s prerogative and choice when it comes to selection of college.</p>
<p align="justify">
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Common Food Allergens in India</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-common-food-allergens-in-india/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 05:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Common Food Allergens in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[common food allergies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Allergens in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[full health checkup in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good medical colleges in bangalore]]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1083</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Allergies are very common amongst us. Either we know we are allergic to stuff based on our experience post consumption of these foods or we aren’t. Many people have hiccups on eating spicy stuff like a chilly, while many get a runny nose. There are people who suffer from lactose intolerance and suffer from diarrhea &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/5-common-food-allergens-in-india/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "5 Common Food Allergens in India"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Allergies are very common amongst us. Either we know we are allergic to stuff based on our experience post consumption of these foods or we aren’t. Many people have hiccups on eating spicy stuff like a chilly, while many get a runny nose. There are people who suffer from lactose intolerance and suffer from diarrhea after consuming foods like milk or cheese. But, if you think all these are allergies, then you aren’t completely right. These can be categorized under food intolerance or insensitivity. A food allergy is not the same. It occurs when your body considers harmless food to apparently harm the body. Food allergies could range from creating simple reactions like rashes on skin, or irritation to eyes or breathing problems to turn out to be life threatening if immediate steps are not taken. The best way to keep yourself safe is to be aware of such triggers and avoid them.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1084" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India.jpg" alt="5 Common Food Allergens in India" width="800" height="600" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/5-Common-Food-Allergens-in-India-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Let’s look through 10 different food allergens and their side effects or reactions they cause. The most common allergens are as follows &#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Eggs</strong> &#8211; The trigger that causes food allergies in eggs is egg protein like conalbumin, ovumucoid and ovalbumin. This allergy is found mostly in children than in adults. Some of the allergens are destroyed when the eggs are cooked but not all. This allergy can also cause anaphylaxis. The allergy can vary from person to person. While some might be allergic to yoke, some to egg white and some to all.</p>
<p><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/department/cardiology/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-995 size-full" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg" alt="" width="397" height="41" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore.jpg 397w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/best-hospitals-in-bangalore-300x31.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 397px) 100vw, 397px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Fish</strong> &#8211; Fish allergy could be really harmful. It can be life threatening and lead to anaphylaxis. The allergy can show reactions like throat swelling, diarrhea and puking, skin irritations, blood pressure drop and anaphylaxis as well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Milk</strong> – Many children may be allergic to cow’s milk. It can also be passed to the child indirectly through breast feeding. Many children out-grow of the allergy once adults but one fifth of them are said to have it in their adulthood too. The presence of the milk antibodies can be determined with the help of the blood test.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Soyabean</strong> &#8211; Soy bean is also one of the common allergy to have. The reactions of soya bean allergy includes vomiting, diarrhea, ashes as well as stomach cramps. Sometimes it could also cause swelling of the tongue, lips as well as hand, feet and puffed eyes too. Other reactions include bloating, flatulence. Though, it rarely gets life threatening and cause anaphylaxis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Shellfish</strong> – Shell fish includes aquatic life like shrimp, oyster, crabs, mussels, clams, scallops, to name a few. This allergy can get serious and even vapor of the cooking shell fish can be allergic. The reaction are very much similar to other allergic reactions</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As far as allergens go, prevention is always the best idea. So be aware of allergies if you have any and avoid food that can cause allergies primarily. Also, in case you get one for the first time, take immediate action and consult a doctor without wasting much of a time.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know about <strong><a href="http://hospital.rrmch.org/">Top Private Hospitals in Bangalore, Karnataka</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>E-Cigarettes are Harmful Too</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/e-cigarettes-are-harmful-too/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 08:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E-Cigatettes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1079</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A Harvard study says that the chemicals that are commonly used to in flavoring e cigarettes may damage our lungs in a way that its ability to fight the dust, dirt and other allergens can be put to risk, thereby increasing risk of diseases like asthma. The researchers found that two chemicals namely diacetyl and &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/e-cigarettes-are-harmful-too/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "E-Cigarettes are Harmful Too"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A Harvard study says that the chemicals that are commonly used to in flavoring e cigarettes may damage our lungs in a way that its ability to fight the dust, dirt and other allergens can be put to risk, thereby increasing risk of diseases like asthma.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The researchers found that two chemicals namely diacetyl and 2, 3 – pentanedione are responsible for the impairment as they affect the functioning of antennae like proturberances. These proturberances are present on 50-75 percent of the cells lining the human airways and are very important contributors in keep the human airway free from dust dirt and mucus thus allowing people to breathe easily without irritation.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/e-cigatettes-are-Harmful-Too.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1080" src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/e-cigatettes-are-Harmful-Too.jpg" alt="e-cigatettes" width="800" height="480" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/e-cigatettes-are-Harmful-Too.jpg 800w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/e-cigatettes-are-Harmful-Too-300x180.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/e-cigatettes-are-Harmful-Too-768x461.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Cilia is the first line of defense in lungs and as per the study these chemicals harm it, by altering the gene expression pertaining to the cilia function as well as production.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The study carried out the testing of e-cigarettes and found that 90% of them have the flavoring chemicals diacetyl and 2 as well as 3-pentanedione are present.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The chemical diacetyl is also found in food flavors like butter flavored microwave popcorn, candy as well as baked goods. Though for foods it is not known to be harmful but only when it is inhaled that if turns dangerous.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>HOW ARE LUNGS AFFECTED</strong><br />
Impaired cilia function is responsible for lung conditions like asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. An associate professor at the Harvard University also mentioned that even though chemicals are used for flavoring e-cigs but it is known as to how they impact the health. This study therefore throws light on the chemicals that are responsible for harming the lungs and how.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The chemical Diacetyl was earlier linked to lung conditions like bronchilitis obliterans, a lung condition also dubbed as popcorn lung for a reason that it was first found in workers of popcorn processing facilities after they inhaled artificial butter flavor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As per researchers the present standards of safe limits of chemical exposure for workers are not enough and need to change as even low levels of the chemical does affect gene expression.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Thus as per researchers, today e-cigarette users are heating as well as inhaling the flavoring chemicals are in common use and users do not know that they are not tested for inhalation safety as well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just know more about <strong><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/">RRMCH</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
