<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>chocolates are good for health &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/chocolates-are-good-for-health/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 06:28:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>CHOCOLATES ARE GOOD FOR HEALTH</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/chocolates-are-good-for-health/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 06:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chocolates are good for health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=642</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yes, you read that right. Chocolates are good for health and this is how. A recent study has found that Chocolate can help prevent heartbeat irregularities, thus reducing the risk of stroke and other heart diseases. As per the researchers, chocolate has worked well against atrial fibrillation, a condition which results in heart beat irregularities. &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/chocolates-are-good-for-health/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "CHOCOLATES ARE GOOD FOR HEALTH"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/CHOCOLATES-ARE-GOOD-FOR-HEALTH-1-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-643" src="http://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/CHOCOLATES-ARE-GOOD-FOR-HEALTH-1-1.jpg" alt="CHOCOLATES ARE GOOD FOR HEALTH" width="615" height="250" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Yes, you read that right. <strong>Chocolates are good for health</strong> and this is how. A recent study has found that<em> Chocolate can help prevent heartbeat irregularities</em>, thus <em>reducing the risk of stroke and other heart diseases</em>. As per the researchers, chocolate has worked well against atrial fibrillation, a condition which results in heart beat irregularities. In this condition, a variation in pace of the heart’s lower two chambers and atria or heart’s two upper chambers occurs. This irregularity in the heart beat increases the risk of heart failures, strokes as well as cognitive impairment.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The study found that adults consuming around 1 ounce of chocolate two to six times during the week had the strongest effect. Though the mechanism on how chocolate helps in preventing atrial fibrillation is yet to be known, it is said that flavonoids, types of compounds found in chocolate might play a significant role in the same as they already have anti-oxident and anti-inflammatory properties.<br />
The data study of over 55000 adults, both male and female under the age group of 50-64 was analyzed to get the results. Here are the findings:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Women</strong><br />
Women eating 1 ounce of chocolate once a week lowered the risk of atrial fibrillation by 21 percent.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Men</strong><br />
Men eating 2 to six servings of 1 ounce of chocolate per week lowered the risk of atrial fibrillation by 23 percent.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Cocoa Rich Chocolates</strong><br />
It was found that chocolates with high content of cocoa if had in moderation are considered to be a heart healthy snack. They have significant health benefits as well as protective constituents. The study also revealed that chocolate consumers were healthier, well educated and had less chances of high blood pressure and diabetes when compared to non consumers of chocolate.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Having said that, the debate on the geographic constraint of the study is on, but yes, we can still consider eating cocoa rich chocolates in moderation for a healthy heart.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">know about <a title="Best Medical College in Bangalore" href="http://www.rrmch.org" target="_blank">rajarajeswari medical college and hospital</a> Bangalore</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
