<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Swine Flu or H1N1 &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/swine-flu-or-h1n1/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 09:27:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Fast Facts About Swine Flu (H1N1)</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/fast-facts-about-swine-flu-h1n1/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 09:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swine Flu or H1N1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1166</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Swine Flu or H1N1 is also another common condition in India just like Dengue. Both these conditions do not have any cure as of now and research is still on to find one. The year 2019 began with the onset of Swine flu in many states including Rajasthan, Uttar Pradesh, Punjab, Himachal Pradesh, Telangana, Maharashtra &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/fast-facts-about-swine-flu-h1n1/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Fast Facts About Swine Flu (H1N1)"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Swine Flu or H1N1 is also another common condition in India just like Dengue. Both these conditions do not have any cure as of now and research is still on to find one. The year 2019 began with the onset of Swine flu in many states including Rajasthan, Uttar Pradesh, Punjab, Himachal Pradesh, Telangana, Maharashtra and Gujarat.  Sadly, the former defense minister of India George Fernandes, who was suffering from Alziemer’s was down with swine flu and passed away in the beginning of the year.  Here are a few facts around Swine Flu. After that it was BJP party head Amit Shah, with H1N1 and admitted for treatment.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Swine-Flu-H1N1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1167" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Swine-Flu-H1N1.jpg 750w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Swine-Flu-H1N1-300x150.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Swine
Flu – The Condition </strong>
</p>



<p>Swine
is affects the respiratory tracts of a human body and is caused due
to Influenza Viruses.  It is known as swine flu as it affects the
respiratory tracts of pigs leading to barking cough, nasal
secretions, decreased appetite and more. 
</p>



<p>Swine
flu is contagious and can transmit to humans very easily because of
the ability of viruses to mutate.</p>



<p>
Swine flu symptoms are not different from general flu infections.
This could include headache, fever of (100 F or more), fatigue and
runny nose. 
</p>



<p>The
incubation period for swine flu is one to four days and it is
contagious just a day before the symptoms surface upto seven days
afterwards. Though in some patients, the time span could be longer.</p>



<p>While
some have approved medications like  Baloxavir marboxil, xofluza,
rapivab do help in prevention/ reducing side effects of swine flu.
Though there is still speculation on the same and many disagree
stating antivirals don’t have any side-affect. 
</p>



<p>Complications
of Swine flu include pneumonia. 
</p>



<p>Well, Swine flu can transform into a life threatening condition if not treated on time and hence it is important to consult the doctor if you find symptoms of flu for 3 to 4 days.  </p>



<p>*Sourced from the Internet</p>



<p>Just know about <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/"><strong>Rajarajeswari Hospital in Bangalore</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
