<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>obg specialist in bangalore &#8211; RRMCH</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/tag/obg-specialist-in-bangalore/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog</link>
	<description>Best Medical College &#38; Hospital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 06:05:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.18</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp – A Rare Pregnancy Rash</title>
		<link>https://www.rrmch.org/blog/plaques-of-pregnancy-or-puppp-a-rare-pregnancy-rash/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 05:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rrmch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[College Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospital Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best gynecologist in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best hospital in banglaore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good hospitals in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical colleges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obg specialist in bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaques of Pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hospitals in karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top medical colleges in bangalore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.rrmch.org/blog/?p=1248</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know that pregnancy can bring along a lot of side effects also like fatigue, nausea, vomiting and more. But, one rare condition that only a few or say 1 in 160 women get are pregnancy PUPPPs. Though, it is known to be a common condition experienced by pregnant women, not all are aware &#8230; <p class="link-more"><a href="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/plaques-of-pregnancy-or-puppp-a-rare-pregnancy-rash/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp – A Rare Pregnancy Rash"</span></a></p>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We
all know that pregnancy can bring along a lot of side effects also
like fatigue, nausea, vomiting and more. But, one rare condition that
only a few or say 1 in 160 women get are pregnancy PUPPPs. Though, it
is known to be a common condition experienced by pregnant women, not
all are aware of it. Here’s and over view of Pruritic Urticarial
Papules or PUPPPS, also known as plaques or Pregnancy. 
</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp.jpg" alt="Plaques of Pregnancy or Puppp" class="wp-image-1249" srcset="https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp.jpg 600w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.rrmch.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Plaques-of-Pregnancy-or-Puppp-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Though
as on day scientists and medical experts aren’t really sure of the
reason behind the surfacing of such itchy rashes in women during
pregnancy but believe that it could be due to excessive stretching of
skin in the months nearing to delivery. 
</p>



<p>Also,
there is no cure. The rashes tend to appear in the third semester and
disappear within 2 weeks post birthing. The rashes start mostly from
the stomach and spread across your thighs, legs, hands and neck area.
They look like red swollen patches and are extremely itchy. 
</p>



<p>Another
reason cited by experts around rash is the circulation of immune
fetal cells through the body. These cells spark an immune response
that in turn leads to the rash surfacing. The theory finds support in
the fact that the fetal cells do stay in the body for short time
after delivery. But, it’s not proved yet. 
</p>



<p>The
itching could get worse if you tend to scratch it. Better to avoid
scratching. In hotter regions the itching and pain is much worse and
proper care needs to be taken for relief. Here are a few tips around
relief from rashes 
</p>



<ol><li>

	Ice – Cool ice compresses
	can help relieve the itching. Wrap the ice compress in a cloth and
	apply few time during the day. 
	
	</li><li>

	Oatmeal – Oatmeal baths are
	known to be effective home remedy for may skin conditions including
	this one. 
	
	</li><li>

	Peppermint – Peppermint
	comes with menthol and it is known to have cooling effects. Use
	peppermint oil on the rashes or you might consume the prescribed
	quantity after consulting your doctor. 
	
	</li><li>

	Moisturiser –
	</li><li>

	Clove oil &#8211;  Clove oil is
	also known to have  cooling effects because it contains
	antimicrobials and antioxidants, phenol eugenol to be specific. 
	
</li></ol>



<p>
A study in 2017 revealed that
around 25 participants who applied petroleum jelly followed by clove
oil on rash prone areas show a reduction in symptoms compared to the
group that used on petroleum jelly.</p>



<p> Having said that, not every pregnant woman gets these itchy rashes but those who get could use the above tips for relief purpose because these rashes could get itchy to hell and frustrate you to the core. But, be calm, this will pass off and there is not known effects to the fetus due to their occurrence as yet.</p>



<p></p>



<p>*Sourced from Internet</p>



<p>Know more about  <a href="https://hospital.rrmch.org/department/obg/"><strong>Best Gynecologist in Bangalore </strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
